<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
 

 

 <channel>
    <title>This is Feed #1</title>
     <language>en</language>
    <description>
        
            This is the Description, can be changed based on the content
        
    </description>
    <link>https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/gp-app/category1</link>
    <copyright>Radio Free Asia</copyright>

    
	     <category>cat1, cat2, cat3</category>
    

	 
	 <atom:link href="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/gp-app/category1/rss2.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
     

	 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>NGOs Demand End to Impunity, Independent Probes in Cases of Murdered Cambodian Reporters (STICKY)</title>
        <guid>0a29ee59-eeca-444a-a2e1-68450d752612</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/impunity-11022018164107.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>At least 13 reporters have been murdered in the country since 1994, with nearly no convictions.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/impunity-11022018164107.html/cambodia-teang-theav-march-2015-crop.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Teang Theav, wife of slain reporter Suon Chan, speaks to reporters outside of a court in Kampong Chhnang province, March 2, 2015.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[RFA]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Dozens of nongovernmental organizations marked International Day to End Impunity for Crimes Against Journalists Friday by slamming Cambodia for failing to hold the perpetrators of crimes against reporters and rights activists accountable and demanding independent, transparent probes of their cases.<br/><br/>“When journalists are targeted by violence for what they write or report, freedom of expression is stifled and replaced by self-censorship and fear; the public is denied information; and the powerful cannot be held to account,” said the statement, signed by 42 watchdogs—including global groups Amnesty International and Human Rights Watch, and local organizations Adhoc and Licadho.<br/><br/>“When the state fails to investigate and punish violence against journalists, it sends a chilling message that attacks on journalists are permissible.”<br/><br/>The NGOs noted that since 1994, at least 13 journalists have been murdered in Cambodia for their reporting, and that all but one of them were “engaged in activities that posed a direct threat to powerful individuals within the Cambodian elite.”<br/><br/>In 11 of the cases, no one was convicted for the murders, the groups said, while in seven, no suspect was arrested or interrogated. “Serious concerns remain” in the two cases where a trial took place, they added.<br/><br/>And while no journalists have been killed in the last two years in Cambodia, reporters are regularly targeted with judicial harassment, according to the statement, including trumped-up charges, and media outlets perceived as critical of Prime Minister Hun Sen’s regime have been forced to close.<br/><br/>The groups noted that impunity in Cambodia is not limited to attacks against journalists, citing the murders of environmental activist Chut Wutty, trade unionists Chea Vichea and Ros Sovannareth, and political analyst Kem Ley as representative of “the thousands of instances of abuse” against outspoken critics that have “gone unaddressed” by authorities.<br/><br/>“We condemn the rampant impunity that harms Cambodian people and society and demand justice for all those whose rights have been cast aside,” the groups said.<br/><br/>“We call on the authorities to prosecute perpetrators of crimes committed against journalists and human rights defenders by undertaking effective, independent, and transparent investigations and prosecutions in accordance with international human rights standards … and to restore the integrity of the Cambodian legal system.”<br/><br/><strong>Call for justice</strong><br/><br/>Separately on Friday, Club of Cambodia Journalists president Pen Bona urged authorities to seek justice for the 13 slain journalists—Thou Char Mongkol, Nun Chan, Chan Dara, Thun Bun Ly, Chet Duong Daravuth, Pich Em, Dok Sokhan, Ou Saroeun, Chour Chetharith, Khim Sambo, Hang Serei Oudom, Suon Chan, and Taing Try.<br/><br/>Speaking in an interview with RFA’s Khmer Service, he said it was a “good sign” that no reporters had been killed in Cambodia over the past two years, but questioned why there have been no breakthroughs in finding those responsible for the 13 murders since 1994, despite authorities claiming that they continue to investigate the cases.<br/><br/>Ministry of Interior spokesman Khieu Sopheak could not be reached for comment Friday, but has previously pledged that authorities “won’t close those cases until the perpetrators are brought to justice.”<br/><br/>But Ministry of Justice spokesman Chin Malin on Friday hit out at the statement from the NGOs, telling RFA that “there is no impunity” in the cases of the slain journalists, as investigations continue.<br/><br/>“It isn’t impunity—it’s still at the investigative stage,” he said, adding that the cases are “complicated” and require more time to close.<br/><br/>Nop Vy of the Cambodian Center for Independent Media, however, refuted Chin Malin’s claims, noting that the journalists had all been killed after reporting on sensitive issues, including corruption scandals involving powerful people.<br/><br/>He urged authorities to “be more responsible” because journalists are working to improve society, and said a culture of impunity had negatively impacted local reporting.<br/><br/>“We have seen a delay in bringing justice to victims,” he said, adding that authorities should “speed up investigations to end impunity.”<br/><br/><strong>Internet freedom</strong><br/><br/>Friday’s statement came days after U.S. NGO Freedom House said in its annual “Freedom on the Net” report that of the 65 countries it monitors, Cambodia was one of five nations that “experienced the steepest deterioration in internet freedom over the last five years,” citing amendments initiated by the ruling Cambodian People’s Party (CPP) that led to an uptick in arrests for online political commentary.<br/><br/>Freedom House designated Cambodia “partly free” with a score of 55 over the past year, on a scale where zero represents “most free” and 100 indicates “least free,” noting a crackdown on online dissent by Hun Sen’s government that led to a “surge in arrests and prison sentences,” and ensured his party’s victory ahead of a July 29 election.<br/><br/>Council of Ministers spokesman Phay Siphan slammed the Freedom House report Friday as “bogus and lies,” saying Cambodia “doesn’t have any law restricting internet freedom.”<br/><br/>Phay Siphan said Hun Sen’s regime is working to improve internet access for everyone throughout the country, but warned that internet freedom “doesn’t give users free rein to insult people or incite violence.”<br/><br/>When asked about claims in the report that China has provided Cambodia with training on how to monitor the internet use of its citizens, the spokesman said that authorities “only monitor the internet to fight against terrorism and for other security reasons.”<br/><br/><strong>Requesting happier news</strong><br/><br/>Also on Friday, Hun Sen’s wife and Cambodia Red Cross chairwoman Bun Rany urged members of the local media to “decrease reporting on crimes, rapes, and deaths from traffic accidents,” asking them to instead focus on the work her husband’s government has done to develop the country.<br/><br/>Pro-government media outlet Fresh News quoted Bun Rany during a donation distribution in Kampong Chhnang province as saying that “local TV stations don’t broadcast news about government efforts that have helped to develop the country, but only about violent crimes, suicides, traffic accidents, rapes and killings.”<br/><br/>“Every morning, I only see news about people dying, rapes and killings. I would like to use this forum to appeal to all TV stations to broadcast government achievements instead of bad topics.”<br/><br/>The Red Cross chairwoman did not specify what kind of developments she would prefer the nation’s news organizations to focus on.<br/><strong><i><br/>Reported by RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Samean Yun. Written in English by Joshua Lipes.</i></strong></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>censorship, media, reporters, internet, freedom house, hun sen, cambodia elections</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Cambodian Journalists Pen Letter Demanding Court Drop Charges Against Former RFA Reporters</title>
        <guid>11f976c2-f64e-4607-9318-1809a35b844f</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/letter-01102019170640.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>They also urge the prime minister to intervene in the case, citing promises of increased media freedom.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 22:12:27 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/letter-01102019170640.html/cambodia-uon-chhin-and-yeang-sothearin-bail-aug-2018.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Former Radio Free Asia reporters Uon Chhin and Yeang Sothearin walk out of Prey Sar Prison, in the outskirts of Phnom Penh, Aug. 21, 2018.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AP Photo]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>More than three dozen journalists in Cambodia published an open letter on Thursday urging the Phnom Penh Municipal Court to drop all charges against two former RFA reporters who have lived under police surveillance for more than a year while awaiting a trial for “espionage.”<br/><br/>The 38 journalists said they affixed their names and thumbprints to the letter, a copy of which was obtained by RFA’s Khmer Service, “to express our concern over the seriousness of the charges” facing Uon Chhin and Yeang Sothearin, who were taken into custody on Nov. 14, 2017 and charged with “illegally collecting information for a foreign source,” but released on bail nine months later.<br/><br/>“Keeping them under court supervision makes it extremely difficult for them to live and work as reporters,” the journalists said, noting that Uon Chhin and Yeang Sothearin are barred from changing their addresses or traveling abroad, and must check in with their local police station once a month.<br/><br/>“In democratic countries, the press has played a vital role in providing people with the truth, and that is what these former reporters have done,” the letter continues.<br/><br/>“We believe that the charges against them … are too harsh. The charges intimidate other reporters who are trying to do their work and will negatively impact the freedom of the press in Cambodia as well.”<br/><br/>RFA closed its nearly 20-year old bureau in Phnom Penh on Sept. 12, 2017 amid a growing crackdown by Prime Minister Hun’s ruling Cambodian People’s Party (CPP) on the political opposition, NGOs and independent media ahead of national elections in July last year, in what was seen as a bid to silence criticism of his government. The CPP handily won the ballot, securing all 125 seats in parliament.<br/><br/>Cambodian journalists working for RFA had reported over the years on corruption, illegal logging, and forced evictions, among other stories largely ignored by pro-government media, and authorities had already closed independent radio stations carrying RFA reports, using a pretext of tax and administrative violations.<br/><br/>The arrest of Uon Chhin and Yeang Sothearin came after a warning from Cambodia’s Ministries of Information and Interior that any journalists still working for RFA after its office in the capital closed would be treated as spies.<br/><br/>Their release on bail followed condemnation from multiple local and international rights groups over their treatment during detention, and demands that they be freed.<br/><br/><b>Call for intervention</b><br/><br/>May Titthara, a reporter from the <i>Khmer Times</i>, said he and the other signatories of Thursday’s open letter were also calling on Hun Sen to intervene in the case because his government had recently suggested it would work to ensure press freedom in Cambodia, and the prime minister is scheduled to meet with members of the media on Friday evening.<br/><br/>“This shows that he is paying attention to reporters, so we hope [Hun Sen] will consider intervening with the court to dismiss the charges,” he said, adding that he will ask the prime minister directly during the meeting.<br/><br/>When asked on Thursday whether Hun Sen would direct court authorities to drop the case, Council of Ministers spokesman Phay Siphan told RFA that “the government doesn’t have jurisdiction over the court.”<br/><br/>“The prime minister can’t intervene ahead of the final verdict, but he can ask [the court] to speed up the case,” he added.<br/><br/>On Wednesday, the lawyer representing Uon Chhin and Yeang Sothearin requested that the court dismiss their case, saying there is no evidence that the former reporters violated the law, and told RFA he believes the charges against them will be dropped because of the lack of proof.<br/><br/>Paris-based media watchdog Reporters Without Borders (RSF) ranked Cambodia 132nd out of 180 countries in its 2017 World Press Freedom Index, and warned that the Southeast Asian nation is “liable to fall” in the 2018 index.<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by RFA’s Khmer Service. Translates by Samean Yun. Written in English by Joshua Lipes.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>cambodia elections, cnrp, cpp, hun sen, media, freedom of expression, judicial system</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Chinese Warships Visit Cambodia to ‘Strengthen Cooperation’ as Western Influence Wanes</title>
        <guid>31b8d21d-4c60-4db6-ad5b-07bd41850675</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/warships-01092019162023.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>Observers say the visit demonstrates financial and military support for Prime Minister Hun Sen’s regime.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
	         
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/multimedia/Audio-slideshow-Burmese-exile-05232008145614.html/audio_hi.mp3" length="1851768"/>
	        
	         
            <enclosure type="audio/mpeg" url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/multimedia/slideshowChinaPart2-12102009121348.html/audio_hi.mp3" length="1732483"/>
	        
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/warships-01092019162023.html/cambodia-china-warship-jan-2019-crop.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[One of three Chinese warships anchored at the port of Sihanoukville in southwestern Cambodia, Jan. 9, 2019.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ministry of Defense spokesman Chhum Socheat's Facebook page]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    
		<media:group>

				
                        
  

  
    
            <media:content url="http://vhpd.rfa.org.edgesuite.net/20171002/1251/1_2lzc7wyq_1_hdxmd47a_1.mp4" medium="video" type="video/3gpp">
	            <media:title>12th Century Cambodian Temple Crumbles</media:title>
	            <media:description>Tourism numbers are down at the historic Banteay Chhmar Temple in northwestern Cambodia. Despite restoration efforts, the 12th century temple continues to crumble.</media:description>
            </media:content>


  

		        

				
					
						
				            

					            <media:content url="http://vhpd.rfa.org.edgesuite.net/20190807/1251/1_192fv4p8_1_1framm86_1.mp4" medium="video" type="video/3gpp">
				                 </media:content>
							
						
					
				
		</media:group>
	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Three Chinese warships arrived in southern Cambodia’s coastal city of Sihanoukville Wednesday on a visit the two authoritarian governments said will promote stronger bilateral ties, a warming that comes as Western influence wanes in the Southeast Asian nation following an election last year seen as unfree and unfair.</p>
<p>
<iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bFwboYmo2Ow" width="560"></iframe>
<br/><br/>The ships carrying some 700 crew members will stay in port for four days, during which Xu Haihan, a delegate from the Chinese navy, will meet with Defense Minister Tea Banh and other Cambodian military officials, Ministry of Defense spokesman Chhum Socheat said in a statement posted to his Facebook page.</p>
<blockquote class="pullquote">THIS IS PULL QUOTE. <span>THIS IS PULL QUOTE. <span>THIS IS PULL QUOTE. </span></span></blockquote>
<p>“The Chinese warship visit will strengthen friendship and cooperation between the Cambodian and Chinese military,” the statement said, noting that Chinese naval vessels have visited Cambodia 17 times in recent years.<br/><br/>China and Cambodia have recently held joint military exercises and Beijing has pledged to help fund a modernization of the Southeast Asian nation’s military.<br/><br/>Meanwhile, China has been pouring investment into Cambodia in recent years, causing some Cambodians to question what type of influence Beijing might have over their government.</p>
<p>

<br/>The arrival of the Chinese warships comes amid speculation that Beijing is building a 45,000 hectare (111,200-acre) naval base in Cambodia’s Koh Kong province, based on a Nov. 15 report by Hong Kong’s Asia Times online news portal, which cited unnamed diplomatic sources.<br/><br/>Cambodia’s Prime Minister Hun Sen later dismissed the report, saying such a move would violate the constitution, while Cambodia’s Ministry of National Defense called it “fake news” and part of a “foreign campaign to mislead the public and the international community with the intention of destroying the country’s independence and neutrality.”<br/><br/>If such a naval base were built on the Gulf of Thailand, it would allow China to significantly expand patrols on the South China Sea, which Beijing claims much of, while rival Taiwan and ASEAN countries Brunei, Malaysia, the Philippines and Vietnam have their own stakes in the waters.<br/><br/>Cambodia has increasingly backed China in disputes with the ASEAN nations over its actions in the sea.<br/><br/>Meanwhile, Western influence in Cambodia is on the decline amid criticism of Hun Sen and his ruling Cambodian People’s Party (CPP) over rollbacks on democracy in the lead up to and aftermath of a July 29 election in which the CPP effectively ran uncontested and won all 125 seats after a ban of the opposition party.<br/><br/>The CPP overwhelmingly won the election following the Supreme Court’s November 2017 dissolution of the main opposition Cambodia National Rescue Party (CNRP) and a five-year ban on the political activities of 118 of its senior officials for the party’s role in an alleged plot to topple the government.<br/><br/>The U.S. has since announced visa bans on individuals seen as limiting democracy in the country, as part of a series of measures aimed at pressuring Cambodia to reverse course, and the European Union, which was the second biggest trade partner of Cambodia in 2017, has said it will drop a preferential trade scheme for Cambodian exports based on the country’s election environment.<br/><br/><strong>‘Show of strength’</strong><br/><br/>Political Analyst Kim Sok told RFA’s Khmer Service on Wednesday that China’s visit is meant not only to “strengthen friendship and cooperation” between the two nations, but to demonstrate support of Hun Sen’s regime both financially and militarily.<br/><br/>“The Chinese warship is here as a show of strength against foreign sanctions,” he said, noting that Cambodia hasn’t shown any signs of backing down in the face of Western pressure.<br/><br/>But he warned that as Hun Sen faces a political deadlock and home and increasingly pushes the West away, “he has no choice but to rely on the Chinese.”<br/><br/>RFA was unable to reach CPP spokesman Phay Siphan for comment on Wednesday.<br/><br/>Hun Sen has repeatedly stressed that his country does not need foreign governments to recognize the legitimacy of Cambodia’s elections, saying acceptance by Cambodians is sufficient.<br/><br/>He has also said that he will continue to welcome aid from China, which is poised to overtake the U.S. as the world’s top foreign donor, and which is currently Cambodia’s largest international aid provider.<br/><br/>China, which typically offers aid to countries without many of the prerequisites that the U.S. and EU place on donations, such as improvements to human rights and rule of law, offered “sincere congratulations” to Hun Sen’s party for its showing in July’s polls.<br/><br/>Trade volume between Cambodia and China was valued at U.S. $5.8 billion in 2017, up 22 percent from U.S. $4.76 billion dollars a year earlier, while China is currently Cambodia’s largest investor, and has poured U.S. $12.6 billion into the Southeast Asian nation from 1994 to 2017. <br/><br/><i><strong>Reported by Tin Zakariya for RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Samean Yun. Written in English by Joshua Lipes.</strong></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>regional influence, military, navy, south china sea, cambodia elections, cnrp, cpp, hun sen</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Hong Kong Abandons Further Democratic Reform as China Tightens Grip</title>
        <guid>460909ad-8181-452d-8152-da20aebd936c</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/reform-01092019124611.html</link>

	    
	         <category>China</category>
	    

        <description>Officials move ahead with plans to criminalize any 'insult' to China's national anthem, without specifying which situations could result in prosecution.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 19:56:38 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/reform-01092019124611.html/china-nip2-010919.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Hong Kong official Patrick Nip addresses a press conference in Hong Kong, Jan. 9, 2019.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[RFA]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>The Hong Kong government on Wednesday ruled out any further attempt at democratic reform as the government moves ahead with plans to criminalize 'insults' to the national anthem of the People's Republic of China.<br/><br/>Patrick Nip, the city's top official in charge of constitutional affairs and liaison with the ruling Chinese Communist Party government in Beijing, said Hong Kong is "in no position" to restart democratic reforms, saying that doing so could be "rash" and lead to "extreme action."<br/><br/>Nip, who was responding to a question from pro-democracy lawmaker James To about the likelihood of a democratically elected chief executive for the city in 2022, didn't specify what he meant by "extreme action."<br/><br/>He said an Aug. 31, 2014 decree by China's parliament insisting that election candidates be screened by Beijing was a fundamental condition for any reform.<br/><br/>"If we are to restart constitutional reform, or further promote its development, this is a starting point," Nip said of the National People's Congress standing committee legal interpretation that sparked the 79-day 2014 Occupy Central civil disobedience movement for fully democratic elections.<br/><br/>"If we cannot even reach a consensus on this fundamental legal basis, I don't see how we are in a position to further our reform proposal," he said.<br/><br/>His comments came as Hong Kong fell to 73rd place in the Economic Intelligence Unit's (EIU's) annual global democracy index.<br/><br/>Last year's banning of the pro-independence Hong Kong National Party (HKNP) and the political screening of election candidates had weakened the city's "already weak democracy," the EIU said.<br/><br/><b>Draft law still vague</b><br/><br/>Meanwhile, Nip said the government is going ahead with laws that will ban any act of "altering or insulting" the national anthem, with criminal penalties of up to three years' imprisonment.<br/><br/>Police will be given the freedom to bring charges against suspects for up to two years after the alleged offense, Nip said. The usual time limit is six months for minor offenses under Hong Kong law.<br/><br/>A draft copy of the bill previously indicated that anyone present in a public place when the "March of the Volunteers" is being played is required to "stand up and show respect."<br/><br/>Civic Party lawmaker Jeremy Tam said the current draft is too vague about what exactly constitutes an "insult" to the national anthem.<br/><br/>"Let us not forget that this legislation is being proposed by the government," Tam said. "They have a duty to explain the various situations in which such acts might take place, and which acts would and would not be in breach of this law."<br/><br/>"And yet, at today's press conference, they refused to give a straight answer to questions about different situations," he said. "The government can't seem to tell us, and yet they want to legislate."<br/><br/>Use of the rousing revolutionary tune, which marks the struggle of the ruling Chinese Communist Party to found the People's Republic, will also likely be banned in advertising, at private funerals, or as background music in public venues.<br/><br/><b>National anthem jeered at match</b><br/><br/>The move came after Hong Kong football fans jeered, turned their backs, and yelled Cantonese obscenities as the national anthem was played over the loudspeakers at the start of recent soccer matches in the city.<br/><br/>Meanwhile, the last British colonial governor of Hong Kong, Chris Patten, said the city had undergone a "general tightening of control" since President Xi Jinping took power in late 2012.<br/><br/>"There was a general tightening of control,” Patten told a parliamentary foreign affairs committee in Westminster on Tuesday.<br/><br/>"[Hong Kong's autonomy] isn’t just about capitalism, it’s about the rule of law. It’s about free speech, it’s about all the freedoms we associate with pluralism, and I think that’s happened to a considerable extent over the past half a dozen years," he said.<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by Lee Wang-yam for RFA's Cantonese Service, and by Hwang Chun-mei for the Mandarin Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>reform, democracy, hong kong</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>China 'Offered to Spy' on Hong Kong-Based Journalists With The Wall Street Journal</title>
        <guid>2f4a5db2-914f-4c6f-9004-8c8220a89bb3</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/china-offered-to-spy-on-hong-kong-based-journalists-01082019110823.html</link>

	    
	         <category>China</category>
	    

        <description>Freshly leaked documents indicate that Chinese officials thought nothing of bugging and surveilling the paper's journalists in violation of Hong Kong's promised autonomy.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 16:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/china-offered-to-spy-on-hong-kong-based-journalists-01082019110823.html/china-hkja-fcc-hong-kong-oct8-2018.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Chris Yeung (C), chairperson of the Hong Kong Journalist Association, stands next to Foreign Correspondents' Club 
president Florence de Changy (3rd R) and legislator Claudia Mo (2nd R) as they speak to journalists before handing over petitions to the Hong Kong government calling for an explanation of its rejection of a visa for Financial Times journalist Victor Mallet, in Hong Kong, Oct. 8, 2018.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Chinese officials offered to install bugs and surveillance equipment in the homes of foreign journalists in Hong Kong in 2016, as part of a bail-out offer to the Malaysian government's 1MDB fund that is embroiled in a massive corruption scandal, <i>The Wall Street Journal</i> reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Citing minutes from "a series of previously undisclosed meetings," the paper said ruling Chinese Communist Party officials had offered to use Beijing's clout to get third countries to drop their investigations into allegations that officials close to then-Prime Minister Najib Razak had appropriated money from the fund.</p>
<p>The minutes show that the Chinese officials also offered to bug the homes and offices of <i>WSJ</i> reporters writing about the scandal from Hong Kong, in a bid to discover their sources, it said.</p>
<p>Najib has denied any wrongdoing in the 1MDB affair. Yet the former Malaysian PM signed off on U.S. $34 billion of rail, pipeline and other deals with Chinese state companies, to be funded by Chinese banks and built by Chinese workers as part of President Xi Jinping's One Belt, One Road infrastructure project.</p>
<p>The project is controversial, with U.S. officials and other overseas analysts warning that Beijing is using the project to advance its strategic and military goals, while getting other developing countries deeply in its debt and boosting its hold over their governments.</p>
<p>Bruce Lui, senior journalism lecturer at the University of Hong Kong, said the offer reflects Communist Party attitudes to journalism.</p>
<p>"It is totally normal for the mainland authorities ... to monitor journalists, to obstruct their work, and to hide [things] from them," Lui said. "If this report is accurate, it would be entirely in keeping with [those methods]."</p>
<p>"There are many areas in which 'one country' trumps 'two systems'," he said, referring to China's promises that Hong Kong would remain a separate jurisdiction under the "one country, two systems" formula after the 1997 handover to Beijing, however.</p>
<p>Democratic Party lawmaker James To, deputy chair of the security committee of Hong Kong's Legislative Council (LegCo), said the report was a matter of concern.</p>
<p>"The central government does have the ability to act in this way in Hong Kong, but under Hong Kong's system, it has no right to go looking for journalists' details, whether or not it's to advance their diplomatic interests," To said.</p>
<p>"This is a crime under laws governing the use of communications," he said.</p>
<p>RFA contacted the offices of chief executive Carrie Lam and the secretary for security John Lee on Tuesday, but neither had responded to requests for comment by the time of writing.</p>
<p><b>‘The lovely people at Wen Wei Po’</b></p>
<p>The revelations come after Kevin Carrico, a lecturer at Macquarie University in Australia, reported being followed throughout a trip to Hong Kong by the pro-Beijing <i>Wen Wei Po</i> newspaper, which ran a front-page story about his visits to local political figures.</p>
<p>"The lovely people at <i>Wen Wei Po</i> stalked me for a week and wrote a cover story about me once I left HK," Carrico wrote after returning to Australia.</p>
<p>"Another overseas ‘pro-independence’ scholar comes to Hong Kong to teach ‘independence theory’ in the name of tourism!" the headline read.</p>
<p>Hong Kong was formerly regarded as a bastion of press freedom, with many international news organizations stationing regional editors and correspondents in the city.</p>
<p>But the rejection last October of a visa renewal application from Victor Mallet, the <i>Financial Times</i>' Hong Kong-based Asia editor, after he hosted a lunch event at the Foreign Correspondents' Club (FCC) at which pro-independence politician Andy Chan was the speaker signaled a sea change for journalists there.</p>
<p>Mallet defended the FCC event in the face of open criticism and requests to cancel Chan's appearance. His visa renewal was later rejected without explanation, and he was given just seven days to leave the city, and later turned away when he tried to re-enter as a visitor.</p>
<p>Alvin Yeung, who heads Hong Kong's Civic party, called on the Hong Kong government to clarify the situation.</p>
<p>"We are talking about public security officials in mainland China, who think that they are free to enter ordinary offices and homes in Hong Kong to set up surveillance," Yeung said. "Does the Hong Kong government know nothing about this, or is it acquiescing in their actions?"</p>
<p>Yeung said agents of the Chinese state have already engaged in suspected cross-border law enforcement, citing the case of U.K. national Lee Po, who was removed from his place of work in Hong Kong in 2015 and later showed up in police detention across the internal border in mainland China.</p>
<p>"If this report is true, it indicates that [the Chinese authorities] couldn't care less about 'one country, two systems'," he said.</p>
<p>A U.S. State Department policy report on Hong Kong said last May that the ruling Chinese Communist Party says one thing and does another when it comes to Hong Kong, often acting in ways that are inconsistent with the city's promised freedom to govern its own affairs.</p>
<p>Repeated comments from Chinese officials asserting the supremacy of the Chinese constitution last year served to "dilute" the concept of a "high degree of autonomy" enshrined in the 1984 Sino-British handover treaty and the city's mini-constitution, the Basic Law, the report said.</p>
<p><b>Murky circumstances</b></p>
<p>Hong Kong's Causeway Bay Books store made world headlines in 2015 when five of its staff members went missing in the course of two or three months.</p>
<p>Swedish national Gui Minhai, who headed the Mighty Current publishing house that owned Causeway Bay Books, "disappeared" under murky circumstances from his holiday home in Pattaya, Thailand on October 2015, only to reappear in China "confessing" on video to a decade-old alleged drunk-driving offense.</p>
<p>He now faces further charges of spying after being snatched from a train as he traveled to Beijing in the company of Swedish diplomats.</p>
<p>In the months that followed, store manager and British national Lee Bo, 65, went missing from his workplace in Hong Kong, and the group's general manager Lui Bo (also spelled Lui Por) and colleagues Cheung Chi-ping and Lam Wing-kei were also all detained.</p>
<p>They later resurfaced in China, which accused them of selling "banned books" in Hong Kong to customers across the internal border in mainland China.</p>
<p><i><b>Reported by Lau Siu-fung for RFA's Cantonese Service, and by Gao Feng for the Mandarin Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>hong kong, media, espionage, surveillance, ccp, corruption, belt and road</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Cambodia’s PM Hun Sen Calls For Political Dialogue at Event Marking End of Khmer Rouge Era</title>
        <guid>354e7499-8814-417e-b347-a292c73d4017</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/dialogue-01072019163412.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>But he falls short of inviting the now-dissolved main opposition party for talks.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 22:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/dialogue-01072019163412.html/cambodia-hun-sen-jan-7-2019-1000.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Cambodia's Prime Minister Hun Sen (C) waves to the crowd during an event marking the 40th anniversary of the end of the Khmer Rouge era at the Olympic Stadium in Phnom Penh, Jan. 7, 2019.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Hun Sen's Facebook page]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Cambodian Prime Minister Hun Sen, during a lavish ruling party celebration Monday to mark the 40th anniversary of the end of the bloody Khmer Rouge era, called for “wider political dialogue” in his country, but fell short of including the now-dissolved opposition Cambodia National Rescue Party (CNRP).<br/><br/>During an event attended by more than 60,000 people at Phnom Penh’s Olympic Stadium, Hun Sen thanked Vietnam for “aiding the struggle to liberate Cambodia and her people from the genocidal regime,” under whose 1975-79 rule an estimated 3 million people are believed to have died.<br/><br/>“The timely Jan. 7 [1979] victory saved millions of Cambodian lives who otherwise would have been subjected to death,” he said, suggesting Vietnam had merely aided the Cambodian National Salvation Front in overthrowing the Khmer Rouge, rather than invaded and taken control of the country.<br/><br/>“That day reintroduced and revived values, both spiritual and material, of the Khmer nation, brought to an end a dark chapter of Cambodia’s history, and opened a new era for the country—one of independence, freedom, democracy and social progress for its pitiful citizens. We have since provided Cambodian citizens all kinds of rights and freedoms for them to have true control over their own fates.”<br/><br/>After Vietnam marched on Phnom Penh, Hanoi administered the country for more than a decade, appointing Hun Sen prime minister and maintaining tens of thousands of troops on the ground.<br/><br/>After facing heavy international pressure and enduring significant military casualties, Vietnam withdrew its troops from Cambodia in September 1989 and two years later became a signatory to the Paris Peace Accord, which paved the way for the country to become a democracy.<br/><br/>During Monday’s event, Hun Sen also vowed to open Cambodia up to “wider political dialogue between all parties, civil society, and all progressive circles,” but fell short of mentioning the now-dissolved opposition Cambodia National Rescue Party (CNRP), which was banned by the Supreme Court in November 2017 for its role in an alleged plot to topple the government.<br/><br/>The court decision, which also slapped a five-year ban on the political activities of 118 of the CNRP’s senior officials, allowed the ruling Cambodian People’s Party (CPP) to effectively run uncontested in Cambodia’s July 29 general election and win all 125 seats in parliament.<br/><br/>Hun Sen said Monday that his government would promote wider political dialogue “to collect intellectual input and human resources from all sources, without discrimination, and to increase the total force for nation-state building and development.”<br/><br/>However, he warned against “a history that we cannot let resurface, as it causes national division due to the ambition of politicians who use our citizens as their tools to attain their personal interests without thinking about the fate of the nation.”<br/><br/><b><div class="image-inline captioned" style="width:1000px;">
<div style="width:1000px;">
<img alt="Marchers parade through Phnom Penh's Olympic Stadium at an event marking the 40th anniversary of the end of the Khmer Rouge era in Phnom Penh, Jan. 7, 2019. Credit: Hun Sen's Facebook page" src="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/dialogue-01072019163412.html/cambodia-parade-jan-7-2019-1000.jpg" title="Marchers parade through Phnom Penh's Olympic Stadium at an event marking the 40th anniversary of the end of the Khmer Rouge era in Phnom Penh, Jan. 7, 2019. Credit: Hun Sen's Facebook page"/>
</div>
<div class="image-caption">
<span style="width:1000px;">Marchers parade through Phnom Penh's Olympic Stadium at an event marking the 40th anniversary of the end of the Khmer Rouge era in Phnom Penh, Jan. 7, 2019. Credit: Hun Sen's Facebook page</span>
<span class="copyright"> </span>
</div>
<div id="zoomattribute">
<a class="single_image" href="/english/news/cambodia/dialogue-01072019163412.html/cambodia-parade-jan-7-2019-1000.jpg" title="Marchers parade through Phnom Penh's Olympic Stadium at an event marking the 40th anniversary of the end of the Khmer Rouge era in Phnom Penh, Jan. 7, 2019. Credit: Hun Sen's Facebook page">
<img src="/rfa_resources/graphics/icon-zoom.png"/>
</a>
</div>
</div>Political dialogue</b><br/><br/>Speaking to RFA’s Khmer Service after the ceremony, senior CNRP official and former lawmaker Um Sam An rejected the idea that Hun Sen is seeking national reconciliation.<br/><br/>“Even if he intends to promote comprehensive dialogue, he will not hold talks with all political parties—particularly the CNRP or civil society organizations that work transparently, fairly, and independent of the government,” he said.<br/><br/>“He only will hold dialogue with minor political parties that serve as his puppets.”<br/><br/>When asked for clarification about Hun Sen’s statement, CPP spokesperson Chhim Phal Vearun told RFA that it should not be taken as an invitation to dialogue with the CNRP.<br/><br/>“This doesn’t suggest that [dialogue] will be held with the now-defunct party—Hun Sen referred only to parties with legal status under Cambodian law,” he said.<br/><br/>Veteran political analyst Lao Mong Hay told RFA that Hun Sen was continuing to isolate himself from the international community by refusing to reinstate the CNRP and restoring political rights to its officials.<br/><br/>Since the election, the U.S. has announced visa bans on individuals seen as limiting democracy in the country, as part of a series of measures aimed at pressuring Cambodia to reverse course, and the European Union, which was the second biggest trade partner of Cambodia in 2017, has said it will drop a preferential trade scheme for Cambodian exports based on the country’s election environment.<br/><br/>Meanwhile, Soeng Sen Karuna, spokesman for local rights group Adhoc, applauded Hun Sen’s promise, noting that civil society has faced difficulties in working with the government at all levels, and has even been accused of staging a revolution for campaigning on behalf of human rights and efforts to ensure free and fair elections.<br/><br/>“We welcome his remarks, but we don’t know from now on whether they will be effectively implemented,” he said.<br/><br/>“The Interior Ministry has already issued a notification to open the space for civil society, but in practice, things have not been improving. For instance, we were obstructed from holding an event to celebrate International Human Rights Day on Jan. 3.”<br/><br/><b>Liberation or invasion</b><br/><br/>Hun Sen’s remarks about Vietnam also drew condemnation on Monday from observers who called Jan. 7 is a day of “invasion,” rather than liberation.<br/><br/>Acting CNRP President Sam Rainsy, who is living in self-imposed exile to avoid a string of convictions by courts seen as beholden to Hun Sen, called the prime minister a “usurper” who was first “installed by the invading Vietnamese Communist army in 1979.”<br/><br/>“He has since clung to power through election manipulation, terror and violence,” he said, in a message posted to his Facebook account.<br/><br/>Ly Srey Sros, a youth political analyst, told RFA that Jan. 7 is a day “with both good and bad connotations” for Cambodia’s youth.<br/><br/>“Vietnam’s intervention in Cambodia can be considered a success story for Cambodian citizens in that they were able to escape the genocidal regime, but we must admit that based on international law, such an intervention was a violation of Cambodia’s sovereignty,” she said.<br/><br/>Sophal Ear, associate professor of World Affairs at Occidental College in Los Angeles, called Vietnam’s intervention “both a liberation and catastrophe for Cambodia.”<br/><br/>“It brought liberation from the Khmer Rouge, but it also brought to power a group of individuals who, 40 years later, are still in power,” he said.<br/><br/>“In that time, Cambodia went from a Vietnamese colony to a Chinese colony,” he added, referring to Beijing’s increasing influence in the Southeast Asian nation.<br/><br/>In the lead up to Monday’s celebration, hundreds of ethnic Cambodians living in Australia and the U.S. staged “anti-Jan. 7 Day” protests over the weekend, referring to the anniversary as a “day of grief” marking a “foreign occupation” of Cambodia.<br/><br/>Animosity between Vietnam and Cambodia goes back centuries, but was heightened by the Vietnamese war in 1979, and accusations over the demarcation of the border between the two countries have become a prominent feature in Cambodian politics as Hun Sen’s opponents have attempted to paint the strong man as a tool of the Vietnamese.<br/><br/>Hanoi’s state-run Vietnam News Agency reported that the two countries held a ceremony on Jan. 4 in the Vietnamese capital to mark the “victory of the southwest border defense war and the joint victory on January 7 of Vietnam and Cambodia over the genocidal regime.” <br/><br/><i><b>Reported by RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Sovannarith Keo. Written in English by Joshua Lipes.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>khmer rouge, genocide, cambodia elections, cnrp, cpp, hun sen, sam rainsy</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Cambodia’s One-Party Parliament Approves Expansion of Councilor Positions With Eye on Opposition</title>
        <guid>5ecb6c3e-718c-4e67-81c7-df9bfb9717f6</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/parliament-01032019170029.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>Prime Minister Hun Sen had earlier suggested the move would encourage the opposition to defect.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 22:55:46 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/parliament-01032019170029.html/cambodia-cnrp-poipet-meeting-jan-2019-1000.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Opposition CNRP activists gather in Banteay Meanchey's Poipet city, Jan. 1, 2019.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Photo provided by an RFA listener]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Cambodia’s rubber stamp parliament on Thursday approved draft laws to increase the number of local level government positions, after Prime Minister Hun Sen suggested such legislation would encourage opposition officials whose party he had dissolved to defect to his ruling Cambodian People’s Party (CPP).<br/><br/>Leng Peng Long, the spokesman for the one-party National Assembly, told RFA’s Khmer Service that CPP lawmakers unanimously voted in favor of draft laws amending the administrative management of the capital, provinces, municipalities and districts, and passed them on to the Senate, where they are likely to be approved before being signed into law by King Norodom Sihamoni.<br/><br/>Ruling party lawmakers Cheam Yeap and Hun Neang had said in a proposal for the draft laws that current laws were put into place in 2008 and no longer reflect the needs of Cambodia’s changing electorate.<br/><br/>“The population has increased, requiring more effective services to address the peoples’ needs,” they wrote ahead of submitting the draft laws for approval.<br/><br/>The proposed draft law called for an increase in the number of municipality councilors from 21 to 27, provincial councilors from 15 to 27, capital councilors from 11 to 21, and district councilors from 11 to 21.<br/><br/>The CPP effectively ran uncontested in Cambodia’s July 29 general election and won all 125 seats in parliament after the Supreme Court dissolved the main opposition Cambodia National Rescue Party (CNRP) in November 2017 and slapped a five-year ban on the political activities of 118 of its senior officials for the party’s role in an alleged plot to topple the government.<br/><br/>Last week, Hun Sen’s Constitutional Council unanimously approved an amendment to the draft law on political parties, paving the way for the reinstatement of rights to the 118 CNRP officials banned from politics by the Supreme Court’s decision.<br/><br/>The legislation does not provide for the reestablishment of the CNRP, and Hun Sen has said the political rights of the officials will only be reinstated if they had “shown respect for the Supreme Court’s ruling,” and provided they each make an individual request.<br/><br/>The move is widely seen as part of a bid by Hun Sen to ease international pressure on his government in response to a crackdown on the opposition, NGOs and the independent media in the lead up to July’s election. Critics have called it a “trap” aimed at fracturing the CNRP.<br/><br/>Hun Sen has regularly called on CNRP officials to defect since their party was dissolved and recently suggested that increasing the number of local level government positions in Cambodia would entice formerly elected opposition members to return to politics with the CPP.<br/><br/>On Thursday, former CNRP councilor of Kampong Thom Province Thai Tim told RFA there are already too many councilor positions in Cambodia and that additional ones are unnecessary.<br/><br/>“The CPP is increasing the number of councilors purely as a benefit to party members,” he said.<br/><br/>San Chey, president of local nongovernmental organization Network for Social Accountability, echoed Thai Tim’s concerns, adding that instead of adding more councilors, the current ones should be made more effective through better training and increased budgets.<br/><br/>“We have enough councilors, what we need is to improve their capabilities,” he said.<br/><br/>San Chey added that younger candidates should also be given a chance to act as councilors to promote new approaches to governance.<br/><br/><b>Opposition targeted</b><br/><br/>While the government has extended an olive branch to CNRP members who are willing to defect to the CPP, it has targeted those who continue to pledge allegiance to the now-dissolved opposition party.<br/><br/>At least three former CNRP officials and commune councilors in Banteay Meanchey province were recently forced by police to sign contracts vowing to sever ties with the party, while security forces are seeking to question several people who gathered earlier this week in support of acting CNRP president Sam Rainsy after he pledged to return from self-imposed exile before March to lead them.<br/><br/>Khun Chanty, a formerly elected CNRP chief of Banteay Meanchey’s Poipet city, told RFA that she and two other former CNRP officials were made to sign affidavits that that would “keep our political opinions to ourselves” and refrain from making public statements about their party.<br/><br/>“We have been deprived of political rights as guaranteed in the constitution,” she told RFA.<br/><br/>“I don’t see the reason for a constitution when the authorities simply turn a blind eye to it.”<br/><br/>Meanwhile, “several others are on the run” from the authorities, Khun Chanty said.<br/><br/>Another CNRP official in Banteay Meanchey, Cheath Khemara, told RFA that police have cracked down on opposition activities since more than 100 CNRP members gathered in Poipet on Jan. 1 at the home of an activist named Khann Lai in support of Sam Rainsy, who has been living abroad to avoid a string of convictions issued by courts seen as acting at Hun Sen’s direction.<br/><br/>Cheath Khemara said several senior CNRP officials in Banteay Meanchey’s Au Chrov, Thma Puok and Mongkul Borei districts have been summoned for questioning and intimidated over the assembly.<br/><br/>Khann Lai told RFA that he was brought in by police on Wednesday and made to sign a document pledging that he would not host another gathering to honor Sam Rainsy, who assumed leadership of the CNRP while the party’s president, Kem Sokha, is held under house arrest awaiting a trial on charges of “treason.”<br/><br/>“I was questioned in a way that I made me feel intimidated, but I did nothing wrong,” he said.<br/><br/>A campaigner with local human rights group Adhoc in Banteay Meanchey named Sum Chankea said he was aware of “at least 10 policemen” who were recently seen questioning people that allowed CNRP activists to gather at their homes.<br/><br/>“The authorities can’t go around intimidating people like this,” he said.<br/><br/>“They need to understand the law. There is no law that prohibits people from gathering to voice their political views.”<br/><br/>Thin Sindeth, a police officer in Poipet, hung up the phone when questioned by RFA about official intimidation of CNRP officials and activists, while other police officers have said that the public can “support any party, as long as it isn’t the CNRP.”<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Samean Yun and Nareth Muong. Written in English by Joshua Lipes.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>national assembly, cnrp, cpp, cambodia elections, democracy, hun sen, sam rainsy</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Hong Kong Protest Group Hits Back at Criticism of Pro-Independence Banners</title>
        <guid>6f2bd61a-a73f-488f-96bd-d704ed5a0e68</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/hong-kong-protest-group-hits-back-01022019112159.html</link>

	    
	         <category>China</category>
	    

        <description>Hong Kong's government bans 'activities promoting or advocating' independence for the city from a square outside its headquarters.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 16:34:14 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/hong-kong-protest-group-hits-back-01022019112159.html/china-hong-kong-new-years-day-demonstration-jan1-2019.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[A group of Hong Kong independence supporters display flags during the annual New Year's Day pro-democracy rally in Hong Kong, Jan. 1, 2019. ]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Pro-democracy activists in Hong Kong on Wednesday hit out at the city's government for condemning the appearance of placards advocating independence during a new-year protest march, saying that freedom of speech is enshrined in the territory's mini-constitution, the Basic Law.</p>
<p>The protesters had "ignored the advice of security guards" and carried the banners into Civic Square outside the east wing of government headquarters at the end of the march, the government said in a statement after the march.</p>
<p>Scuffles around the placards had caused "confusing and two security guards falling on the ground," it said, banning any "activities advocating or promoting" independence for Hong Kong from the area.</p>
<p>It said a pro-independence activist had later addressed the rally, "undermining the constitutional order of [Hong Kong]" and expressed "deep regret" that the Civil Human Rights Front, which organized the traditional Jan. 1 protest march to government headquarters, hadn't prevented this from happening.</p>
<p>But Jimmy Sham of the Civil Human Rights Front said it wasn't the group's job to police the content of demonstrations.</p>
<p>"The Civil Human Rights Front won't become an accomplice in the government's suppression of human rights," Sham said, calling on chief executive Carrie Lam to remember her negative popularity ratings in opinion polls.</p>
<p>"The people [of Hong Kong] don't recognize her as chief executive, and the Jan. 1 march was just the start," he said. "We will be doing everything we can in future to encourage people to break out of their feelings of helplessness, and to stand up together for Hong Kong people's values."</p>
<p>Sham's response was echoed by one participant at Tuesday's march.</p>
<p>"Independence for Hong Kong is an entirely legal, reasonable and acceptable position," the protester said.</p>
<p>And pro-independence student activist Wayne Chan said the placards weren't obviously pro-independence, however, and that the security guards had done nothing to prevent people waving the British colonial-era flag of Hong Kong from entering Civic Square.</p>
<p>"They never said why the two [contested] placards were pro-independence," Chan told RFA. "The way they approached it was extremely inappropriate, and the whole rally could have finished up smoothly and peacefully if they hadn't placed those barriers there, which made no sense."</p>
<p>Hong Kong was promised the continuation of its existing freedoms of press, publication and association, as well as a separate and independent judiciary, under the terms of its 1997 return to Chinese rule, within the "one country, two systems" framework agreed between British and Chinese officials and enshrined in its mini-constitution, the Basic Law.</p>
<p>But the city's freedom and autonomy are now being eroded in the wake of repeated interventions in the city’s political life by Beijing, according to overseas governments and human rights organizations.</p>
<p>Nine Hong Kong politicians have been barred from candidacy in elections in the city in recent years, while six pro-democracy LegCo members were stripped of their seats when Beijing's parliament ruled their oaths of allegiance invalid.</p>
<p><i><b>Reported by Lee Wang-yam for RFA's Cantonese Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>hong kong, protest, carrie lam, human rights</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>New Chinese Ambassador to Cambodia Slams Western Criticism of Hun Sen Regime Over ‘Minor Issues’</title>
        <guid>34d5b379-3e29-424e-91e2-e1f65fa091f6</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/ambassador-12282018135116.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>Wang Wentian dismisses concerns over China-Cambodia ties leading to further democratic rollbacks.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 19:18:38 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/ambassador-12282018135116.html/cambodia-villager-chinese-flag-july-2018.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[A woman shields herself from the sun with a Chinese national flag as she listens to Prime Minister Hun Sen speak during the inauguration of a China-funded bridge in Phnom Penh, July 2, 2018.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AP Photo]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>China’s top diplomat in Cambodia has dismissed criticism from Western governments over Prime Minister Hun Sen’s regime and its ties to Beijing, amid concerns over reversals of democracy following a general election widely seen as unfree and unfair and a wider crackdown on civil society.<br/><br/>Wang Wentian, the newly appointed Chinese ambassador to Cambodia, met with Hun Sen on Friday at the Council of Ministers building in the capital Phnom Penh, after which the prime minister posted a message to his Facebook page saying Wang had pledged to “bolster relations for the sake of people” and referring to ties between the countries as “forged in steel.”<br/><br/>The meeting followed one between Wang and Cambodia’s Foreign Minister Prak Sokhonn on Dec. 25, during which the two pledged to further improve bilateral relations and the Chinese diplomat expressed Beijing’s “strong support” for Hun Sen’s government, according to a statement issued Thursday by Cambodia’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs.<br/><br/>Following the meeting between Wang and Prak Sokhonn, Cambodia’s Foreign Affairs spokesman Ket Sophann told local media that Wang had “slammed the West” for taking a harsh stance against Hun Sen’s government.<br/><br/>“The ambassador said that ‘certain foreign countries’ have criticized Cambodia over minor issues,” he said.<br/><br/>Wang specifically mentioned concerns raised by Washington with Phnom Penh last month following a Nov. 15 report by Hong Kong’s Asia Times online news portal, which cited unnamed diplomatic sources as saying that a 45,000 hectare (111,200-acre) Chinese naval base is being built in Cambodia’s Koh Kong province.<br/><br/>Hun Sen later dismissed the report, saying such a move would violate the constitution, while Cambodia’s Ministry of National Defense called it “fake news” and part of a “foreign campaign to mislead the public and the international community with the intention of destroying the country’s independence and neutrality.”<br/><br/>Chinese investment has poured into Cambodia in recent years and has caused some Cambodians to question what type of influence Beijing might have over their government. China and Cambodia have recently held joint military exercises and Beijing has pledged to help fund a modernization of the Southeast Asian nation’s military.<br/><br/>If such a naval base were built on the Gulf of Thailand, it would allow China to significantly expand patrols on the South China Sea, which Beijing claims much of, while rival Taiwan and ASEAN countries Brunei, Malaysia, the Philippines and Vietnam have their own stakes in the waters.<br/><br/>Political analyst Kim Sok told RFA’s Khmer Service on Friday that a Chinese naval base in Cambodia “is no small issue” because it would directly affect the stability of the country by impacting international relations and triggering anti-Chinese nationalist protests domestically.<br/><br/>Furthermore, he said, improved relations with China would do little to improve Cambodia’s international standing as it “plunges towards dictatorship” amid restrictions on the political opposition.<br/><br/>“Communists have little regard for freedom,” he said.<br/><br/><b>Western criticism</b><br/><br/>The Asia Times report comes amid wider cooperation between Cambodia and China at a time when Western governments have criticized Hun Sen and his ruling Cambodian People’s Party (CPP) over rollbacks on democracy in the lead up to and aftermath of a July 29 election in which the CPP effectively ran uncontested and won all 125 seats after a ban of the opposition party.<br/><br/>The CPP overwhelmingly won the election following the Supreme Court’s November 2017 dissolution of the main opposition Cambodia National Rescue Party (CNRP) and a five-year ban on the political activities of 118 of its senior officials for the party’s role in an alleged plot to topple the government.<br/><br/>The lead up to the polls also saw Hun Sen implement a severe crackdown on nongovernmental organizations and the independent media, in what was seen as a bid to eliminate criticism of his leadership.<br/><br/>The U.S. has since announced visa bans on individuals seen as limiting democracy in the country, as part of a series of measures aimed at pressuring Cambodia to reverse course, and the European Union, which was the second biggest trade partner of Cambodia in 2017, has said it will drop a preferential trade scheme for Cambodian exports based on the country’s election environment.<br/><br/>Hun Sen has repeatedly stressed that his country does not need foreign governments to recognize the legitimacy of Cambodia’s elections, saying acceptance by Cambodians is sufficient.<br/><br/>He has also said that he will continue to welcome aid from China, which is poised to overtake the U.S. as the world’s top foreign donor, and which is currently Cambodia’s largest international aid provider.<br/><br/>China, which typically offers aid to countries without many of the prerequisites that the U.S. and EU place on donations, such as improvements to human rights, offered “sincere congratulations” to Hun Sen’s party for its showing in July’s polls.<br/><br/>Trade volume between Cambodia and China was valued at U.S. $5.8 billion in 2017, up 22 percent from U.S. $4.76 billion dollars a year earlier, while China is currently Cambodia’s largest investor, and has poured U.S. $12.6 billion into the Southeast Asian nation from 1994 to 2017.<br/><br/>Hun Sen also met Friday with Ngo Xuan Lich, the Minister of Defense for Cambodia’s one-party Communist neighbor Vietnam, which has similarly pledged its support for his regime.<br/><br/>Following the meeting, Hun Sen posted a message on his Facebook page saying that Lich had congratulated him on his election victory and announced a donation of U.S. $10 million from Vietnam to construct a new building for Cambodia’s Ministry of Defense.<br/><b><br/>Amendment approved</b><br/><br/>Meanwhile, Cambodia’s Constitutional Council on Friday unanimously approved an amendment to the draft law on political parties, paving the way for the reinstatement of rights to the 118 CNRP officials banned from politics by last year’s Supreme Court decision.<br/><br/>With CPP control of the country secured, Cambodia’s now one-party National Assembly recently submitted an amended version of a draft law on political parties for review to Hun Sen’s Constitutional Council, which approved it Friday and will forward it to King Norodom Sihamoni to sign into law.<br/><br/>The king is widely expected to rubber stamp the legislation, which would permit the 118 officials to reenter politics, although it does not provide for the reestablishment of the CNRP. Hun Sen has said the political rights of the officials will only be reinstated if they had “shown respect for the Supreme Court’s ruling,” and provided they each make an individual request.<br/><br/>The move is widely seen as part of a bid by Hun Sen to ease international pressure on his government in response to limiting democratic freedoms in the lead up to July’s election, in which the CPP won all 125 seats being contested. Critics have called it a “trap” aimed at fracturing the opposition.<br/><br/>Speaking to RFA on Friday, acting CNRP president Sam Rainsy said the 118 opposition officials have no intention of requesting permission to return to politics because there was no legitimate basis for the dissolution of their party in the first place, adding that Hun Sen had orchestrated the Supreme Court’s ban last year.<br/><br/>“We can’t recognize the court’s decision and we won’t ask for a pardon because we didn’t commit any crime,” said the opposition chief, who is living in self-imposed exile to avoid a string of politically motivated convictions.<br/><br/>Sam Rainsy also reiterated a pledge to return to Cambodia to lead the opposition before March next year, despite threats of arrest from Hun Sen, but said he could not provide an exact date for his trip.<br/><br/>CNRP deputy president Mu Sochua, who is also living in self-imposed exile, told RFA Friday that she intends to return to Cambodia in April and expects to be imprisoned upon her arrival. <br/><br/><i><b>Reported by RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Samean Yun. Written in English by Joshua Lipes.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>military, south china sea, hun sen, china, regional influence, cambodia elections, democracy, sam rainsy, hun sen, cnrp, cpp</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Cambodian Opposition Activists Summoned by Police, Pressured to Defect</title>
        <guid>4724f792-e92e-472a-978c-33afeab44d38</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/summoned-12202018170914.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>The move follows a pledge by CNRP leader Sam Rainsy to return to Cambodia to 'fight for democracy' in the country ruled by Hun Sen for 33 years.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/summoned-12202018170914.html/khmer-skype2-122018.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Cambodia National Rescue Party leader Sam Rainsy speaks to RFA in an interview on Skype in a file photo.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[RFA]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Following a recent pledge by opposition leader Rainsy to return next year to Cambodia, police in Kandal province have questioned local  Cambodia National Rescue Party (CNRP) activists concerning their possible support for the party’s acting president in the event he comes back, Cambodian sources say.</p>
<p>Summoned by Akreiy Ksatr commune police on Dec. 20, the eight activists were told to defect to the ruling Cambodian People’s Party (CPP), former CNRP commune chief Touch Savuth told RFA’s Khmer Service on Thursday.</p>
<p>Resisting police pressure, Touch Savuth refused to change her party affiliation, she said.</p>
<p>“I have chosen my party in order to change our country’s leader, who is a dictator and corrupt,” Touch Savuth said, referring to Cambodian Prime Minister Hun Sen, who has ruled the Southeast Asian country for more than 30 years.</p>
<p>Tong Sarun, another activist, said police had forced him to promise not to write on a Facebook page connected to the CNRP, which was dissolved by Supreme Court order last year, allowing Hun Sen to sweep national elections in July without effective opposition.</p>
<p>“They forced me to sign,” Tong Sarun said. “I am very upset, but for the sake of my safety and security I had to do it.”</p>
<p>Reached for comment, commune police chief An Penh declined to comment on the summons, but said that all eight activists called in were no longer members of the CNRP.</p>
<p>Provincial CNRP leaders meanwhile welcomed the news of Sam Rainsy’s promised return, vowing their support for the opposition leader who fled Cambodia into exile following a string of convictions in court cases widely seen as politically motivated.</p>
<p>“We are ready to go to prison with Sam Rainsy if authorities arrest us,” Dim Savoeun—a CNRP leader from northwestern Cambodia’s Battambang province—told RFA. “We have been with Sam Rainsy for 10 to 20 years, and we know that he is working for the sake of our country.”</p>
<p>Cambodian government spokesman Phay Siphan was unavailable for comment Thursday, but has previously said that opposition activists are free to discuss Sam Rainsy’s return as long as they provoke no “instability” in the country.</p>
<p><b>'A vital move'</b></p>
<p>Political analyst Kim Sok meanwhile called Sam Rainsy’s return to Cambodia a vital move in the country’s “fight for freedom and democracy.”</p>
<p>The ruling CPP will find it difficult to arrest not just Sam Rainsy but all of his supporters, he said.</p>
<p>“Hun Sen is afraid of Sam Rainsy, so the CPP will try again and again to frighten him out of the country,” he said.</p>
<p>Cambodian opposition politician Sam Rainsy, living in self-imposed exile since 2016, vowed on Dec.16  to return to Cambodia next year to fight for democracy, amid stark divisions among the government’s political opponents.</p>
<p>“I am asking all Cambodians to rise up and join me at that time, so that we can jointly fight for real change,” Sam Rainsy said, adding, “We need to stand up against Hun Sen and bring back democracy in 2019.”</p>
<p>Once the major opposition party to Prime Minister Hun Sen’s ruling CPP, the CNRP was dissolved by Cambodia’s Supreme Court in Nov. 2017.</p>
<p>Sam Rainsy cofounded the party in 2012 after merging his Sam Rainsy Party with Kem Sokha’s Human Rights Party. Sam Rainsy served as the new party’s president, but stepped down while in exile in Feb. 2017 in favor of Kem Sokha, who was then vice president.</p>
<p>With Kem Sokha currently under house arrest while awaiting trial on charges of treason, Sam Rainsy became acting president on Dec. 9 after being nominated during a two-day international conference of the CNRP in Atlanta that was boycotted by Kem Sokha’s supporters.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, in a Dec. 20 statement released following a two-day meeting of the CPP, the ruling party vowed to continue on its present political course and to resist international pressure to enact reforms, saying “powerful nations” have used calls for human rights and democratic values only to interfere in Cambodia’s internal affairs.</p>
<p><i><b>Reported by Vannarith Im for RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Samean Yun. Written in English by Richard Finney.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>democracy, reform, cnrp, cpp, sam rainsy, hun sen</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Cambodia’s Supreme Court Upholds Defamation Verdict Against Acting Opposition Chief Sam Rainsy</title>
        <guid>dd77a93e-a73f-42b7-adc6-7a3158e76aff</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/upheld-12192018160029.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>Sam Rainsy had alleged that Prime Minister Hun Sen bribed a social media activist to attack his party.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 21:27:55 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/japan-04132018145049.html/cambodia-sam-rainsy-tokyo-april-2018.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Cambodia's self-exiled opposition leader Sam Rainsy speaks during a press conference in Tokyo, April 13, 2018.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AP Photo]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Cambodia’s Supreme Court on Wednesday upheld a lower court ruling to fine the acting president of the country’s now-dissolved opposition Cambodia National Rescue Party (CNRP) Sam Rainsy for defamation in connection with a lawsuit brought against him by Prime Minister Hun Sen.<br/><br/>In December last year, the Phnom Penh Municipal Court ordered Sam Rainsy—who has been living in self-imposed exile since 2015 to avoid convictions on charges widely seen as politically motivated—to pay 4 billion riel (U.S. $1 million) for a January 2017 Facebook post which alleged that Hun Sen had offered pro-government social media activist Thy Sovantha U.S. $1 million to attack the CNRP.<br/><br/>Sam Rainsy, who was found guilty in absentia, was also ordered to pay a fine of 10 million riel (U.S. $2,500) to the state.<br/><br/>On Wednesday, presiding judge Kim Sathavy dismissed Sam Rainsy’s appeal and said the Phnom Penh Municipal Court’s ruling, and an Appeal Court verdict earlier this year that upheld the ruling, were correct.<br/><br/>CNRP Vice President Mu Sochua, who is also living in self-imposed exile, called the Supreme Court’s decision “unjust and unacceptable.”<br/><br/>“Cambodian court decisions at all levels are illegitimate,” she said.<br/><br/>“They regularly fail to provide justice to members of the public and particularly to the leaders of the opposition. It is very unfortunate for Cambodia.”<br/><br/>The acting CNRP president’s accusation stemmed from leaked social media messages between Hun Sen and Thy Sovantha in November 2016, in which they discussed bringing down the opposition party, which was dissolved by the Supreme Court in November 2017 for allegedly working to topple the government with the backing of Washington.<br/><br/>In the leaked messages, Hun Sen calls Thy Sovantha “grandchild” and offers her U.S. $1 million. Thy Sovantha has said her page was hacked.<br/><br/>The Prime Minister has demanded that Sam Rainsy pay him compensation as ordered by the court and has promised to seize the acting CNRP chief’s home in Phnom Penh if he does not.<br/><br/>On Wednesday, Hun Sen’s lawyer, Ky Tech, told the Khmer Times he would seek an order from the Phnom Penh Municipal Court to seize Sam Rainsy’s house, which was the now-dissolved CNRP’s headquarters, for compensation. <br/><br/><i><b>Reported by Tin Zakariya for RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Samean Yun. Written in English by Joshua Lipes.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>defamation, sam rainsy, cnrp, cpp, judiciary, hun sen, cambodia elections</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Cambodia's Hun Sen Blasts RFA Despite Promises of Welcome to 'Return'</title>
        <guid>85e9b436-b5d7-4161-af97-036205bc6e79</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/blasts-12172018163924.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>The prime minister refuses to speak to an RFA reporter, accusing the international broadcaster of bias against him.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 22:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/blasts-12172018163924.html/khmer-freed2-121718.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Former RFA reporters Uon Chhin and Yeang Sothearin walk out of Prey Sar Prison in Phnom Penh, Aug. 21, 2018.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>In a rare phone interview with Radio Free Asia, Cambodian Prime Minister Hun Sen has lambasted the U.S.-funded broadcaster despite recent conciliatory comments by his government suggesting RFA was welcome to resume its operations in the Southeastern Asian nation.</p>
<p>An RFA reporter in Washington called Hun Sen on Friday regarding another matter entirely—whether the FUNCINPEC party might be chosen as new partner with his one-party government. Hun Sen did not answer that question but launched into a tirade against RFA, accusing it of publishing false news. Prompted twice, he did not substantiate his accusation.</p>
<p>“Your radio is so bad. You can quote my statement on this. Your radio is so bad that I cannot speak with you. You broadcast differently from reality,” Hun Sen said.</p>
<p>“When I said west, you say east. I said about something white, you wrote about something black. You don’t need to ask me anything. I won’t answer your questions. You can listen from other people,” he said.</p>
<p>RFA closed its nearly 20-year old bureau in the Cambodian capital in September 2017 amid a government crackdown on independent media, NGOs and independent critics ahead of national elections in July of this year. With the main opposition party outlawed, Hun Sen’s Cambodian People’s Party swept every parliamentary seat.</p>
<p>Over the years, Cambodian journalists working for RFA had reported on corruption, illegal logging, forced evictions, and other issues largely ignored by state-controlled media. RFA is funded by the U.S. Congress but maintains editorial independence.</p>
<p>Challenged to explain why he was accusing RFA of being bad and biased, Hun Sen responded: “You’re crazy. I have said that I would not answer your questions. Yet you are still asking me questions. Go ahead and broadcast my words to prove you are a smart-ass. Sure enough! Your stupidity is now proven!”</p>
<p>When asked why he thought RFA was stupid, the prime minister hung up.</p>
<p><b>Welcome back</b></p>
<p>His blunt comments are in contrast to the more conciliatory remarks from his interior minister and the information ministry in the past two weeks, suggesting RFA was free to return to Cambodia.</p>
<p>On Dec. 5, Interior Minister Sar Kheng contended that RFA and Voice of America—which has been taken off the airwaves inside Cambodia but is still able to report in the country—had not been pressured to close their offices in the country in the first place.</p>
<p>“Now we welcome them back. We welcome them to reopen their offices here again,” he said.</p>
<p>Although the interior minister says RFA’s decision to leave Cambodia was not taken under pressure, it followed the authorities’ closure of independent radio stations carrying RFA reports, citing alleged tax and administrative violations. RFA was also accused of failing to pay taxes.</p>
<p>Two months after RFA closed its office, two of its former reporters there, Uon Chhin and Yeang Sothearin, were arrested and charged with espionage. They deny the charges, which are still pending. They were detained for nine months before being released on bail in August.</p>
<p>Sar Kheng’s comments had followed an earlier statement from the Ministry of Foreign Affairs expressing Cambodia’s commitment to “strengthen democracy and political space” including the promotion of freedom of the press and freedom of expression.</p>
<p>The government is now preparing legislative changes that would allow 118 members of the opposition Cambodia National Rescue Party to reenter politics, although the draft law does not allow for the re-establishment of the party.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, the same ministry on Dec. 10 repeated its unfounded accusation that RFA has operated in secret and sought to tarnish the reputation of the Cambodian government.</p>
<p><b>International pressure</b></p>
<p>Pa Nguon Teang, president of the non-government Cambodian Center for Independent Media, told RFA that Hun Sen is under international pressure to soften his attitude toward the media and civil society.</p>
<p>The United States has announced visa restrictions against unnamed government officials accused of undermining democracy in Cambodia. The European Union, which accounts for about 40 percent of Cambodian garment exports, is moving closer to stripping the country of crucial trade benefits in response to the suppression of democracy.</p>
<p>“During the first six months after [the] EU has notified the government of Cambodia of the procedures to withdraw EBA, Hun Sen shows signs of backing down,” Pa Nguon Teang said, referring to the European bloc’s “Everything But Arms” trade program.</p>
<p>But political analyst Kim Sok was skeptical that Hun Sen had had a change of heart since the election which left the ruling Cambodian People’s Party with complete control of parliament. He said that Hun Sen appears to be employing a similar strategy as he has in the past—escalating pressure, then reducing it to allay international criticism.<br/><i><b></b></i></p>
<p><i><b>Reported by <span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Vannarith Im for</span> RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Nareth Muong. Written in English by Matthew Pennington. </b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>hun sen, media, censorship</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Hong Kong's Occupy Central Trial Ends, Ruling Expected in April</title>
        <guid>981ddf52-7304-4a8b-9c22-7def4ebb16d5</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/trial-12142018103741.html</link>

	    
	         <category>China</category>
	    

        <description>Occupy Central co-founder Benny Tai warns of a 'chilling effect' if the nine defendants are found guilty of public order charges.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 15:41:56 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/trial-12142018103741.html/china-benny-tai-nov-2018-1000.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Benny Tai (C) at a press conference in Hong Kong in November 2018.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Reuters]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Hong Kong's trial of nine pro-democracy activists accused of "inciting" the 2014 Occupy Central movement has ended, with a verdict to be handed down in April.<br/><br/>The District Court said on Friday it will announce its ruling on April 9, on whether the nine defendants, including movement initiators Benny Tai, Chan Kin-man and the Rev. Chu Yiu-ming had caused a "public nuisance" by encouraging the protests.<br/><br/>The nine defendants, who also include barrister and lawmaker Tanya Chan, former lawmaker Lee Wing-tat and democracy activists Eason Chung, Raphael Wong and Tommy Cheung, argued that a reasonable member of the public would be tolerant of the protests, owing to the importance of the movement for fully democratic elections that had been ruled out by Beijing.<br/><br/>All nine pleaded "not guilty."<br/><br/>But the prosecution argued that the worthiness of the protests was irrelevant to the case against the nine, and that the court should base its finding on the facts, including the extent of obstruction to the public from the use of major highways.<br/><br/>The protests calling for universal suffrage grew out of a week-long student strike following an Aug. 31, 2014 ruling from China's National People's Congress (NPC) standing committee insisting on the vetting of electoral candidates if universal suffrage was to go ahead.<br/><br/>The ruling was also rejected by pan-democratic lawmakers as "fake universal suffrage."<br/><br/>In June 2014, an unofficial referendum saw 400,000 people vote in favor of universal suffrage and unrestricted nominations, in spite of a central government white paper spelling out that the city's autonomy was still subject to the will of Beijing, and didn't constitute full autonomy or decentralized power.<br/><br/>Protesters broke through into the shuttered-off Civic Square outside government headquarters on Sept. 27, bringing thousands of protesters onto the streets of nearby Admiralty.<br/><br/>Public anger soared when police used tear gas, batons and pepper spray against unarmed protesters on Sept. 28, bringing hundreds of thousands of people onto the city's streets at its height, many of them calling for fully democratic elections.<br/><br/>Hong Kong was promised the continuation of its existing freedoms of press, publication and association, as well as a separate and independent judiciary, under the terms of its 1997 return to Chinese rule, within the "one country, two systems" framework agreed between British and Chinese officials and enshrined in its miniconstitution, the Basic Law.<br/><br/>But the city's freedom and autonomy are now being eroded in the wake of repeated interventions in the city’s political life by Beijing, according to overseas governments and human rights organizations.<br/><br/><b>'Chilling effect'</b><br/><br/>Occupy co-founder Benny Tai said there would be a strong and obvious "chilling effect" if the court convicted the nine defendants.<br/><br/>"It is clear to everyone and the world that the people will be under pressure if we are convicted," he told reporters outside the court after the trial concluded on Thursday.<br/><br/>"In the future, you may be charged with all kinds of crazy offenses and actually people would not talk about things that they worry about," Tai warned, in comments aired by government broadcaster RTHK. "The chilling effect is clear and I hope the judge will be able to see that."<br/><br/>Each charge against the nine defendants carries a maximum sentence of seven years' imprisonment.<br/><br/>Tai, who has been targeted by a smear campaign in the pro-Beijing press after he discussed the hypothetical notion of independence for Hong Kong at an academic forum, told the court earlier this week that he didn't fear going to jail.<br/><br/>Earlier this month, former Occupy Central student leader and opposition activist Joshua Wong warned that political prosecutions against protesters "have become the new norm" in Hong Kong.<br/><br/>At the start of the trial, British MPs condemned the use of criminal charges to intimidate and silence pro-democracy figures, noting that more than 100 pro-democracy protesters have been charged, and many jailed, on the basis of common law charges which curtail freedom of expression and have been criticized by the United Nations Human Rights Committee.<br/><br/><b>'Unlawful assembly' conviction</b><br/><br/>This year's trial comes after Wong and fellow Occupy leaders Nathan Law and Alex Chow were found guilty of public order offenses in July 2017 for their role in the occupation of Civic Square at the start of the movement.<br/><br/>Wong and Chow were convicted of "unlawful assembly" after they climbed into the fenced-off area outside government headquarters on the night of Sept. 26, 2014, at the start of a 79-day civil disobedience campaign for universal suffrage.<br/><br/>They were jailed after a retrial at the request of the justice department, which said their non-custodial sentences were too lenient, but were later released on appeal.<br/><br/>U.S. and U.K. officials have warned that growing political interference from Beijing is eroding the city's promised autonomy, known as the "one country, two systems" framework.<br/><br/>The cross-border detentions of five Hong Kong booksellers, and the barring of six directly elected pro-democracy lawmakers after Beijing intervened to rule their oaths of allegiance invalid have also thrown up doubts about the city's judicial independence.<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by Gao Feng for RFA's Mandarin Service, and by the Cantonese Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>occupy central, umbrella movement, hong kong elections, democracy, joshua wong, benny tai</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Cambodia’s PM Hun Sen Calls For Lift of Ban on Opposition Political Activities based on ‘Individual Merit’</title>
        <guid>3a9b115d-74de-4cc4-8e35-b6377b88db70</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/ban-12122018171230.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>But critics say the move seeks to ease international pressure and won’t resolve the country’s political crisis.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 22:17:59 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/ban-12122018171230.html/cambodia-hun-sen-and-garment-workers-dec-2018-1000.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Cambodia's Prime Minister Hun Sen poses picture with garment factory workers at a public gathering in Kampong Speu province, Dec 12, 2018.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Hun Sen's Facebook account]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Cambodia’s Prime Minister Hun Sen said Wednesday that he will ask for a royal decree to grant permission for more than 100 senior members of the now-dissolved opposition Cambodia National Rescue Party (CNRP) to reenter politics based on “individual merit,” following a ban last year.<br/><br/>The prime minister and his ruling Cambodian People’s Party (CPP) overwhelmingly won a July 29 election widely criticized as unfree and unfair following the Supreme Court’s November 2017 dissolution of the CNRP and a five-year ban on the political activities of 118 of its senior officials for the party’s role in an alleged plot to topple the government.<br/><br/>With CPP control of the country secured, Cambodia’s now one-party National Assembly is preparing an amended version of a draft law on political parties for a vote on Dec. 13 which, if accepted, would allow the 118 officials to reenter politics, although it does not provide for the reestablishment of the CNRP.<br/><br/>The move is widely seen as part of a bid by Hun Sen to ease international pressure on his government in response to limiting democratic freedoms in the lead up to July’s election, in which the CPP won all 125 seats being contested.<br/><br/>On Wednesday, Hun Sen told an audience during a speaking event in Kampong Speu province that he will ask King Norodom Sihamoni to reestablish the political rights of only those 118 officials who had “shown respect for the Supreme Court’s ruling,” and vowed to imprison any who violated the ban.<br/><br/>“As prime minister, I am ready to accept individual requests [to have the political ban lifted], not one from a party,” he said.<br/><br/>He warned Interior Minister Sar Kheng to “make no mistake” that the passing of the draft law on political parties did not mean a blanket lifting of the ban on political activities for the 118 senior CNRP officials, and that “each official needs to make an individual request” to have their rights reinstated.<br/><br/>Hun Sen’s critics, including acting CNRP president Sam Rainsy, have said the move to lift the ban on the opposition officials is “a trap” and warned that it does not go far enough to resolve Cambodia’s political crisis.<br/><br/><b>Political ‘trap’</b><br/><br/>On Wednesday, Sam Rainsy, who is living abroad in self-imposed exile to avoid a string of politically motivated convictions, urged the 118 officials not to accept Hun Sen’s demand that they request to have their political rights reinstated.<br/><br/>He told RFA’s Khmer Service that any deal must include the release of CNRP President Kem Sokha, who was arrested on charges of treason two months ahead of his party’s dissolution and, while he has been granted bail, remains under house arrest, is barred from meeting with CNRP officials or foreigners, and cannot speak at or host any rallies or political activities.<br/><br/>Sam Rainsy suggested that international pressure is working, and would soon lead Hun Sen to free Kem Sokha, reinstate the CNRP, drop all charges against members of the opposition, and return elected seats of government to the party’s officials.<br/><br/>Since the July election, the U.S. has since announced visa bans on individuals seen as limiting democracy in the country, as part of a series of measures aimed at pressuring Cambodia to reverse course, and outgoing U.S. Ambassador to Cambodia William Heidt recently called on the government to free Kem Sokha and foster political reconciliation in the nation.<br/><br/>The European Union, which was the second biggest trade partner of Cambodia in 2017, withdrew support ahead of the ballot and has said it will drop a preferential trade scheme for Cambodian exports based on the country’s election environment.<br/><br/>“Hun Sen can’t avoid it, so he is trying to trick the CNRP by offering a partial solution that will likely require its officials to defect to the ruling party,” Sam Rainsy said.<br/><br/>“No one should fall into his trap—don’t feel threatened and please remain calm. Hun Sen must provide us a full solution that includes the reinstatement of the CNRP, Kem Sokha’s release and allowing all 118 CNRP officials to reenter politics.”<br/><br/>Analyst Kim Sok told RFA that Hun Sen is trying to split the CNRP into pieces, like he has with other parties in the past.<br/><br/>“Hun Sen is facing a dead end [because of international pressure], so the CNRP must maintain its firm stance and don’t fall for his strategy,” he said.<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Samean Yun. Written in English by Joshua Lipes.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>cnrp, cpp, hun sen, sam rainsy, democracy</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>China Detains Former Canadian Diplomat Days After Arrest of Huawei Executive</title>
        <guid>ea0bf6dc-c6e8-45ea-838b-fd5f4107d358</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/china-detains-former-canadian-diplomat-12112018113150.html</link>

	    
	         <category>China</category>
	    

        <description>A Hong Kong connection is emerging in the case of Meng Wanzhou, accused by the U.S. of violating sanctions against Iran.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/china-detains-former-canadian-diplomat-12112018113150.html/china-meng-wanzhou-court-vancouver-dec10-2018.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Members of the media wait outside the British Columbia Supreme Court bail hearing of Meng Wanzhou, chief financial officer of Chinese telecom giant Huawei Technologies, who is being held on an extradition warrant, in Vancouver, Canada, Dec. 10, 2018.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Reuters]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p><b style="text-align: left; ">UPDATED at 6:15 P.M. EST on 2018-11-12</b></p>
<p><b style="text-align: left; "></b>Authorities in China have detained a former Canadian diplomat working for a think-tank, just days after police in Canada arrested the chief financial officer of China's Huawei Technologies at Washington's request.</p>
<p>"International Crisis Group is aware of reports that its North East Asia Senior Adviser, Michael Kovrig, has been detained in China," the group said in a statement on Tuesday.</p>
<p>"We are doing everything possible to secure additional information on Michael’s whereabouts as well as his prompt and safe release," it said.</p>
<p>Following the arrest of Huawei CFO Meng Wanzhou in Vancouver on Saturday, Chinese vice foreign minister Le Yucheng summoned Canada’s ambassador to Beijing, John McCallum, warning him of "severe consequences" if Meng, 46, wasn't immediately released.</p>
<p>Responding to the detention of a Huawei "principal" at the request of the U.S., the statement accused Canada of violating Meng's rights and called for her release.</p>
<p>"Otherwise, there will be severe consequences, and Canada must bear the full responsibility," the foreign ministry said in a statement at the time.</p>
<p>Meng, who faces possible extradition to the United States, was granted bail by a court in Vancouver on Tuesday, after agreeing to post $10 million and surrender her passports, wear an ankle bracelet and follow strict limits on where she lives and moves in the Canadian city, according to Canadian media reports from the hearing.</p>
<p>Kovrig had been working as a full-time expert for the International Crisis Group since February 2017 and had previously served as a Canadian diplomat in Beijing and Hong Kong, Reuters reported.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the Hong Kong government tried to quell a rising tide of questions over Meng's possession of three of its passports, in apparent violation of the city's immigration regulations.</p>
<p>While Hong Kong Special Administrative Region (HKSAR) passport holders are only allowed to hold one passport at a time, "there will be occasions where a passport holder will apply for a new passport before the natural expiry date because of various circumstances, like the loss of the passport, or the change of personal particulars, or other specified circumstances," the city's chief executive told reporters on Tuesday.</p>
<p>"It is not uncommon for the passport holder to use a valid current passport, but at the same time in entering that particular country with visa requirements, to present the old passport with a valid visa," Carrie Lam said.</p>
<p>"She has been issued a few passports over a period since she has obtained the Hong Kong Permanent Resident status because of the specified circumstances that I have explained, but at one point in time or at any point in time, she holds only one valid Hong Kong SAR passport," she said.</p>
<p>But she said the "very special circumstances" surrounding the case had led her to order an investigation by Hong Kong's immigration department.</p>
<p>Meng was found to hold a total of seven passports in all, including the Hong Kong ones, according to evidence presented at her ongoing bail hearing in Vancouver, reports said.</p>
<p><b>‘Not just the passport muddle’</b></p>
<p>Alvin Yeung, lawmaker for the pro-democracy Civic Party in Hong Kong, said the city's government should follow up all aspects of Meng's activities there, as they may have a bearing on the accusation that she facilitated the violation of U.S. economic sanctions on Iran via another company, Skycom.</p>
<p>"Actually, this whole thing isn't just about the passport muddle; it also involves the U.S. accusation that Meng Wanzhou used Hong Kong shell companies to conduct transactions with Iran," Yeung told RFA on Tuesday.</p>
<p>"Owing to Hong Kong's position as an open and international financial hub, the HKSAR government should be watching very closely," he said.</p>
<p>He said any perception by foreign governments or investors that Hong Kong has "loopholes" that are too easily exploited by people carrying out illegal transactions could have a substantial impact on the city's international reputation.</p>
<p>"I think the Hong Kong SAR government should follow this up and take concrete actions to restore international confidence," Yeung said. "I don't think the chief executive can just sit on her hands and wait for the Chinese foreign ministry to follow up on this."</p>
<p>Beijing-based scholar Sun Daping said the ruling Chinese Communist Party only has one way of responding to Meng's detention.</p>
<p>"The Chinese authorities are playing such a high-profile role in the case of Meng Xiazhou, because actually they are also under pressure from domestic nationalist sentiment, both within the system and in patriotic organizations," Sun said.</p>
<p>"The authorities have been igniting this nationalism in recent years, so now they can only continue to play this role and spout nonsense with their eyes closed in the case of Meng Wanzhou," he said.</p>
<p>China's foreign minister warned Tuesday against the "bullying" of any Chinese citizen.</p>
<p>"The safety and security of Chinese compatriots are our priority, China will never sit idly by and ignore any bullying that violates the legitimate rights and interests of Chinese citizens," foreign minister Wang Yi said, without mentioning Meng or Huawei directly.</p>
<p>"We will fully safeguard the legitimate rights of Chinese citizens and return fairness and justice to the world," he told a diplomatic symposium.</p>
<p>China has accused Canada of treating Meng in an "inhumane" manner, citing reports in Chinese state-run media alleging she was not given adequate medical care, Reuters reported.</p>
<p><i><b>Reported by Tam Siu-yin for RFA's Cantonese Service, and by Shi Shan and Qiao Long for the Mandarin Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>diplomacy, hong kong, us, sanctions, ccp</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Cambodia Now ‘More Free’ Than Under Khmer Rouge:  Hun Sen</title>
        <guid>6015bb52-db94-4119-a6aa-20bb68fb9959</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/free-12102018173904.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>But rights groups say the government does not uphold its international rights commitments.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 22:52:24 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/free-12102018173904.html/khmer-chaksopheap-121018.JPG" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Chak Sopheap, executive director of the Cambodian Centre for Human Rights, is shown in an undated photo.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[CCHR]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Cambodian Prime Minister Hun Sen kept the bar low in a statement marking the 70th anniversary of International Human Rights Day, asserting that under his 33-year rule Cambodia’s people now enjoy more freedoms and rights than they did during the 1975-1979 rule of the Khmer Rouge.<br/><br/>Writing on Facebook, Hun Sen said that the rights of Cambodia’s citizens have been “fully restored” since the collapse on Jan. 7, 1979 of the murderous  Khmer Rouge, under whose rule an estimated 3 million people are believed to have died.<br/><br/>“With such rights and freedoms, our citizens can enjoy their lives and work, and can choose their beliefs and religion and freely elect their own leaders according to their wish,” Hun Sen wrote.<br/><br/>“These rights and freedoms also allow Cambodia to develop and advance. Let us all jointly maintain and defend our [country’s] peace, so that this can sustain and support Cambodia’s progress.”<br/><br/>Also writing on Facebook, political opposition leader Kem Sokha—now facing treason charges in Cambodia widely believed to be politically motivated—said that national unity, peace, and development can be achieved only when others’ rights are respected, “especially the freedom of speech and the right to participate in the country’s development.”<br/><br/>Speaking to RFA’s Khmer Service, human rights activist Am Sam Ath said that Cambodia’s ruling Cambodian People’s Party does not yet fully respect the commitments to human rights already guaranteed by the country’s constitution and in international covenants that Cambodia has ratified.<br/><br/>“We have seen that these rights either decline or improve depending on the country’s political situation,” Am Sam Ath—head of the investigations office of the Cambodian rights group LICADHO—said.<br/><br/>“Each time following elections, especially in 2017 and 2018, Cambodia has been subject to mounting criticisms from the international community regarding the decline in human rights. As a result, they have set out conditions for the restoring of human rights and democracy in Cambodia.”<br/><br/><b>'A great honor'</b><br/><br/>Meanwhile, in a statement Monday, the French and German embassies in Phnom Penh awarded Chak Sopheap—executive director of the Cambodian Centre for Human Rights—the 2018 Franco-German Prize for Human Rights and the Rule of Law.<br/><br/>Speaking to RFA, Chak Sopheap called the award a “great honor” for all Cambodians working for democracy and human rights in the authoritarian country.<br/><br/>“I want to share this award with all human rights activists in Cambodia,” Chak Sopheap said, adding, “This also serves as a message to our country, and especially to the government, to recognize the value of activists.”<br/><br/>“I hope that Cambodia will ensure the safety and basic rights and freedoms for all our communities so that they can perform their work free from fear,” she said.<br/><br/><b>Hundreds gather</b><br/><br/>Also on Monday, hundreds of Cambodians gathered to celebrate International Human Rights Day at the newly reopened Freedom Park, now located on the outskirts of the capital Phnom Penh.<br/><br/>Participants in the rally—including members of civil society organizations (CSOs), famers, young people, and workers—raised banners demanding basic rights including justice, jobs, land reform, and a restoration of democracy in the Southeast Asian nation in which the ruling CPP swept national elections in July after using the courts to cripple its only viable political opposition.<br/><br/>Hundreds of plainclothes security officers were deployed to prevent participants from marching, sources said.<br/><br/>Speaking to RFA, Informal Economy Association president Vorn Pov said Monday’s heavy security presence had intimidated many who had wanted to take part in the event, causing hundreds to stay home.<br/><br/>“We had planned to have up to a thousand participants, but because of the presence of [police], many citizens became worried and afraid,” he said.<br/><br/>“As a result, many began to go home, and we now have only three to four hundred people.”<br/><br/>Celebrations of International Human Rights Day were also held under tight control in Banteay Meanchey, Preah Vihear, and Takeo provinces, where police blocked access to requested rally sites or restricted marchers to smaller districts, preventing them from assembling in large numbers.<br/><i><b><br/>Reported by RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Sovannarith Keo. Written in English by Richard Finney.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>democracy, human rights, hun sen, cnrp, cpp</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Cambodian Court's Appeals Review a 'Ploy' to Weaken Political Opposition</title>
        <guid>4c755af2-8282-44a3-8203-da4a6741b022</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/appeals-12062018171931.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>Observers call the move an attempt to divide exiled CNRP leader Sam Rainsy and former party chief Kem Sokha, now detained in Cambodia.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 22:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/appeals-12062018171931.html/khmer-samrainsytokyo-120618.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Cambodia's exiled opposition leader Sam Rainsy speaks in Tokyo in an April 13, 2018 photo.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Cambodia’s Supreme Court began on Wednesday to hear an appeal against the 2017 conviction in a defamation case brought against CNRP leader Sam Rainsy, now living in exile outside Cambodia, with observers calling the move a ploy by the ruling party to divide its opposition.<br/><br/>The move follows the appointment in early December by the Cambodia National Rescue Party of Sam Rainsy as acting party president while previous party chief Kem Sokha remains detained in the capital Phnom Penh on charges of treason.<br/><br/>Speaking to RFA’s Khmer Service on Dec. 6, CNRP supporter Mao Vibol said that the Court’s appeal hearing, with a decision to be announced on Dec. 19, was forced by Sam Rainsy’s growing popularity following his appointment as party leader.<br/><br/>“In the past, the CNRP has faced all kinds of difficulties . . . while several lawsuits were launched against Sam Rainsy himself,” Mao Vibol said.<br/><br/>“All of this has caused great concern for citizens, human rights activists, and civil society officials,” he said, adding that ruling-party lawsuits brought against the CNRP have blocked the development of democracy in Cambodia “and become barriers for politicians who are nationalists and patriots and lovers of justice.”<br/><br/>Also speaking to RFA, political commentator Kim Sok—who served more than a year in prison for making statements critical of Cambodian prime minister Hun Sen and the ruling Cambodian People’s Party (CPP)—called the Supreme Court’s move a ploy to weaken the exile-based CNRP, which was banned in Cambodia by the Supreme Court in November last year for its role in an alleged plot to topple the government.<br/><br/>The restrictions on the CNRP and the arrest two months earlier of its president, Kem Sokha, were part of a wider crackdown on civil society and media that paved the way for Prime Minister Hun Sen’s ruling Cambodian People’s Party (CPP) to sweep all 125 seats contested in a July 29 election that was widely dismissed as unfree and unfair.<br/><br/>“Now that [Sam Rainsy’s] political journey has attracted more attention and become more energized, [Hun Sen and the CPP] will seek to further interrupt or hinder him,” Kim Sok said.<br/><br/>“Otherwise, his political activities will become a real threat to Hun Sen’s strategies to cling to power,” he said.<br/><b><br/>CNRP fully united</b><br/><br/>Speaking to RFA in a Dec. 5 call-in show, Sam Rainsy said that government moves to divide the CNRP are doomed to fail, adding “We won’t play Hun Sen’s game.”<br/><br/>“We must uphold the strong position that the CNRP is fully united, and that Kem Sokha and Sam Rainsy are also united.”<br/><br/>The international community, which has threatened trade sanctions over the outcome of July’s ballot, “must not believe in Hun Sen,” Sam Rainsy said, adding that Kem Sokha must be “immediately and unconditionally” freed from detention, and all charges dropped against CNRP officials charged with crimes.<br/><br/>The CNRP must meanwhile be reinstated in Cambodia, with opposition party officials restored to the posts to which they were elected in local elections, and from which they were dismissed by the government after the party was dissolved.<br/><br/>“These positions must be reinstated, since citizens voted for the CNRP,” Sam Rainsy said, adding that new elections for the Senate and National Assembly must also now be held.<br/><br/>Cambodia’s government on Monday outlined a plan to “strengthen democracy and political space” in the country following July’s divisive election, but observers said the proposal is aimed at alleviating international pressure and does not go far enough in rolling back restrictions put in place ahead of the ballot.<br/><b><br/>Not far enough</b><br/><br/>In a statement issued by the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Cambodia said it plans to amend the country’s political party law to lift a five-year ban on the political activities of 118 senior members of the opposition Cambodia National Rescue Party (CNRP), which was dissolved by the Supreme Court in November last year for its role in an alleged plot to topple the government.<br/><br/>Cambodia’s government also vowed to promote “genuine partnership” with civil society groups and nongovernmental organizations (NGOs), address matters related to labor and trade union rights, uphold press freedom and freedom of expression, and address longstanding land disputes by accelerating nationwide land registration, Monday’s statement said.<br/><br/>Speaking to RFA earlier this week, political analyst Ly Srey Sros said that Hun Sen’s regime appears to be trying to resolve the tense political situation in Cambodia following international pressure, adding that the country stands to benefit if the government truly want to “open up the political space” without trying to divide the opposition.<br/><br/>But she warned that tricks aimed at benefiting the ruling party will only further destabilize Cambodia’s political environment.<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Sovannarith Keo. Written in English by Richard Finney.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>cnrp, cpp, hun sen, sam rainsy, democracy</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Hong Kong Student Leader Warns of 'Dire Situation' For City's Democracy</title>
        <guid>da4beb59-a502-4d65-b396-03e21c14e501</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/hong-kong-student-leader-warns-of-dire-situation-12062018112917.html</link>

	    
	         <category>China</category>
	    

        <description>Joshua Wong, a student leader of the 2014 pro-democracy movement, warns of a threat to democracy from Beijing as he wins a major human rights award.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 16:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/hong-kong-student-leader-warns-of-dire-situation-12062018112917.html/china-joshua-wong-hong-kong-sept28-2018.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Pro-democracy activist and Demosisto party member Joshua Wong speaks during a gathering outside Hong Kong government headquarters to mark the fourth anniversary of the Umbrella Movement, in Hong Kong, Sept. 28, 2018.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Hong Kong student leader and pro-democracy politician Joshua Wong has been awarded a major human rights award in Washington, although an effective travel ban meant he was unable to accept it in person.</p>
<p>Former Hong Kong lawmaker and student protest leader Nathan Law accepted the 2018 Lantos Human Rights Prize on Wednesday evening on Wong's behalf, as Wong hit out at the "dire situation" facing the city in the wake of the 2014 Umbrella Movement for fully democratic elections.</p>
<p>"The Lantos Human Rights Prize is intended to serve as a beacon of hope, justice and human decency in a world too often covered in a shroud of darkness," Wong wrote in <i>The Washington Post</i>.</p>
<p>"Yet I can’t help but feel that Lantos would be saddened to see the dire situation facing Hong Kong ... in the face of China’s efforts to increase its authoritarian control within its sphere of influence," the article said.</p>
<p>"Beijing is actively deploying its sharp power against Hong Kong," Wong warned. "All this constitutes a grave threat to our democracy."</p>
<p>Wong cited the removal from office in recent years of democratically elected lawmakers including Law, with whom he cofounded the political party Demosisto, while fellow activists had been barred from running in elections at all based on their political views.</p>
<p>"Political prosecutions against protesters have become the new norm," he said, citing a six-year jail term recently handed down to fellow activist Edward Leung.</p>
<p>Law, who traveled with former student leader and debarred election candidate Agnes Chow, said he had met with various members of the House of Representatives to talk about the proposed Hong Kong Human Rights and Democracy Act.</p>
<p>"The bill can give the United States more choices and flexibility when thinking about its Hong Kong policy," Law said. "For example, officials who are responsible for eroding Hong Kong's democratic human rights and autonomy would have their U.S. assets frozen, or be unable to enter the country."</p>
<p>He said he was confident that the bill, proposed by Congressmen Chris Smith and Marco Rubio, would win widespread public support among pan-democrats back home.</p>
<p>"The Hong Kong Human Rights and Democracy Act that is being actively pursued by Demosisto will target human rights and democracy in particular," Law said. "It is more likely to win the broad support of pan-democrats."</p>
<p><b>Sentenced for ‘contempt of court’</b></p>
<p>Wong began serving a six-month jail term for his part in the storming of police barriers outside government headquarters on Sept. 26, 2014, at the start of the Umbrella Movement.</p>
<p>He was acquitted alongside fellow defendants Nathan Law and Alex Chow by Hong Kong's Court of Final Appeal in February, but was also handed a three-month sentence for "contempt of court," for trying to block the police clearance of an Occupy protest site in Mong Kok at the tail-end of the Umbrella Movement, which gained its nickname from the use of umbrellas by peaceful protesters to ward off pepper spray and tear-gas attacks by riot police.</p>
<p>Wong was released on bail in January, but his passport was confiscated. The city's High Court denied his request to ease his bail conditions pending a hearing in the "contempt of court" case scheduled for April next year, putting him under an effective travel ban.</p>
<p>The Lantos Human Rights Prize is an annual award aimed at raising global awareness of human rights violations around the world, and to support individuals committed to fighting against them.</p>
<p>Previous recipients have included Hillary Clinton, Chen Guangcheng, Elie Wiesel, and the Dalai Lama.</p>
<p><i><b>Reported by Fok Leung-kiu for RFA's Cantonese Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>hong kong, human rights, lawmakers, activists, us, law, democracy, umbrella movement, occupy central</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>RFA, Cambodia Daily May Reopen in Cambodia: Interior Minister</title>
        <guid>938eeb22-2d4e-490d-bc2e-ad6cb93697e4</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/reopen-12042018171127.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>Observers doubt sincerity of promises to relax restrictions on media and politics, calling them ploys to avoid threatened trade sanctions.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 22:27:52 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/reopen-12042018171127.html/khmer-cambodiadaily-020518.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[The Aug. 23, 2017 edition of the Cambodia Daily.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[RFA]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>The Cambodian government said Tuesday that Radio Free Asia is welcome to reopen its office in the capital Phnom Penh, asserting that no pressure had been applied to RFA to shut down last year and that the congressionally funded U.S.-based international broadcaster had  chosen to close on its own.<br/><br/>“There was no pressure,” Minister of the Interior Sar Kheng said during a public meeting at the ministry attended by police officers and NGO representatives. “RFA closed the office by itself.”<br/><br/>“But now we welcome them back, and the radio station can reestablish its office in Phnom Penh,” Sar Kheng said.<br/><br/>RFA closed its nearly 20-year old bureau in the Cambodian capital on Sept. 12, 2017 amid a growing crackdown by Prime Minister Hun’s ruling Cambodian People’s Party (CPP) on independent media, NGOs, and independent critics ahead of national elections in July of this year.<br/><br/>Cambodian journalists working for RFA had reported over the years on corruption, illegal logging, and forced evictions, among other stories largely ignored by state-controlled media, and authorities had already closed independent radio stations carrying RFA reports, using a pretext of tax and administrative violations.<br/><br/>On Nov. 14, 2017, RFA reporters Uon Chhin and Yeang Sothearin were taken into custody and charged with “illegally collecting information for a foreign source.” <br/><br/>Cambodia’s Ministries of Information and Interior had warned prior to their arrests that any journalists still working for RFA after its office in the capital closed would be treated as spies.<br/><br/>The pair were released on bail in September 2018 after spending nine months behind bars on charges of espionage. Multiple local and international rights groups had condemned Hun Sen’s government for its treatment of the two reporters during their detention, demanding that they be freed.<br/><b><br/>Back taxes owed</b><br/><br/>Meanwhile, Sar Kheng said, the <i>Cambodia Daily</i>—an independent newspaper often critical of Prime Minister Hun Sen that closed in September 2017—can resume operations if the paper pays what he said were taxes still owed to the government.<br/><br/>Sar Kheng said that the paper had evaded payment by closing its operations in the country.<br/><br/>“But if the <i>Cambodia Daily</i> returns and agrees to pay its taxes, they will have full rights to resume operations,” he said.<br/><br/>Speaking to RFA’s Khmer Service, Cambodian Center for Independent Media director Nop Vy said that instead of simply saying that foreign media outlets can return, Cambodia’s government should introduce clear measures guaranteeing press freedoms in the authoritarian Southeast Asian country.<br/><br/>“I would like the government to open more space for everyone to freely express their opinions on how to improve society,” he said.<br/><br/>“I would also like to see journalists work independently and in security,” he said.<br/><br/>Speaking to RFA, ethnic minority villagers in Mondulkiri and Ratanakiri provinces voiced caution over statements Monday by Cambodia’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs that independent media can resume operations in Cambodia.<br/><br/>One villager named Chan Vorn said that independent media have helped local communities in the past to voice their concerns, and have helped expose government inaction in solving problems.<br/><br/>Promises now by the ruling party to restore press freedoms may be deceptive, though, Chan Vorn said.<br/><br/>“I don’t believe the government will do this. They just want to show that they are restoring democracy, though they’re not,” he said.<br/><br/>Also speaking to RFA, a Mondulkiri villager named Kroeung Tola said he wants press freedoms to be restored so that journalists can travel freely to remote areas to report.<br/><br/>“Independent media help a lot,” he said.<br/><br/><b>Promises doubted</b><br/><br/>Paris-based media watchdog Reporters Without Borders (RSF) ranked Cambodia 132nd out of 180 countries in its 2017 World Press Freedom Index, and warned that the Southeast Asian nation is “liable to fall” in the 2018 index.<br/><br/>Cambodia’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs on Monday outlined a plan to “strengthen democracy and political space” in the country following a divisive election that returned Hun Sen and the ruling CPP to power, though observers say the proposal is aimed only at alleviating international threats of trade sanctions over last year’s election, which was widely criticized as unfree and unfair.<br/><br/>The statement’s provisions include plans to amend the country’s political party law to lift a five-year ban on the political activities of 118 senior members of the opposition Cambodia National Rescue Party (CNRP), which was dissolved by the Supreme Court in November last year for its role in an alleged plot to overthrow the government.<br/><br/>Sin Chanpov Rozeth, a popular CNRP commune chief stripped by the ruling party of her post in Banteay Meanchey’s O’Char commune, expressed doubt that the government will follow through on its pledge, however.<br/><br/>“If 118 CNRP members are allowed to return to politics, this would mean a reinstatement of the CNRP,” she said.<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by  RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Samean Yun. Written in English by Richard Finney.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>censorship, media, hun sen, cpp, cnrp, democracy</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Cambodia Seeks to Drop Pending Charges Against Unionists in About-Face on Labor</title>
        <guid>4dddb4fe-71ee-444f-9566-d7b2ed3d94ec</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/cambodia-seeks-to-drop-pending-charges-11292018162727.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>Prime Minister Hun Sen says the move will allow greater freedom for organized labor, but critics say he’s trying to avoid EU trade restrictions.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 21:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/cambodia-seeks-to-drop-pending-charges-11292018162727.html/cambodia-hun-sen-money-garment-factory-orkers-aug30-2017.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Cambodian Prime Minister Hun Sen (R) offers envelopes of cash to pregnant workers at a garment factory compound on the outskirts of Phnom Penh, Aug. 30, 2017.  ]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Cambodia’s Ministry of Labor on Thursday asked all union leaders and labor activists who have court cases pending against them to report to the ministry so it can work with justice officials to have the charges dropped, in a move by Prime Minister Hun Sen’s authoritarian regime to ease pressure by the international community over his human rights record.</p>
<p>The move comes a day after Hun Sen asked the two ministries to end pending cases to allow greater freedom for unions to work independently without fear of prosecution, especially in the crucial garment manufacturing sector.</p>
<p>A statement issued by the labor ministry said those who have cases pending against them should submit relevant documents before Dec. 10.</p>
<p>The roughly 40 cases still outstanding against unionists and activists entail charges mainly related to organizing and participating in labor demonstrations, including incitement, causing violence, destruction of property, and obstructing traffic.</p>
<p>It is believed that the cases have not gone to trial so that Hun Sen can use the charges to continue to stifle labor activists and organizers who pose a threat to his regime without drawing further condemnation from the international community.</p>
<p>Yang Sophorn, president of the Cambodian Alliance of Trade Unions, who has a case pending against her on criminal charges of incitement, told RFA’s Khmer Service that she has already submitted paperwork to the labor ministry.</p>
<p>She said that government officials brought a case against her solely because her profession entails helping workers, and that she had not committed any crime.</p>
<p><b>‘It won’t help’</b></p>
<p>At least five prominent independent union leaders, including Ath Thon, president of the Coalition of Cambodian Apparel Workers’ Democratic Union; Rong Chhun, president of the Cambodian Confederation of Unions; and Chea Mony, an advisor at the Free Trade Union of the Workers of the Kingdom of Cambodia, have open cases on charges of crimes related to labor issues.</p>
<p>Unionists accused of crimes under the penal code are forbidden to engage in activities with workers or access factory premises.</p>
<p>Ath Thon told RFA that the lawsuit against him has affected his work.</p>
<p>“Because of the complaints, we can’t help workers resolve labor disputes,” he said.</p>
<p>Rong Chhun told RFA that Hun Sen’s move to have the cases dropped is not a genuine intention to give greater freedom to independent unions that engage in collective bargaining and advocate for rights and improved working conditions in the 600 factories that comprise Cambodia’s heavily unionized garment and footwear sector.</p>
<p>He said the prime minister made the decision to stop the European Union from withdrawing Cambodia’s preferential Everything But Arms (EBA) trade agreement that gives the developing country tariff-free access to the bloc.</p>
<p>“Hun Sen is doing this just to stop Cambodia from plunging into further crisis, but it won’t help,” he said.</p>
<p>Cambodia’s U.S. $7 billion apparel industry — the country’s largest — employs around 700,000 people and accounts for four-fifths of exports.</p>
<p><b>Loss of EBA preferences</b></p>
<p>The EU informed Cambodia on Oct. 5 that it was ending its preferential trade status because of a worsening of the country’s human rights record amid a crackdown by Hun Sen on the political opposition, NGOs, and the independent media surrounding the general election on July 29.</p>
<p>The prime minister and his ruling Cambodian People’s Party overwhelmingly won the  election widely criticized as unfree and unfair following the Supreme  Court’s dissolution of the opposition Cambodia National Rescue Party for  its role in an alleged plot to topple the government.</p>
<p>EU officials said that it would take 18 months to complete the procedure if the EBA agreement is dropped, <i>The Phnom Penh Post</i> reported.</p>
<p>In early July, the EU launched a fact-finding mission to Cambodia to assess whether Hun Sen’s government was adhering to its commitments in the Generalised Scheme of Preferences — an agreement that grants Cambodian exports tax-free entry into the European market under the EBA scheme.</p>
<p>The EU is the most important market for Cambodia's apparel industry, accounting for about 45 percent of the country’s garment exports.</p>
<p>In March, industry organizations representing major European and American apparel brands sent an open letter to Hun Sen, stating their concern over several controversial labor-related laws and court cases against labor organizers.</p>
<p>They also asked for amendments to the country’s 2016 Trade Union Law and called for an end to the harassment of labor activists.</p>
<p><i><b>Reported by RFA's Khmer Service. Translated by Samean Yun. Written in English by Roseanne Gerin.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>labor, unions, activists, hun sen, eu, trade, factories</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Cambodia's Hun Sen 'Sorry' He Hadn't Killed Protest Leaders</title>
        <guid>1abde920-bf2d-4e94-aa55-4547e54dc494</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/sorry-11292018161515.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>He hadn't wanted to do so 'at the time,' the prime minister tells a gathering of Cambodian workers.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 21:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/sorry-11292018161515.html/khmer-speaking-112918.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Cambodian prime minister Hun Sen gestures while speaking in Phnom Penh, Aug. 1, 2018.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Cambodian Prime Minister Hun Sen voiced regret on Thursday that he hadn’t had leaders of protests against his ruling Cambodian People’s Party in 2013 and 2014 killed, saying only that he hadn’t wanted to do this “at the time.”<br/><br/>Speaking to a gathering of hundreds of workers, Hun Sen said that protest leaders had been lucky to escape Cambodia after the protests, which saw opposition Cambodia National Rescue Party members attacked and dispersed by security forces, with at least one shot dead and several others wounded by gunfire in 2013.<br/><br/>“I want to let you know that if you hadn’t fled Cambodia, you would already have had your funeral,” Hun Sen said in remarks apparently addressed to former opposition leader Sam Rainsy, now living in exile in France after fleeing a string of convictions in Cambodian courts widely seen as politically motivated.<br/><br/>“We didn’t pursue you because we didn’t want to kill you at the time,” Hun Sen said.<br/><br/>Speaking to RFA’s Khmer Service from France, Sam Rainsy said that Hun Sen’s comments show he is a dictator who is not afraid to kill to maintain his hold on power.<br/><br/>“Please don’t forget that Hun Sen is a former soldier,” Sam Rainsy said. “He is not afraid to kill people.”<br/><br/><b>'Quite shocking'</b><br/><br/>Also speaking to RFA, Richard Rogers—a London-based lawyer who filed an international complaint in 2014 on behalf of Cambodian victims of land grabs—voiced shock at Hun Sen’s remarks.<br/><br/>“Threatening to kill someone, threatening to kill someone without lawful excuse, is illegal in itself,” Rogers said. “So Hun Sen has effectively threatened to kill someone simply for demonstrating, and that’s in fact a crime.”<br/><br/>“So it’s quite shocking, and it’s a shame that instead of listening to the people and trying to address their frustrations, he will simply threaten them,” he said.<br/><br/>Cambodian security forces had in fact fired into unarmed crowds in anti-government protests in the past, “so he’s proven that he’s certainly accepting of his security forces doing that,” Rogers said.<br/><br/>“And maybe he even suggested to them that they do that. So that’s quite shocking.”<br/><b><br/>Deadly violence</b><br/><br/>On Sept. 15, 2013, deadly violence broke out in Phnom Penh as tens of thousands of Cambodians protested for the second weekend in a row to back calls for an independent probe into charges of election fraud, which the opposition said had robbed them of victory in July 28 polls.<br/><br/>Security forces shot dead one protester and wounded several others when they opened fire and used tear gas and water cannon in clashes with protesters in the tension-filled capital.<br/><br/>Four top CNRP lawmakers were detained and at least 30 protesters injured the following year as CNRP members moved to end a government blockade of Freedom Park, the country’s main protest grounds in Phnom Penh.<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Samean Yun. Written in English by Richard Finney.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>hun sen, cpp, cnrp, sam rainsy</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Occupy Central Founders Begin Defense at Public Order Trial in Hong Kong</title>
        <guid>32846de2-aab1-4968-9412-f8891942ab38</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/defense-11292018140146.html</link>

	    
	         <category>China</category>
	    

        <description>Chan Kin-man says the movement's founders were dismissed by high-ranking government officials when they sought a dialogue.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 19:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/defense-11292018140146.html/china-bennytai2-112918.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Occupy Central protest defendants Eason Chung, Raphael Wong, Chu Yiu-ming, and Benny Tai are shown left to right in a Nov. 29, 2018 photo.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[RFA]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Nine prominent figures in Hong Kong's 2014 Occupy Central pro-democracy movement began making the case for their defense on Thursday in their controversial trial on public order charges.<br/><br/>A group of supporters gathered outside West Kowloon Magistrate’s Court, chanting: "Occupy Central is innocent!" "Shame on political prosecutions!" and "Peaceful protest is legitimate!"<br/><br/>The three activists who initiated the movement—law professor Benny Tai, retired sociology professor Chan Kin-man, and reverend Chu Yiu-ming—face one count each of conspiracy to cause public nuisance, inciting others to cause public nuisance, and inciting people to incite others to cause public nuisance.<br/><br/>Former student federation leaders Tommy Cheung and Eason Chung, League of Social Democrats vice-chairman Raphael Wong, and lawmakers Tanya Chan and Shiu Ka-chun face two counts of inciting others to cause a public nuisance, while former Democratic Party lawmaker Lee Wing-tat faces one count.<br/><br/>Chan Kin-man, who conducted his own defense, said the chief purpose of the Occupy Central movement was to campaign for fully democratic elections using civil disobedience tactics.<br/><br/>"Civil disobedience doesn't just mean the occupation of a place; it also means that participants expect to make sacrifices to make society pay attention to injustice," he told the court.<br/><br/>Asked why he didn't plead guilty, Chan Kin-man said he felt that some of the charges were unreasonable, and that any conviction would have "a profound impact" on waning freedom of speech in the city.<br/><br/>He said he, Tai, and Chu had carried out an unofficial referendum with 792,000 voters taking part, the majority of whom support universal, direct elections to Hong Kong's Legislative Council, and for its chief executive.<br/><br/>He said the trio had repeatedly sought meetings with high-ranking government officials, but weren't offered any meaningful dialogue when the meeting finally took place, with chief executive Carrie Lam merely urging them not to proceed with the Occupy Central movement.<br/><br/><b>'Too radical'</b><br/><br/>Chan said that when the trio showed the officials their data in support of universal suffrage, the then-undersecretary for constitutional affairs, Lau Kong-wah, repeatedly told them they were too radical.<br/><br/>No further meetings were arranged, and the officials left the handouts prepared for them in the meeting room. <br/><br/>Later, an Aug. 31, 2014 ruling from China's National People's Congress (NPC) standing committee insisting on the vetting of electoral candidates led the trio to believe that the path to dialogue was now closed.<br/><br/>At that point, they decided to move ahead with the occupation of a pedestrian area in the Central business district. But the "storming" of Civic Square outside government headquarters on Sept. 27 brought thousands of protesters onto the streets of nearby Admiralty, and Chan then announced the start of the movement the following day, he said.<br/><br/>Chan’s lawyer told the court that he will play an hour’s worth of video footage on Friday which has never been seen publicly before, government broadcaster RTHK reported.<br/><br/>The prosecution had told the court that the actions of the seven were "unreasonable," and accused them of repeatedly calling on protesters to shut down parts of the central Admiralty district, where key government buildings are located, by blocking traffic with “illegal” sit-ins.<br/><br/>Prosecutors accused Tai, Chan, and Chu of initiating the civil disobedience movement at a news conference in March 2013, as a way of achieving fully democratic elections, and of encouraging large numbers of people to take part.<br/><br/>All nine pleaded not guilty to the charges, which were based largely on evidence of their statements made to the media at the time.<br/><b><br/>Broken promises</b><br/><br/>British MPs have condemned the use of criminal charges to intimidate and silence pro-democracy figures, noting that more than 100 pro-democracy protesters have been charged, and many jailed, on the basis of common law charges which curtail freedom of expression and have been criticized by the United Nations Human Rights Committee.<br/><br/>Hong Kong was promised the continuation of its traditional freedoms of speech and association by a mini-constitution drafted by U.K. and Chinese officials ahead of the 1997 handover to Chinese rule.<br/><br/>But those freedoms are now being eroded in the wake of repeated interventions in the city’s political life by Beijing, according to overseas governments and human rights organizations.<br/><br/>The trial comes after student leaders Joshua Wong, Nathan Law, and Alex Chow were found guilty of public order offenses in July 2017 for their role in the occupation of a cordoned-off public space at the start of the movement.<br/><i><b><br/>Reported by Lee Wang-yam for RFA's Cantonese Service, and by Jing Yuan and Hwang Chun-mei for the Mandarin Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>democracy, justice system, occupy central, hong kong</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>China's Fujian Province Backs News Website Targeting Hong Kong, Macau</title>
        <guid>7f3e3467-dae2-4fc2-9003-795404b6f922</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/targeting-11212018123041.html</link>

	    
	         <category>China</category>
	    

        <description>Local commentators say the move is part of a growing tendency for provincial-level leaders to show loyalty to President Xi by evangelizing his ideology.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 18:15:51 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/targeting-11212018123041.html/china-linqianxiang2-112118.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Southeast Net website director Lin Qianxiang is shown in his office in Hong Kong, Nov. 20, 2018.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[RFA]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>The ruling Chinese Communist Party in the southeastern province of Fujian has set up a new website offering local "news" to residents of Hong Kong and Macau, RFA has learned.<br/><br/>Southeast Net, which is run by the Fujian Hong Kong and Macao Media Center of the provincial propaganda department, has been recruiting Hong Kong and Macao-based journalists to staff its Hong Kong news site since May.<br/><br/>The site, which already has a branch in Australia, has been recruiting reporters, video producers, and editors and "social media specialists" in the two former colonial cities in recent months, according to an online recruitment advertisement seen by RFA.<br/><br/>"The news released by the Fujian Hong Kong and Macau Media Center is officially authoritative, allowing [people] with ancestral hometowns in Fujian to read about the good deeds of Hokkien [Fujian] people in Hong Kong and Macau, as well as all the latest news from Hong Kong, in a speedy manner," the ad explains.<br/><br/>Journalists and other communications professionals are being recruited to "Tell the stories of the people of Hong Kong and Macau, hearing [their] voices, serving communities in Hong Kong and Macau, and building a platform for exchanges between Fujian and Hong Kong and Macau," it said.<br/><br/>The site is already up and running, at http://hk.fjsen.com, and includes stories about the Hong Kong Federation of Fujian Associations meeting to study recent comments by President Xi Jinping to local politicians, as well as a feature titled "Southeast Net's Hong Kong reporter experiences the speed of the Hong Kong-Zhuhai-Macao Bridge."<br/><br/>A Special Reports section offers a welter of patriotic information about singing the ruling party's praises, patriotism, and studying President Xi's ideas.<br/><br/><b>'No official connection'</b><br/><br/>However, website director Lin Qianxiang denied the site had any official connection.<br/><br/>Speaking from an office in Hong Kong's North Point district that seemed not yet fully occupied when visited by RFA on Tuesday, Lin said: "No comment," when asked who was behind his operation. <br/><br/>"No, no one is saying that. We are just a regular media organization. Who told you that?"<br/><br/>Asked if the website had long-term plans to set up in Hong Kong, Lin declined to give details.<br/><br/>"No, there is no such plan," he said. "We don't have much stuff here, and not much to do. We're just standing around."<br/><br/>Li repeatedly denied the connection with the Fujian authorities, in spite of this being documented online, before leaving in a hurry "to catch a plane to Shenzhen." When followed from the building, Li said the operation wasn't a media operation at all.<br/><br/>"There is no media operation here," Li said. "It doesn't matter what gets reported on the website. We don't know anything about that. We aren't open for business."<br/><br/><b>Provincial ties</b><br/><br/>According to the Southeast Net website, the site operates under the aegis of the <i>Fujian Daily</i>, which is in turn run by the provincial party committee.<br/><br/>It set up a Hong Kong branch in 2016, with an official launch ceremony held last month at the Hong Kong Convention and Exhibition Center attended by Chen Dong, deputy head of Beijing's central liaison office in Hong Kong and Liang Jianyong, head of the Fujian provincial propaganda department and his deputy Xu Shanna, the website reports.<br/><br/>The Hong Kong branch was listed in Hong Kong's companies register in April under the name "Fujian Hong Kong and Macau Media Center Co. Ltd," with a registered share capital of just HK$1. The registered directors were listed only as "Mr. Xie" and "Mr. Lin."<br/><br/>The company also recently changed its name to Southeast Media Hong Kong Ltd. and registered a change of address to a commercial site of some 1,000 square feet, with a monthly rent of some HK$40,000, according to the register.<br/><br/>The stories on the website mentioning the "study" of remarks by President Xi indicate that the organizations concerned, including the Federation of Hong Kong Fujian Associations, are partners of the ruling Chinese Communist Party's United Front Work Department, which carries out outreach work with non-communist groups both at home and overseas.<br/><br/>The Federation has previously hosted Lei Chunmei, head of the Fujian provincial United Front Work Department, at a symposium in Hong Kong, according to reports on the site itself.<br/><br/><b>'More and more blatant'</b><br/><br/>Democratic Party lawmaker Lam Cheuk-ting said he is worried that China is continuing to overstep the mark when it comes to wielding its influence in Hong Kong, which was promised a "high degree of autonomy" and the maintenance of its traditional freedoms of speech, publication, and association, under the terms of the 1997 handover.<br/><br/>"I am worried, because this is getting more and more blatant," Lam said. "There are official or semi-official organizations from mainland China that come and set up in Hong Kong to try to influence public opinion here."<br/><br/>"This is a threat to our freedom of speech, and I think it may be a violation of the Basic Law," Lam said, in a reference to the city's mini-constitution setting out its status as a separate jurisdiction from mainland China.<br/><br/>"Mainland government departments cannot be allowed to come and operate in Hong Kong."<br/><br/>Political commentator Liu Ruishao said provincial-level party committees are taking the lead across China in a bid to demonstrate their loyalty to Xi Jinping Thought, which was enshrined in the country's constitution as Xi began an indefinite second term as president in March.<br/><br/><b>Using mainland resources</b><br/><br/>Their work in Hong Kong has been made easier by the fact that the Hokkienese community has long preserved traditional links with ancestral hometowns in Fujian.<br/><br/>"Provincial party committees across China are stepping up this sort of activity, under the banner of promoting Xi Jinping Thought," Liu told RFA. "This is also a way for them to signal their own political attitude [to Beijing]."<br/><br/>Liu said the setting up of Southeast Net's Hong Kong branch indicates that Beijing has lost much of its former shyness when it comes to funding media organizations to spread its message.<br/><br/>"They are openly using mainland resources to carry out these activities," he said. "It's pretty clear that this drama is nowhere near played out yet. I think we are going to see more and more local branches of official Chinese media invading Hong Kong in future."<br/><br/>Bruce Lui, senior journalism lecturer at the University of Hong Kong, said the move is a new development because only central media organizations like Xinhua news agency and CCTV have previously set up branches in Hong Kong.<br/><br/>"The greatest concern is that they claim to be a media organization, but they are actually part of the machinery of the state," Lui said, adding that Fujian used to be one of Xi Jinping's power bases.<br/><br/>He said Southeast Net's move into Hong Kong won't be welcome across the whole of the political elite, however.<br/><br/>"For [Xi's] political opponents, such as the faction supportive of [former president] Jiang Zemin or others, the use of media identities to monitor activities hostile [to Xi] is far from being acceptable," he said.<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by Tam Siu-yin for RFA's Cantonese Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>propaganda, media, hong kong</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>UK Drops Charges Against China's CCTV Reporter Kong Linlin</title>
        <guid>6037a27e-9a61-4d47-a04b-c0e991e8b07d</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/reporter-11212018125029.html</link>

	    
	         <category>China</category>
	    

        <description>Prosecution says there was insufficient evidence to secure a conviction for 'common assault,' the least severe of possible assault charges in the UK.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 17:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/assault-10262018111709.html/china-disrupt-101618.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Chinese journalist disrupts an event during a Conservative Party conference in Birmingham, UK, Sept. 30, 2018.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Social Media]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Authorities in the U.K. have dropped assault charges against a reporter for the Chinese Communist Party's state broadcaster following an angry confrontation with organizers and volunteers at a fringe event of the ruling Conservative Party conference in September.<br/><br/>A video of the incident posted by the rights group Hong Kong Watch at the time showed China Central Television (CCTV) reporter Kong Linlin being escorted from the venue on Sept. 30.<br/><br/>West Midlands Police had charged Kong with common assault after she was accused of "slapping" a volunteer, but the U.K.'s Crown Prosecution Service (CPS) said it had dropped the charge.<br/><br/>"This case was originally charged by the police," a spokeswoman for the CPS said in a statement.<br/><br/>"The CPS subsequently reviewed the available evidence and determined it was insufficient to provide a realistic prospect of conviction and therefore discontinued the case," she said.<br/><br/>The decision comes after CCTV claimed last month that charges against Kong had been dropped "due to diplomatic pressure."<br/><br/>A spokesman for the Chinese Embassy in London had also called for the event organizers to apologize to Kong, 48, adding that the Chinese Communist Party strongly objected to the content of the panel which was discussing democracy and eroding freedoms since the handover of Hong Kong to China in 1997.<br/><br/>The panel included pro-democracy politicians Nathan Law, Martin Lee, and Hong Kong University law lecturer Benny Tai, one of the founders of the 2014 pro-democracy Umbrella Movement, who has been lambasted by the pro-China press for discussing the concept of independence for the city in public.<br/><br/>The spokesman said the event had "boosted the arrogance of the anti-China separatists," and was "a cause for grave concern and strong objection."<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by RFA's Mandarin and Cantonese Services. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>media, regional influence, umbrella movement, democracy, hong kong</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Cambodia’s PM Hun Sen Denies Reports of Plans For Chinese Naval Base</title>
        <guid>a2f0c78c-5044-4561-b873-ebcc41db421f</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/base-11192018155126.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>He calls the reports part of a ‘disinformation campaign’ and says a base would violate the constitution.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 21:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/base-11192018155126.html/cambodia-us-asean-summit-nov-2018.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Leaders pose for a group photo before the start of the ASEAN-US summit on the sidelines of the 33rd ASEAN summit in Singapore, Nov. 15, 2018.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Cambodia’s Prime Minister Hun Sen on Monday dismissed U.S. concerns that he would grant China the right to build a military base in his country, saying such a move would violate the constitution.<br/><br/>During a meeting of his Council of Ministers, Hun Sen noted that U.S. Deputy Secretary of State John Sullivan met with Cambodia’s Deputy Prime Minister Prak Sokhonn on the sideline of the ASEAN Summit in Singapore last week and expressed concerns about the possible opening of a foreign military base on Cambodian soil.<br/><br/>“I also received a letter from U.S. Vice President Mike Pence raising concerns of the possible presence of a Chinese naval base in Cambodia in the future,” the prime minister said.<br/><br/>“I want to make clear to our compatriots and foreign friends that Cambodia will not violate its own constitution. Cambodia’s Constitution prohibits the presence of foreign armies or military bases inside the country … Cambodia will not permit any foreign military base for a navy, army or air force.”<br/><br/>Hun Sen said he would never allow “foreigners to fight one another on Cambodian territory” and slammed what he called a “disinformation campaign” against Cambodia, adding that he will make his position clear in a written response to Pence.<br/><br/>On Nov. 15, Hong Kong’s Asia Times online news portal cited unnamed diplomatic sources in a report as saying that a 45,000 hectare (111,200-acre) Chinese naval base is being built in Cambodia’s Koh Kong province, “though it remains unclear how far construction has progressed.”<br/><br/>In a press release issued the same day, Cambodia’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs noted that Sullivan had raised the issue with Prak Sokhonn, saying that such an agreement could “significantly affect” relations between Phnom Penh and Washington.<br/><br/>The ministry said Prak Sokhonn “categorically dismissed this as a rumor more than likely spun out of a significant increase of Chinese investment in the area” and said the Cambodian government would “neither allow a foreign military base on its territory nor likewise allow its military to operate [in military bases] abroad” except within the framework of the United Nations.<br/><br/>Cambodia’s Ministry of National Defense followed with a statement on Nov. 17, calling the Asia Times report “fake news” and part of a “foreign campaign to mislead the public and the international community with the intention of destroying the country’s independence and neutrality.”<br/><br/>Chinese investment has poured into Cambodia in recent years and has caused some Cambodians to question what type of influence Beijing might have over their government. China and Cambodia have recently held joint military exercises and Beijing has pledged to help fund a modernization of the Southeast Asian nation’s military.<br/><br/>If such a naval base were built on the Gulf of Thailand, it would allow China to significantly expand patrols on the South China Sea, which Beijing claims much of, while rival Taiwan and ASEAN countries Brunei, Malaysia, the Philippines and Vietnam have their own stakes in the waters.<br/><br/>In 2016, the Hague-Based Permanent Court of Arbitration ruled in favor of the Philippines in its challenge to China’s efforts in the region, but China has rejected the ruling and continues to expand structures including landing strips on islands it has claimed.<br/><br/>When asked on Monday about reports of China’s plan to open a military base in Cambodia, Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesperson Geng Shuang only said that “cooperation between [Cambodia and China] is open and transparent which targets no third party and gives no ground for criticism,” adding that he hoped the U.S. “could view it in a correct way.”<br/><br/><b>Government response</b><br/><br/>Political commentator Kim Sok told RFA’s Khmer Service on Monday that Hun Sen is “hiding the truth” about plans for a Chinese naval base to avoid pressure from the U.S. and Cambodia’s neighbors in the Association of Southeast Asian Nations.<br/><br/>“He fears that such a reaction [from the U.S.] won’t lead to just words, but may also spark prompt measures [against his government], as the issue could create insecurity within the region,” he said.<br/><br/>Meas Nee, another observer, called Hun Sen’s comments “an appropriate response from the government that it must make in order to defend itself” against the allegations, lest it face “pressure from the U.S. and Western nations.”<br/><br/>But he added that the statement was also necessary because the reports could “affect the popularity of the government within the country, as relations between Cambodians and Chinese have not gone so well in the past,” and noted “rising dissatisfaction among Cambodians against the Chinese” as a result of their influence in Cambodia.<br/><br/>A third political commentator named Ly Srey Sros said that Hun Sen’s government routinely denies reports that paint it in a bad light without bothering to investigate the claims.<br/><br/>“I am concerned about this issue because when the Chinese come to Cambodia, surely they request authorization to build something,” she said.<br/><br/>“I believe there may be some secret actions carried out by Chinese technicians claiming to cooperate with Cambodia, and they are trying to hide them from Hun Sen. It’s not good that Hun Sen is so quick to deny the reports.”<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Sovannarith Keo. Written in English by Joshua Lipes.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>military, south china sea, hun sen, china, regional influence</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Cambodia’s Court of Appeal Routinely Fails to Explain Verdicts: Rights Group</title>
        <guid>1623d4c3-668e-4abc-a3c9-a8609b973898</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/judgments-11152018123551.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>Reasoned judgments allow parties to prepare for higher appeals and promote transparency, CCHR says.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 19:48:31 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/judgments-11152018123551.html/cambodia-court-of-appeals-feb-2014.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Villagers call for the release of anti-government protesters from behind a locked main gate outside of Cambodia's Court of Appeal in Phnom Penh, in a file photo.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AP Photo]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Cambodia’s Court of Appeal, which has come under fire for what are widely seen as politically motivated verdicts issued at the behest of Prime Minister Hun Sen’s one-party government, failed to provide a reasoned judgment in nearly three-fourths of cases it tried over the last two years, a rights group said Thursday.<br/><br/>In a report for its Fair Trial Rights Newsletter, the Cambodian Center for Human Rights (CCHR) said its staffers were present for the verdicts of 338 cases between Nov. 1, 2016 and Aug. 31, 2018 at the Phnom Penh Court of Appeal, and found that in 244 instances, or 72 percent of the time, judges only announced their decision without explaining it.<br/><br/>According to CCHR’s findings, the percentage of cases where no reasons were given for the judgment “has drastically increased” since last year, ranging from 61 percent between May and July of 2017 to 89 percent between May and July 2018.<br/><br/>“Unfortunately, in nearly all of the cases monitored by CCHR the judges failed to provide detailed reason for their judgment, instead only announcing the ruling,” CCHR said.<br/><br/>“It is essential that more attention is given on this issue in order to protect fair trial rights in Cambodia.”<br/><br/>According to the International Covenant for Civil and Political Rights, to which Cambodia is a party, and Cambodia’s own Code of Criminal Procedure, parties have the right to a “reasoned judgment,” meaning that a criminal judgment rendered against an individual must explain why and how the verdict has been reached, and why the person was found guilty or innocent.<br/><br/>To do so, the judgment must set out the facts for which the person is convicted—including dates, locations and events—by referring to evidence, and the legal framework on which the ruling is based—both in terms of the crime and liability.<br/><br/>CCHR said that the right to a reasoned judgment is “intrinsically linked to … the right to appeal,” noting that such details allow the parties to see how judges evaluated evidence, and reached factual and legal conclusions, so that they can identify points they would like to challenge before a higher court.<br/><br/>Reasoned judgments also allow upper courts to properly review and analyze the judgment of the lower court, it added.<br/><br/>Additionally, CCHR said, reasoned judgments promote transparency in the judicial system and are critical to the development of jurisprudence and legal certainty about the interpretation and application of the law.<br/><br/>The rights group noted that in March this year, the United Nations Special Rapporteur on the situation of human rights in Cambodia, Rhona Smith, called for “greater transparency in judicial decision-making,” as well as “more consistent decisions on evidence and on the application of the law,” and recommended that “plans to make public judgments and legal reasoning should be progressed” in the nation.<br/><br/>In order to protect the right to a reasoned judgment, CCHR called on Cambodia’s government and judiciary to require that all judges cite relevant articles of law and list the key evidence on which they rely for their ruling in their judgment, and set out detailed guidelines indicating the kind of information which must be included in a judgment and ensure that those guidelines are strictly implemented.<br/><br/>It also recommended that defendants be guaranteed to receive reasoned written judgments within a reasonable time, and that those judgments are made publicly available.<br/><br/>When asked for comment, Ministry of Justice spokesman Chin Malin told RFA’s Khmer Service he had yet to see CCHR’s report and questioned the methods used to compile it, saying it was unclear whether the group had approached the Court of Appeal to verify its findings.<br/><br/>“We are planning to discuss the methodology for this report with CCHR’s staff,” he said.<br/><br/>“If we find that the report is accurate, we will accept the findings and correct the problem.”<br/><br/>Chin Malin said the ministry is currently training judges to provide defendants with written judgments.<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Samean Yun. Written in English by Joshua Lipes.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>judicial system, courts, hun sen, trials</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Report on Ruling Chinese Communist Party Cell at Hong Kong University Deleted</title>
        <guid>0239dbf0-84a7-46c7-a445-717ad6b5506c</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/deleted-11142018114211.html</link>

	    
	         <category>China</category>
	    

        <description>China's National Judges College party chief calls on Hong Kong branch members to 'fight against wrong words and actions.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 17:07:46 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/deleted-11142018114211.html/china-judges2-111418.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Huang Wenjun, president of China's National Judge's College, lectures at Hong Kong's City University, Oct. 20, 2018.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[National Judges College webpage]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>An official training institute for Chinese judges has deleted a report detailing the setting up of a temporary branch of the ruling Chinese Communist Party on a Hong Kong university campus, after it was reported by the city's media.<br/><br/>The move comes amid growing public opposition to the erosion of Hong Kong's status as a separate jurisdiction from mainland China and the maintenance of its traditional freedoms for 50 years, as promised in the treaty governing the city's 1997 handover to Chinese rule.<br/><br/>According to an Oct. 25 article on the official website of mainland China's National Judges College, its party chief Huang Wenjun attended a meeting of the party branch that was set up for Chinese judges studying at Hong Kong's City University.<br/><br/>However, only a cached copy of the article was available through Google on Wednesday, with the original link returning an error code for "empty" content.<br/><br/>Huang told the meeting that its chief job was to uphold President Xi Jinping's vision for a "new era" of socialism with Chinese characteristics, in particular, to ensure that none of the visiting master's students embraced the wrong kind of ideology during their stay in the city.<br/><br/>"We must strengthen political power and effectively enhance political acumen and political discernment," Huang told the meeting, which was attended by 39 Communist Party members and 11 non-party members.<br/><br/>"Dare to fight against wrong words and actions!" he said.<br/><br/>Neither City University nor lawmaker Priscilla Leung, who teaches in the university's law department, had replied to requests for comment by the time of writing.<br/><br/><b>Temporary organizations</b><br/><br/>However, a report on the City U website said the school has trained more than 800 Chinese judges since the inception of its master's program in conjunction with the National Judges College 10 years ago.<br/><br/>Hong Kong political commentator Liu Ruishao told RFA that party cells are being set up to serve existing Communist Party members.<br/><br/>"They may have left mainland China, but they haven't left the party or its organizations," Liu said. "The party cells are set up as temporary organizations to maintain their life within the party."<br/><br/>"They have had similar activities before, but they have never done it openly before. Perhaps they want Hong Kong people to get used to the party's organizational model," he said.<br/><br/>Liu said the announcement of Huang's visit to the party branch had a strong flavor of ideology.<br/><br/>"They are going to war against wrong words and deeds, which of course is a matter of concern. Perhaps this is a call for party members to expand their work into the academic sphere, or into society at large?"<br/><br/>"A party presence also implies a party disciplinary presence, as well as investigators responsible for party discipline," Liu said.<br/><br/>The Chinese Communist Party openly sets up overseas "temporary branches" to oversee the ideological correctness of party members studying overseas, and to draw in new recruits from among Chinese nationals on campus.<br/><br/><b>Eroding status</b><br/><br/>However, the deletion of the article comes as democratic politicians, rights activists, and overseas governments have pointed to the rapid erosion of the "one country, two systems" concept protecting Hong Kong's separate status.<br/><br/>A report last month from the U.S. Congressional-Executive Commission on China (CECC) said the city is losing the autonomy promised under a 1984 Sino-British agreement governing the handover.<br/><br/>Citing the banning of political parties and politicians campaigning for Hong Kong's autonomy and independence, the vetting of candidates and the narrowing of space for political debate, the city's autonomy faces "continued erosion," the report said.<br/><br/>Bruce Lui, senior journalism lecturer at Hong Kong Baptist University, said the presence of Communist Party branches on the city's campuses could affect academic freedom.<br/><br/>"These organizations are everywhere," Lui said. "But they are the enemies of academic freedom, because the Communist Party opposes the universal values of the West, including academic freedom."<br/><br/>He called on the authorities to investigate whether such branches were legal in Hong Kong.<br/><br/>"If you say that you want to ban other political groups as illegal organizations, you should actually investigate the Chinese Communist Party for being an illegal organization," Lui said. "However, I can't see this ever being enforced."<br/><br/><b>'Imminent threat'</b><br/><br/>Hong Kong in September formally banned a pro-independence political party, in a move strongly criticized by rights groups and pro-democracy politicians for curbing freedom of speech in the city.<br/><br/>Using colonial-era legislation once used to target "triad" criminal gangs in the city, the government ruled that Andy Chan's separatist Hong Kong National Party posed an "imminent threat" to China’s territorial integrity and national security, because Chan had refused to rule out the use of force or civil disobedience.<br/><br/>Communist Party branches, or cells, have long been a feature of political life in mainland China, but are increasingly being used as a vehicle for the expansion of the party's United Front ideological campaign, which seeks to bring specific groups of people into the party's fold, as well as keeping tabs on what they are doing, saying, and even thinking.<br/><br/>According to an article last November in the <i>Global Times</i> newspaper, sister paper to Communist Party mouthpiece the <i>People's Daily</i>, party members at overseas branches are required to hand in "a report about their thoughts every three months, participate in a group party activity and hold a party meeting once every half-year."<br/><br/>Their aim is to strengthen overseas students' political convictions and help them "resist the corrosive influence of harmful ideologies," it said.<br/><br/>Similar reports have emerged of party branches being set up by Chinese students last year at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, as well as campuses in Ohio, New York, Connecticut, North Dakota, and West Virginia, according to a recent report from the U.S.-based journal Foreign Policy.<br/><br/>The practice also extends to groups of employees of the Chinese state working overseas, according to online statements on the websites of state-owned enterprises.<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by Tam Siu-yin for RFA's Cantonese Service, and by Gao Feng for the Mandarin Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>justice system, regional influence, hong kong</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Repeated Blows to Free Speech Spark Outcry in Hong Kong</title>
        <guid>330b6de9-8537-45b2-90fa-cd562bd7016c</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/outcry-11092018110146.html</link>

	    
	         <category>China</category>
	    

        <description>Democratic politicians and journalists say Beijing's 'red lines' are vague and subject to change, and that the city's government nods along with them too willingly.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 17:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/outcry-11092018110146.html/china-majian-110918.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Chinese dissident writer Ma Jian waves to reporters after arriving in Hong Kong, Nov. 9, 2018.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>A second venue in Hong Kong pulled out of hosting a literary event by dissident Chinese author Ma Jian, after immigration authorities in Hong Kong allowed him to enter the city under its visa-free visitor program.<br/><br/>"I was let through. No problem," Ma said via his Twitter account after landing in Hong Kong on Friday. But he added: "Just heard that the second venue has pulled out of hosting my talks."<br/><br/>Hong Kong's Tai Kwun Arts and Heritage Centre canceled Ma's Hong Kong International Literary Festival (HKILF) event, in which Ma plans to discuss his latest book <i>China Dream</i>, a biting satire of President Xi Jinping's concept of a resurgent China.<br/><br/>But the venue apparently changed its mind and reinstated the event on Friday after a public outcry, the HKILF said in a statement on Facebook.<br/><br/>"The Festival is pleased to announce that ... Tai Kwun are now offering to host the events as scheduled. We are delighted to be able to hold our events with Ma Jian tomorrow as planned," it said.<br/><br/>"The principles of free speech and cultural expression are central to our mission as an international literary festival," it said.<br/><br/>Tai Kwun said it had "reconsidered our position in light of the possibility that these events might be prevented from taking place altogether."<br/><br/>Ma said: "I am pleased that Tai Kwun has reconsidered, and I am looking forward to speaking about my book, <i>China Dream</i>," according to the HKILF statement.<br/><br/>Ma, who is described in the festival's promotional material as "China's answer to Orwell, Swift and Solzhenitsyn," had earlier tweeted that he had no political agenda other than freedom of speech, and Tai Kwun said this "clarification" had contributed to its change of heart.<br/><br/><b>Entry to Hong Kong refused</b><br/><br/>But the reinstatement of Ma's event will likely do little quell concerns over vanishing freedoms in Hong Kong.<br/><br/>The cancellations came as Hong Kong immigration authorities refused a visitor entry stamp to the <i>Financial Times' </i>Asia news editor Victor Mallet, who had had his work permit revoked after hosting a discussion event featuring pro-independence politician Andy Chan in August in spite of requests to cancel from ruling Chinese Communist Party officials.<br/><br/>Mak Yin-ting, former chair of the Hong Kong Journalists' Association (HKJA), said the refusal of entry to Mallet was unprecedented.<br/><br/>"If Mallet isn't even allowed in as a visitor, then that suggests even more strongly that there are political considerations at play in the background," Mak told RFA. "It gives the impression that Hong Kong is pretty similar ... to the rest of mainland China."<br/><br/>"Maybe I could even be refused entry illegally to Hong Kong at some point in the future," Mak said. "Maybe they will seek to punish any dissenting voices in that way."<br/><br/>Meanwhile, Democratic Party lawmaker Ted Hui hit out at Tai Kwun's decision, which he attributed to the venue's ultimate owners, the Hong Kong Jockey Club.<br/><br/>"It seems that in its management of Tai Kwun, the Jockey Club is willing to sacrifice freedom of speech and expression in Hong Kong," Hui told reporters on Friday during a protest outside the arts venue on Friday.<br/><br/>"The Jockey Club has shown it is subject to political pressure and interference, because it wouldn't allow Ma Jian's event to go ahead at this venue," he said. "The Jockey Club itself also self-censors in order to minimize its political risk."<br/><br/><b>Decisions made 'according to law'</b><br/><br/>The Hong Kong Jockey Club, which dates back to the dawn of colonial era horse-racing in 1884, is the city's largest community benefactor, operating as a not-for-profit organization and funding venues, clinics, and community projects.<br/><br/>Hong Kong's secretary for security John Lee declined on Friday to comment on individual cases, but said immigration officers make their decisions "according to law."<br/><br/>"The Immigration Department will always consider the specific circumstances of each case, and make decisions based on Hong Kong laws and established policies," Lee told journalists in response to the decision to refuse entry to Mallet.<br/><br/>"The number of overseas visitors is almost 60 million [annually]; some are approved for entry, and some are not," he said. "It is normal for the immigration department to carry out immigration controls."<br/><br/>Democratic Party lawmakers protested the decision on Friday, saying Lee's explanation was unacceptable.<br/><br/>"We protest political pressure! We want freedom of the press back!" they shouted, calling on the city's chief executive Carrie Lam to apologize and explain the decision to deny Mallet entry.<br/><br/>Democratic Party lawmaker Andrew Wan said the decision had dealt a severe blow to freedom of speech in the city, which was promised the continuation of its existing freedoms under the terms of the 1997 handover to China.<br/><br/>"I think that this is very bad news that will cause huge concern in the international community over whether Hong Kong really has free speech, and whether the immigration regime will be used to suppress it," Wan said.<br/><br/>"Are foreign correspondents terrorists, or some kind of scourge, that they should be treated in this way?"<br/><br/>Veteran journalist Claudia Mo said the latest developments show that Beijing is keen to turn Hong Kong into just another Chinese city sooner rather than later.<br/><br/>"The Mallet incident, the cancellation of the exhibition by [satirical cartoonist] Badiucao [last week], and the cancellation of Ma Jian's literary event are similar in that they are effectively a ban on their speech," Mo said.<br/><br/>"These red lines, that exist in the imagination of Carrie Lam, have clearly been drawn by Beijing, and we know for sure now that they can be moved," she said. "Hong Kong is getting closer and closer to the end [of free speech]."<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by Wen Yuqing for RFA's Cantonese Service, and by Gao Feng for the Mandarin Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>censorship, culture, hong kong</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Cambodia’s Hun Sen Denies Plan to Free Opposition Leader Kem Sokha</title>
        <guid>7d8c22ff-0cc8-43d2-9a1a-664ea9e038d3</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/plan-11072018160904.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>But former CNRP leader Sam Rainsy says the move will come in December in response to international pressure.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 21:22:50 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/plan-11072018160904.html/khmer-ballot-110718.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[CNRP president Kem Sokha casts a ballot in local elections in Phnom Penh, June 4, 2017.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Cambodian prime minister Hun Sen denied on Wednesday he has plans to free opposition leader Kem Sokha, rejecting comments made on Facebook by former opposition chief Sam Rainsy, who said the move will be made in December.<br/><br/>“No, I won’t release him,” Hun Sen said, addressing a gathering of hundreds of workers in southwestern Cambodia’s Takeo province and adding that the former opposition leader, now living in exile in France, believes Kem Sokha will be freed in response to international pressure.<br/><br/>Because Kem Sokha has not yet been convicted of a crime, the prime minister has no power to apply to Cambodia’s King Norodom Sihamoni for a pardon that would free him, Hun Sen said.<br/><br/>Hun Sen also rejected a suggestion made by Sam Rainsy that Kem Sokha, arrested in September 2017 for treason charges widely seen as politically motivated, would be released on Dec. 29 during a 20-year anniversary celebration of Hun Sen’s “Win Win Policy” taking credit for the ending in 1998 of a long-running civil war.<br/><br/>“Please wait and see, Sam Rainsy,” Hun Sen said.<br/><br/>Reached by RFA’s Khmer Service, Kem Sokha’s lawyer Peng Heng declined to comment on the case.<br/><br/>Sam Rainsy, who has been living in self-imposed exile for nearly three years to avoid a string of convictions by courts seen as beholden to Cambodia’s Prime Minister Hun Sen, stepped down as head of the Cambodia National Rescue Party (CNRP) in February last year to prevent a state-ordered dissolution of the party.<br/><br/>But the Supreme Court dissolved the CNRP anyway in November, saying the party had played a role in an alleged plot by Kem Sokha to overthrow the government, and opposition candidates were banned from taking part in the country’s July 29, 2018 general election, which Hun Sen's ruling Cambodian People's Party (CPP) won handily in the absence of a viable political opposition.<br/><br/>Hun Sen, who secured another five-year term to add to his 33 years in office after official election results were announced on Aug. 15, has made a practice of heavy-handed crackdowns on his critics, followed by a relaxation of restrictions after facing international condemnation.<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Samean Yun. Written in English by Richard Finney.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>hun sen, kem sokha, sam rainsy, justice system, cnrp, cpp</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>No Rights Problems in Cambodia, Official Asserts After Meeting With UN Envoy</title>
        <guid>9f987603-5ded-4af8-a518-7a6e5579b765</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/official-11052018172639.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>Meanwhile, villagers attempting to present petitions in land-dispute cases are held and questioned by police.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 22:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/official-11052018172639.html/khmer-rhona2-102918.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[UN special rapporteur Rhona Smith speaks to reporters in Phnom Penh, Cambodia, Aug. 18, 2017.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[RFA]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>There are no human rights violations in Cambodia, the head of a Cambodian government committee told reporters on Monday following talks with a United Nations rapporteur on the rights record of the autocratic Southeast Asian country that has been run by strongman Hun Sen for 33 years.<br/><br/>“Accusations that Cambodia violates human rights are, frankly, not true,” Keo Remy, head of the Cambodian Human Rights Committee, said in Phnom Penh after meeting with U.N. Special Rapporteur on Human Rights in Cambodia Rhona Smith.<br/><br/>Especially in issues related to Cambodian workers, the Cambodian government has been paying closer attention in recent months, with Prime Minister Hun Sen addressing gatherings of workers on a regular basis, Keo Remy said.<br/><br/>“Some of our neighboring countries have single-party governments, and their human rights situations are no better than ours, but [the European Union] deals with such countries by giving them trade preferences,” he said.<br/><br/>Cambodia banned its main opposition party and jailed its leader in 2017, paving the way for Hun Sen’s ruling party to in all 125 seats on offer in parliamentary elections in July. <br/><br/>Also speaking to reporters, Rhona Smith said there remain steps the government can take to improve the human rights situation in the country “not just for the EU but for other development partners of choice for Cambodia.”<br/><br/>“I think there are always issues, and there are always challenges,” Smith said.<br/><br/>“But I think the government can certainly, if it chooses, improve the human rights situation in Cambodia,” Smith said.<br/><br/>In a move aimed at countering European criticism of his rule, Hun Sen has worked recently to persuade leaders from the bloc to forgo threatened sanctions against his government following July 29 national elections widely regarded as rigged.<br/><br/>Cambodia’s Supreme Court dissolved the opposition Cambodia National Rescue Party (CNRP) in September 2017 for its role in an alleged plot to topple the government amid a months-long crackdown that also targeted NGOs and the independent media—ensuring that Hun Sen’s ruling Cambodian People’s Party (CPP) emerged victorious from the July ballot.<br/><b><br/>Petitioners held, questioned</b><br/><br/>Meanwhile, Cambodian villagers trying to deliver petitions in land-dispute cases to the residence of Hun Sen were detained by police on Monday and released three hours later after being questioned, with five others later presenting petitions to the Phnom Penh office of the United Nations Office of the High Commissioner for Human Rights (UNOHCHR), sources said.<br/><br/>Speaking to RFA’s Khmer Service via Skype, one of the detained women, Chray Nim, said “This morning, they used violence against us. They threatened to slap our faces and to attack us.”<br/><br/>“We are neither culprits, nor thieves or robbers,” she said. “We are merely normal citizens.”<br/><br/>“Why did they treat us like this?”<br/><br/>Also speaking to RFA, Thida Klus--executive director of Silaka, a Cambodia-based civil society organization focused on good governance--voiced disappointment with authorities’ handling of the detained villagers, saying the women had not come to the capital “for pleasure.”<br/><br/>“They have lost their land for farming and have no way to earn their daily living,” she said.<br/><br/>“The government should urgently settle their disputes.”<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Sovannarith Keo. Written in English by Richard Finney.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>human rights, un, hun sen, cpp, cnrp, land dispute</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>NGOs Demand End to Impunity, Independent Probes in Cases of Murdered Cambodian Reporters (STICKY)</title>
        <guid>0a29ee59-eeca-444a-a2e1-68450d752612</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/impunity-11022018164107.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>At least 13 reporters have been murdered in the country since 1994, with nearly no convictions.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/impunity-11022018164107.html/cambodia-teang-theav-march-2015-crop.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Teang Theav, wife of slain reporter Suon Chan, speaks to reporters outside of a court in Kampong Chhnang province, March 2, 2015.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[RFA]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Dozens of nongovernmental organizations marked International Day to End Impunity for Crimes Against Journalists Friday by slamming Cambodia for failing to hold the perpetrators of crimes against reporters and rights activists accountable and demanding independent, transparent probes of their cases.<br/><br/>“When journalists are targeted by violence for what they write or report, freedom of expression is stifled and replaced by self-censorship and fear; the public is denied information; and the powerful cannot be held to account,” said the statement, signed by 42 watchdogs—including global groups Amnesty International and Human Rights Watch, and local organizations Adhoc and Licadho.<br/><br/>“When the state fails to investigate and punish violence against journalists, it sends a chilling message that attacks on journalists are permissible.”<br/><br/>The NGOs noted that since 1994, at least 13 journalists have been murdered in Cambodia for their reporting, and that all but one of them were “engaged in activities that posed a direct threat to powerful individuals within the Cambodian elite.”<br/><br/>In 11 of the cases, no one was convicted for the murders, the groups said, while in seven, no suspect was arrested or interrogated. “Serious concerns remain” in the two cases where a trial took place, they added.<br/><br/>And while no journalists have been killed in the last two years in Cambodia, reporters are regularly targeted with judicial harassment, according to the statement, including trumped-up charges, and media outlets perceived as critical of Prime Minister Hun Sen’s regime have been forced to close.<br/><br/>The groups noted that impunity in Cambodia is not limited to attacks against journalists, citing the murders of environmental activist Chut Wutty, trade unionists Chea Vichea and Ros Sovannareth, and political analyst Kem Ley as representative of “the thousands of instances of abuse” against outspoken critics that have “gone unaddressed” by authorities.<br/><br/>“We condemn the rampant impunity that harms Cambodian people and society and demand justice for all those whose rights have been cast aside,” the groups said.<br/><br/>“We call on the authorities to prosecute perpetrators of crimes committed against journalists and human rights defenders by undertaking effective, independent, and transparent investigations and prosecutions in accordance with international human rights standards … and to restore the integrity of the Cambodian legal system.”<br/><br/><strong>Call for justice</strong><br/><br/>Separately on Friday, Club of Cambodia Journalists president Pen Bona urged authorities to seek justice for the 13 slain journalists—Thou Char Mongkol, Nun Chan, Chan Dara, Thun Bun Ly, Chet Duong Daravuth, Pich Em, Dok Sokhan, Ou Saroeun, Chour Chetharith, Khim Sambo, Hang Serei Oudom, Suon Chan, and Taing Try.<br/><br/>Speaking in an interview with RFA’s Khmer Service, he said it was a “good sign” that no reporters had been killed in Cambodia over the past two years, but questioned why there have been no breakthroughs in finding those responsible for the 13 murders since 1994, despite authorities claiming that they continue to investigate the cases.<br/><br/>Ministry of Interior spokesman Khieu Sopheak could not be reached for comment Friday, but has previously pledged that authorities “won’t close those cases until the perpetrators are brought to justice.”<br/><br/>But Ministry of Justice spokesman Chin Malin on Friday hit out at the statement from the NGOs, telling RFA that “there is no impunity” in the cases of the slain journalists, as investigations continue.<br/><br/>“It isn’t impunity—it’s still at the investigative stage,” he said, adding that the cases are “complicated” and require more time to close.<br/><br/>Nop Vy of the Cambodian Center for Independent Media, however, refuted Chin Malin’s claims, noting that the journalists had all been killed after reporting on sensitive issues, including corruption scandals involving powerful people.<br/><br/>He urged authorities to “be more responsible” because journalists are working to improve society, and said a culture of impunity had negatively impacted local reporting.<br/><br/>“We have seen a delay in bringing justice to victims,” he said, adding that authorities should “speed up investigations to end impunity.”<br/><br/><strong>Internet freedom</strong><br/><br/>Friday’s statement came days after U.S. NGO Freedom House said in its annual “Freedom on the Net” report that of the 65 countries it monitors, Cambodia was one of five nations that “experienced the steepest deterioration in internet freedom over the last five years,” citing amendments initiated by the ruling Cambodian People’s Party (CPP) that led to an uptick in arrests for online political commentary.<br/><br/>Freedom House designated Cambodia “partly free” with a score of 55 over the past year, on a scale where zero represents “most free” and 100 indicates “least free,” noting a crackdown on online dissent by Hun Sen’s government that led to a “surge in arrests and prison sentences,” and ensured his party’s victory ahead of a July 29 election.<br/><br/>Council of Ministers spokesman Phay Siphan slammed the Freedom House report Friday as “bogus and lies,” saying Cambodia “doesn’t have any law restricting internet freedom.”<br/><br/>Phay Siphan said Hun Sen’s regime is working to improve internet access for everyone throughout the country, but warned that internet freedom “doesn’t give users free rein to insult people or incite violence.”<br/><br/>When asked about claims in the report that China has provided Cambodia with training on how to monitor the internet use of its citizens, the spokesman said that authorities “only monitor the internet to fight against terrorism and for other security reasons.”<br/><br/><strong>Requesting happier news</strong><br/><br/>Also on Friday, Hun Sen’s wife and Cambodia Red Cross chairwoman Bun Rany urged members of the local media to “decrease reporting on crimes, rapes, and deaths from traffic accidents,” asking them to instead focus on the work her husband’s government has done to develop the country.<br/><br/>Pro-government media outlet Fresh News quoted Bun Rany during a donation distribution in Kampong Chhnang province as saying that “local TV stations don’t broadcast news about government efforts that have helped to develop the country, but only about violent crimes, suicides, traffic accidents, rapes and killings.”<br/><br/>“Every morning, I only see news about people dying, rapes and killings. I would like to use this forum to appeal to all TV stations to broadcast government achievements instead of bad topics.”<br/><br/>The Red Cross chairwoman did not specify what kind of developments she would prefer the nation’s news organizations to focus on.<br/><strong><i><br/>Reported by RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Samean Yun. Written in English by Joshua Lipes.</i></strong></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>censorship, media, reporters, internet, freedom house, hun sen, cambodia elections</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 </channel>
 
</rss>