<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
 

 

 <channel>
    <title>Main Story Feed</title>
     <language>en</language>
    <description>
        
            This is main feed for whole English subsite
        
    </description>
    <link>https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/gp-app/main-feed</link>
    <copyright>Radio Free Asia</copyright>

    
	     <category>news, commentaries, cartoons</category>
    

	 
	 <atom:link href="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/gp-app/main-feed/rss2.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
     

	 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>NGOs Demand End to Impunity, Independent Probes in Cases of Murdered Cambodian Reporters (STICKY)</title>
        <guid>0a29ee59-eeca-444a-a2e1-68450d752612</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/impunity-11022018164107.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>At least 13 reporters have been murdered in the country since 1994, with nearly no convictions.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/impunity-11022018164107.html/cambodia-teang-theav-march-2015-crop.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Teang Theav, wife of slain reporter Suon Chan, speaks to reporters outside of a court in Kampong Chhnang province, March 2, 2015.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[RFA]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Dozens of nongovernmental organizations marked International Day to End Impunity for Crimes Against Journalists Friday by slamming Cambodia for failing to hold the perpetrators of crimes against reporters and rights activists accountable and demanding independent, transparent probes of their cases.<br/><br/>“When journalists are targeted by violence for what they write or report, freedom of expression is stifled and replaced by self-censorship and fear; the public is denied information; and the powerful cannot be held to account,” said the statement, signed by 42 watchdogs—including global groups Amnesty International and Human Rights Watch, and local organizations Adhoc and Licadho.<br/><br/>“When the state fails to investigate and punish violence against journalists, it sends a chilling message that attacks on journalists are permissible.”<br/><br/>The NGOs noted that since 1994, at least 13 journalists have been murdered in Cambodia for their reporting, and that all but one of them were “engaged in activities that posed a direct threat to powerful individuals within the Cambodian elite.”<br/><br/>In 11 of the cases, no one was convicted for the murders, the groups said, while in seven, no suspect was arrested or interrogated. “Serious concerns remain” in the two cases where a trial took place, they added.<br/><br/>And while no journalists have been killed in the last two years in Cambodia, reporters are regularly targeted with judicial harassment, according to the statement, including trumped-up charges, and media outlets perceived as critical of Prime Minister Hun Sen’s regime have been forced to close.<br/><br/>The groups noted that impunity in Cambodia is not limited to attacks against journalists, citing the murders of environmental activist Chut Wutty, trade unionists Chea Vichea and Ros Sovannareth, and political analyst Kem Ley as representative of “the thousands of instances of abuse” against outspoken critics that have “gone unaddressed” by authorities.<br/><br/>“We condemn the rampant impunity that harms Cambodian people and society and demand justice for all those whose rights have been cast aside,” the groups said.<br/><br/>“We call on the authorities to prosecute perpetrators of crimes committed against journalists and human rights defenders by undertaking effective, independent, and transparent investigations and prosecutions in accordance with international human rights standards … and to restore the integrity of the Cambodian legal system.”<br/><br/><strong>Call for justice</strong><br/><br/>Separately on Friday, Club of Cambodia Journalists president Pen Bona urged authorities to seek justice for the 13 slain journalists—Thou Char Mongkol, Nun Chan, Chan Dara, Thun Bun Ly, Chet Duong Daravuth, Pich Em, Dok Sokhan, Ou Saroeun, Chour Chetharith, Khim Sambo, Hang Serei Oudom, Suon Chan, and Taing Try.<br/><br/>Speaking in an interview with RFA’s Khmer Service, he said it was a “good sign” that no reporters had been killed in Cambodia over the past two years, but questioned why there have been no breakthroughs in finding those responsible for the 13 murders since 1994, despite authorities claiming that they continue to investigate the cases.<br/><br/>Ministry of Interior spokesman Khieu Sopheak could not be reached for comment Friday, but has previously pledged that authorities “won’t close those cases until the perpetrators are brought to justice.”<br/><br/>But Ministry of Justice spokesman Chin Malin on Friday hit out at the statement from the NGOs, telling RFA that “there is no impunity” in the cases of the slain journalists, as investigations continue.<br/><br/>“It isn’t impunity—it’s still at the investigative stage,” he said, adding that the cases are “complicated” and require more time to close.<br/><br/>Nop Vy of the Cambodian Center for Independent Media, however, refuted Chin Malin’s claims, noting that the journalists had all been killed after reporting on sensitive issues, including corruption scandals involving powerful people.<br/><br/>He urged authorities to “be more responsible” because journalists are working to improve society, and said a culture of impunity had negatively impacted local reporting.<br/><br/>“We have seen a delay in bringing justice to victims,” he said, adding that authorities should “speed up investigations to end impunity.”<br/><br/><strong>Internet freedom</strong><br/><br/>Friday’s statement came days after U.S. NGO Freedom House said in its annual “Freedom on the Net” report that of the 65 countries it monitors, Cambodia was one of five nations that “experienced the steepest deterioration in internet freedom over the last five years,” citing amendments initiated by the ruling Cambodian People’s Party (CPP) that led to an uptick in arrests for online political commentary.<br/><br/>Freedom House designated Cambodia “partly free” with a score of 55 over the past year, on a scale where zero represents “most free” and 100 indicates “least free,” noting a crackdown on online dissent by Hun Sen’s government that led to a “surge in arrests and prison sentences,” and ensured his party’s victory ahead of a July 29 election.<br/><br/>Council of Ministers spokesman Phay Siphan slammed the Freedom House report Friday as “bogus and lies,” saying Cambodia “doesn’t have any law restricting internet freedom.”<br/><br/>Phay Siphan said Hun Sen’s regime is working to improve internet access for everyone throughout the country, but warned that internet freedom “doesn’t give users free rein to insult people or incite violence.”<br/><br/>When asked about claims in the report that China has provided Cambodia with training on how to monitor the internet use of its citizens, the spokesman said that authorities “only monitor the internet to fight against terrorism and for other security reasons.”<br/><br/><strong>Requesting happier news</strong><br/><br/>Also on Friday, Hun Sen’s wife and Cambodia Red Cross chairwoman Bun Rany urged members of the local media to “decrease reporting on crimes, rapes, and deaths from traffic accidents,” asking them to instead focus on the work her husband’s government has done to develop the country.<br/><br/>Pro-government media outlet Fresh News quoted Bun Rany during a donation distribution in Kampong Chhnang province as saying that “local TV stations don’t broadcast news about government efforts that have helped to develop the country, but only about violent crimes, suicides, traffic accidents, rapes and killings.”<br/><br/>“Every morning, I only see news about people dying, rapes and killings. I would like to use this forum to appeal to all TV stations to broadcast government achievements instead of bad topics.”<br/><br/>The Red Cross chairwoman did not specify what kind of developments she would prefer the nation’s news organizations to focus on.<br/><strong><i><br/>Reported by RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Samean Yun. Written in English by Joshua Lipes.</i></strong></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>censorship, media, reporters, internet, freedom house, hun sen, cambodia elections</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Nepal Deports 6 Tibetan Asylum Seekers to China</title>
        <guid>f0c71f7a-f687-4bd0-b5d9-6a38d753d1db</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/tibet/nepal-deport-09092019064318.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Tibet</category>
	    

        <description>The six were arrested upon reaching Nepali soil and swiftly handed over to China on Sept. 5.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/tibet/nepal-deport-09092019064318.html/nepal-tibet.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Tibetans living in Nepal honor the Dalai Lama, in file photo.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[RFA]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Nepal deported six Tibetans who had crossed into the Himalayan country to seek asylum, handing them over to Chinese police shortly after they crossed the border last week, two witnesses told RFA’s Tibetan Service.</p>
<p>“When those six Tibetan escapees arrived on Nepal soil [on foot], at a place called Legme, the Nepalese border police arrested them. From there, the Nepali police led the handcuffed Tibetan refugees to Simikto police station," said the source, a trader who requested anonymity to protect his personal security.</p>
<p>"The Nepali police handed over those arrested Tibetan refugees to the Chinese border police on the evening of that day, September 5<sup>th</sup>,” added the source.</p>
<p>"The handcuffed Tibetan refugees were wailing in great distress at their fate, and were pleading the police with folded hands not to take them back to the Chinese,” said the source.</p>
<p>Simikto is the administrative headquarter of Humla district of Karnali Pradesh in the northwestern corner of Nepal. Simikto airport is the main tourist gateway on the Nepalese side to Mount Kailash and Lake Manasarovar, revered pilgrimage sites in Tibet.</p>
<p>The six had crossed the Nepali border from Purang (In Chinese, Burang) county in Ngari (Ari) prefecture. The source said they had ruddy complexions and wore Tibetan clothing.</p>
<p>"On the way, many local Nepali bystanders witnessed the Nepali police leading them away in handcuffs," added the source.</p>
<p>“When the armed Nepalese police were escorting them, the residents were waved off from approaching them closer," said a second source, a Tibetan living in Kathmandu, the Nepal capital.</p>
<p>"Without even keeping them for one day at Simikot, the Nepali police returned them to the Chinese authorities,” said the Kathmandu source.</p>
<p>"The Nepali police warned residents not to share the news of this incident, and if any of them caught for doing it, will face severe consequences," added the Kathmandu resident.</p>
<p>“The Tibetans repeatedly appealed to the Nepalese police that they were going to Nepal to seek asylum. Meanwhile the local Nepalese also pleaded with the police to release and let them go. But the police did not heed their request and they also got annoyed by their interference,’ said the first source.</p>
<p>Nepal shares a long border with Tibet and is home to around 20,000 exiles who began arriving in 1959 when a failed Tibetan uprising against Chinese rule forced Tibet’s spiritual leader the Dalai Lama into exile in Dharamsala in India’s Himalayan foothills.</p>
<p>Nepal cites the "One-China Policy" Beijing demands from countries and its strong ties with its wealthier neighbor in cracking down on Tibetan community activities in the country, such as elections among the refugee community and birthday celebrations for the Dalai Lama.</p>
<p><b><i>Reported by Kunsang Tenzin </i></b><b><i>for RFA’s Tibetan Service. Translated by Dorjee Damdul. Written in English by Paul Eckert.</i></b></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords></keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Cambodian Opposition Figure to Meet US Lawmakers and Join Democracy Rally in Washington</title>
        <guid>a90aff33-3813-4f40-b534-a002a88c1093</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/meach-sovannara-in-dc-01182019160128.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>Ex-political prisoner Meach Sovannara says the Cambodia National Rescue Party will remain united despite a crackdown by the ruling party.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 20:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/meach-sovannara-in-dc-01182019160128.html/meach.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[meach]]></media:description>
                
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>A senior Cambodia National Rescue Party (CNRP) member, released from prison last year, will join pro-democracy demonstrations in Washington this weekend and discuss his detainment at the hands of the Cambodian government with U.S. lawmakers, he told RFA’s Khmer Service on Friday.</p>
<p>The former political prisoner, Meach Sovannara, who holds dual Cambodian and U.S. citizenship, will meet with congressmen Ted Yoho (R-MN), Steve Chabot (R-OH) and Alan Lowenthal (D-CA) to discuss his experience of being a political prisoner on two occasions, detained for a cumulative period of about four years.</p>
<p>In his most recent detention, Sovannara along with 11 others had been incarcerated since 2014 for their alleged role in a July 15, 2014 demonstration held by the CNRP against government manipulation of the general election a year earlier.</p>
<p>
<iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HEeH7eY0Hz4" width="560"></iframe>
</p>
<p>They received sentences of from seven to 20 years in prison but were released in August 2018 under a royal pardon.</p>
<p>Sovannara said that his detention affected him both “financially and mentally.”</p>
<p>“I want to request that [the congressmen introduce legislation to] intervene to normalize democracy in Cambodia because it is narrowing down,” he said in an interview with RFA in Washington.</p>
<p><span>“Cambodia is now not a multi-party state. It is a one-party state, and that’s dangerous for Cambodia,” he said.</span></p>
<p>“I have already stressed my stance: that I will die with the CNRP,” he said.</p>
<p>He said that he will join with other party members in protests on Saturday aimed at restoring Cambodian democracy.</p>
<p>“All the people can participate in the fight for democracy; we want democracy to survive,” he said.</p>
<p>“The current government in Cambodia regards the voters as their slaves,” he said, adding, “We want a collective voice.”</p>
<p>“If the current leaders say that they are good leaders, they must release Kem Sokha,” he said.</p>
<p><span>CNRP President Kem Sokha has been under house arrest since September 2017 facing charges of treason.</span></p>
<p>Sovannara added that Prime Minister Hun Sen’s Cambodian People’s Party (CPP) dissolved the CNRP in Nov. 2017, fearing they would lose [in the 2018 general] election.</p>
<p>In the July election, the CPP captured all 125 seats in Cambodia’s National Assembly, with only token opposition from minor political parties.</p>
<p><i><strong>Reported by Huot Vuthy for RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Samean Yun. Written in English by Eugene Whong.</strong></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords></keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Cambodia Allows Ceremony for Murdered Union Leader, But Blocks March</title>
        <guid>bf24e8f0-6ef9-4312-87d0-7738dcc3b04a</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/ceremony-01182019151725.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>Former CNRP members barred from politics may not take part, Cambodian authorities say.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 19:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/ceremony-01182019151725.html/khmer-cheakimny2-011819.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Chea Vichea's wife Chea Kimny speaks with RFA via Skype, Jan. 15, 2019.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[RFA]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Cambodian authorities this week gave permission for trade union members to commemorate the 2004 murder of their former president Chea Vichea, forbidding participants to march, however, and warning against the involvement of former opposition party members now banned from political life.<br/><br/>Chea Vichea, an outspoken critic of Prime Minister Hun Sen’s government and president of the Free Trade Union of Workers of the Kingdom of Cambodia (FTUWKC), was gunned down on Jan. 22, 2004 by an unknown assailant while he read a newspaper at a stand in Phnom Penh.<br/><br/>Two men were arrested within days of the murder with each handed 20-year jail sentences in a 2005 trial decried by rights groups as unjust. <br/><br/>The men, Sok Sam Oeun and Born Samnang, maintained they had been framed by police, and were finally acquitted in 2013 by Cambodia’s Supreme Court, which ruled they had been wrongfully convicted.<br/><br/>Writing in a Jan. 15 letter to FTUWKC president Touch Seu, Phnom Penh Municipality deputy governor Mean Chanyada denied permission for a requested march by 150 union members to the place where Chea Vichea was killed, allowing a brief ceremony to be held at the site instead.<br/><br/>However, former members of the now-dissolved opposition Cambodia National Rescue Party banned from active political life in Cambodia would not be permitted to take part, and the event itself should not be “politicized,” he said.<br/><br/>“In order for the event to go smoothly, and for reasons of security, City Hall asks the Union to cooperate with the authorities and not allow the 118 individuals who were banned from politics to participate in the event,” he said.<br/><br/>Speaking to RFA’s Khmer Service, FTUWKC vice president Mann Senghak said he would not block former CNRP officials from taking part in the commemoration, calling it a nonpolitical event and adding, “I don’t agree with the ban. These 118 people are Buddhists, and they have a right to pay their respects to Chea Vichea.”<br/><br/>CNRP members had joined in similar commemorations in the past, he said.<br/><strong><br/>Killers still not found</strong><br/><br/>Speaking to RFA from Finland where she has lived since her husband’s murder, Chea Vichea’s wife Chea Kimny called on Cambodia’s government to find and arrest her husband’s real killers.<br/><br/>“There has been no justice for me and my family for the last 15 years until now,” she said. “The government must try to arrest the real killers, but they haven’t been able to arrest any suspects, and I wonder why that is.”<br/><br/>Now grown, Chea Vichea’s daughter Chea Vicheata said that her father’s murder has made her stronger and more motivated to work hard at her studies.<br/><br/>“I want to use the knowledge that I’ve gained here to continue my father’s work to provide justice for the people,” she said.<br/><br/><i><strong>Reported by RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Samean Yun. Written in English by Richard Finney.</strong></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>activists, labor</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Court in China's Guangdong Jails Human Rights Lawyer For Five Years</title>
        <guid>ab896530-13a9-4b23-ba60-f4be3c02702e</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/lawyer-01182019120223.html</link>

	    
	         <category>China</category>
	    

        <description>Chen Wuquan is handed the sentence after helping local people protest against a planned land reclamation project.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 16:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/lawyer-01182019120223.html/china-chenwuquan3-011819.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Chen Wuquan protests against a reclamation project opposed by local residents in Zhenjiang in an undated photo.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Weiquanwang rights group website]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Authorities in the southern Chinese province of Guangdong have jailed a human rights lawyer for five years, RFA has learned.<br/><br/>Chen Wuquan was found guilty of "picking quarrels and stirring up trouble" by a court in Guangdong's Zhenjiang city and sentenced to five years' imprisonment.<br/><br/>Chen stood trial alongside six co-defendants on Dec. 25, 2018 at the Zhenjiang Economic and Technological Development Zone District People's Court, his wife Chen Lianjuan said.<br/><br/>His co-defendants were handed jail terms ranging from one year to 18 months in a sentencing decision handed down on Jan. 9, the Weiquanwang rights website reported.<br/><br/>"They allowed the family members of the defendants to sit in on the trial; three relatives per family," Chen's wife Chen Lianjuan said. "There was no verdict or sentence announced at the time."<br/><br/>"They just made recommendations for a sentence of 5-10 years," she said. "The court informed the lawyers on Jan. 15, and the lawyers told us to go and collect the judgment from the court."<br/><br/>Chen's jailing come after he helped residents of Zhenjiang's Donghai Island to protest against a reclamation project that damaged the offshore environment and affected their livelihoods.<br/><br/>Chen took part in shoreline protests with banners, and initiated an online petition against the project. He and six protesters were detained in February 2018.<br/><br/>Chen Lianjuan said her husband had done nothing wrong.<br/><br/>"Of course I think it's unfair," she said. "My husband was in the right, and tried to defend people's rights using legal means."<br/><strong><br/>License taken away</strong><br/><br/>Chen became involved in the protest after losing his license to practice law after offering legal assistance to members of the banned Falun Gong spiritual movement, which Beijing has designated an "evil cult."<br/><br/>Chen had also offered legal assistance to blind Shandong dissident Chen Guangcheng, who made a daring escape from house arrest before taking refuge in the U.S. Embassy in April 2012, and who now lives in the U.S.<br/><br/>China frequently withholds the licenses of lawyers who represent "sensitive" and disadvantaged groups, such as those who pursue complaints against official wrongdoing.<br/><br/>"He had already changed from a lawyer into a farmer," Chen Lianjuan said. "What kind of trouble would he cause after that?"<br/><br/>Guangdong lawyer Tan Yongpei, whose consultancy "club" for lawyers who lost their licenses was raided by police earlier this week, said Chen, a former police officer, had run for the post of village chief in local elections three years earlier, and narrowly lost.<br/><br/>"He won more than 40 percent of the votes, which is anathema to the [ruling] Chinese Communist Party," Tan said. "It would have been far worse if he had won."<br/><br/>"His opposition to the reclamation project was just an excuse," he said. "Chen Wuquan was a human rights attorney, highly educated, with an excellent knowledge of the law."<br/><br/>He said Chen had been given a harsh jail term in the hope that he wouldn't trouble the authorities for some time.<br/><br/>"They were afraid of a backlash if they only gave him one year; he is also a former cop, and a lawyer, and that's two things the authorities are afraid of," Tan said.<br/><br/>A nationwide police operation under the administration of President Xi Jinping has targeted more than 300 lawyers, law firms, and related activists for questioning, detention, imprisonment, debarring, and travel bans since it launched in July 2015.<br/><br/><i><strong>Reported by Gao Feng for RFA's Mandarin Service, and by the Cantonese Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</strong></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>rights lawyers, justice system, activists</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>North Koreans Struggle to Fulfill Daily Human Manure Quotas</title>
        <guid>218bb120-66ff-44bf-93a4-804eea3583c4</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/korea/nk-manure-quota-01162019142901.html</link>

	    
	         <category>North Korea</category>
	    

        <description>No relief for citizens who must either find 100 kg of feces a day or pay a fine.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 18:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/korea/nk-manure-quota-01162019142901.html/photo-1531966662811-c6501e46eda6.jfif" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[photo-1531966662811-c6501e46eda6]]></media:description>
                
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>The North Korean government has decreed that every able-bodied citizen must turn in 100 kg (220 lbs) of human manure a day to be used for fertilizer, to bolster the agricultural sector.</p>
<p>Leader Kim Jong Un announced in his New Year’s address that the agricultural front would be the primary instrument for economic reconstruction.</p>
<p>“After Kim Jong Un’s [speech], the entire population has been mobilized to produce manure as the first major task of the year,” a source in North Hamgyong province told RFA’s Korean Service on Sunday.</p>
<p>“The authorities in each local region task factories, institutions and citizens groups with assigning production quotas to each individual,” the source said.</p>
<p>“They are demanding that each person produce 100kg of human feces per day, or about 3 tons per month,” said the source.</p>
<p>“But how on earth can it be possible for one person to make 3 tons of human feces and deliver it?”</p>
<p>While the collection of feces is a yearly task, high quotas this year are driving many to find interesting ways to collect human feces in the bitter cold, or to find ways to get out of their quota.</p>
<p>Some however, are critical of the government, saying the high quotas amount to a shakedown of the people.</p>
<p>“If you cannot fill the quota, you have to supply 300kg of compost or livestock manure instead,” the source added.</p>
<p>“Most people can’t [make or collect] 100kg per day, so they end up giving what they think is sufficient. The quota is therefore meaningless,” said the source.</p>
<p>“[The quotas] are the same in both the cities and the countryside because the quotas are applied to everyone evenly,” said the source, adding “When the city’s clothing and food factories are [operating at full capacity], workers will try all sorts of ways to fill the quota.”</p>
<p><strong>Alternative measures</strong></p>
<p>“Compared with last year, there’s a growing number of residents who are choosing to pay cash instead of providing the manure itself,” said the source.</p>
<p>In addition to paying cash, citizens can buy manure from merchants.</p>
<p>“The manure merchants are doing really well these days, charging 20 yuan (about $3) per 100kg of human feces or 300kg of compost,” the source said.</p>
<p>“Young women who work in restaurants and beauty parlors usually just pay cash, though,” said the source.</p>
<p>Another source, also in North Hamgyong province, said on Monday, “The residents of Chongjin City have been fully mobilized to fulfil this task.”</p>
<p>“Authorities are encouraging people to produce more manure, stressing that it provides a vital boost to the agricultural front, and thereby the socialist movement in general,” the source said.</p>
<p>“People are becoming increasingly dissatisfied though, as authorities are keeping production records for each person and putting pressure on those who haven’t produced enough [to fill their quota.],” said the source.</p>
<p>“In winter, there isn’t as much manure and compost. Cash payments exceed the value of the manure that actually ends up being delivered, so people are saying the regime is just using the quota as a means to collect more money from the citizens,” the source said.</p>
<p>“More than 80% of all the female workers in Chongjin’s clothing factory pay cash instead of manure,” said the source.</p>
<p>“People are angry, criticizing the regime for [deliberately setting quotas so high] to force people to pay cash, then claiming it’s for agricultural production.”</p>
<p><strong><i>Reported by Jieun Kim for RFA’s Korean Service. Translated by Dukin Han. Written in English by Eugene Whong.</i></strong></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>agriculture</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>'Tang Jingling Would Have Fought For Vaccine Victims, But He's in Jail'</title>
        <guid>5143ee28-6bdf-4a36-918a-983bbf665a8d</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/wang-yanfang-vaccine-01182019115339.html</link>

	    
	         <category>China</category>
	    

        <description>Wang Yanfang, wife of a detained rights attorney, says people like her
husband are jailed instead of being praised for their work.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 16:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/wang-yanfang-vaccine-01182019115339.html/5cf68de6-bd29-4b84-a92d-dc62d0b65204.jpeg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[wang-yanfang]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[RFA]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Angry parents in the eastern Chinese province of Jiangsu clashed with officials and police last week, after 145 children got sick from expired vaccines.</p>
<p>The victims, who range in age from three months to four years, suffered fever, skin rashes, facial paralysis and deafness, among other symptoms.</p>
<p>Wang Yanfang, the U.S.-based wife of jailed human rights lawyer Tang Jingling, who once represented the victims of tainted and fake vaccines, said the problem hasn't gone away.</p>
<p>She added that there are fewer channels of redress for victims following a nationwide crackdown on rights lawyers since 2015.</p>
<p>“Such cases are very risky and impossible to win, and lawyers could lose their licenses if they take them on,” she said.</p>
<p>“Tang Jingling had been working on a case like that, but the cases failed to make the government take the problem of harmful vaccines seriously,” she said.</p>
<p>“There were no further investigations into those responsible,” said Wang, adding, “If the case had been rigorously investigated, then this incident wouldn't have happened today.”</p>
<p>“It is really ridiculous,” she said.<br/> <br/> “The help that a lawyer offers to their clients affects each family, including the health of the children; their lives and their safety,” said Wang, adding, “Under the law, we need people to carry out such duties. In a normal situation, they should win approval for doing these things.”<br/> <br/> “But progress on the rule of law has been reversed, and the people who break the law are getting more and more out of control,” she said.</p>
<p>“The issue of fake and tainted vaccines is getting more and more serious, and yet it's still the same people making those fake vaccines,” said Wang.<br/> <br/> “Instead of being regarded as a defender of the law, [my husband] has now become a person who violates the law,” she said.</p>
<p>“This society doesn't care about the law at all,” Wang said.</p>
<p>“Just as Tang Jingling said in court, the courts don't uphold the law, nor any kind of legal justice, because upholding justice and the law requires everyone to abide by it,” she said.<br/> <br/> “If Tang Jingling were still able to be a lawyer, he would have continued to fight for the victims of fake and tainted vaccines,” she said.</p>
<p>“But while another fake vaccine comes to light in Jiangsu, he is stuck in prison.”<br/> <br/><strong><i> Reported by C.K. for RFA's Mandarin Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</i></strong></p>
<div class="tableauPlaceholder" id="viz1548951948973" style="position: relative"><a href="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/wang-yanfang-vaccine-01182019115339.html/#"><img alt=" " src="https://public.tableau.com/static/images/Ac/Accident_22/Dashboard1/1_rss.png" style="border: none"/></a><object class="tableauViz" style="display:none;"><param name="host_url" value="https%3A%2F%2Fpublic.tableau.com%2F"> <param name="embed_code_version" value="3"> <param name="site_root" value=""><param name="name" value="Accident_22/Dashboard1"><param name="tabs" value="no"><param name="toolbar" value="yes"><param name="static_image" value="https://public.tableau.com/static/images/Ac/Accident_22/Dashboard1/1.png"> <param name="animate_transition" value="yes"><param name="display_static_image" value="yes"><param name="display_spinner" value="yes"><param name="display_overlay" value="yes"><param name="display_count" value="yes"></param></param></param></param></param></param></param></param></param></param></param></param></object></div> <script type="text/javascript">                    var divElement = document.getElementById('viz1548951948973');                    var vizElement = divElement.getElementsByTagName('object')[0];                    vizElement.style.minWidth='420px';vizElement.style.maxWidth='1050px';vizElement.style.width='100%';vizElement.style.minHeight='127px';vizElement.style.maxHeight='587px';vizElement.style.height=(divElement.offsetWidth*0.75)+'px';                    var scriptElement = document.createElement('script');                    scriptElement.src = 'https://public.tableau.com/javascripts/api/viz_v1.js';                    vizElement.parentNode.insertBefore(scriptElement, vizElement);                </script>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>dissident wife, women in the news</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Hong Kong Trade Unions Call For Release of Jasic Activists</title>
        <guid>3a65b5e9-d0c3-45fc-a1b8-c87a00a9327d</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/hong-kong-trade-unions-call-for-release-of-jasic-activists-01182019112732.html</link>

	    
	         <category>China</category>
	    

        <description>More than 30 Maoist activists, former Jasic workers, and NGO staff are being held, some on criminal charges, since a crackdown began last July.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 16:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/hong-kong-trade-unions-call-for-release-of-jasic-activists-01182019112732.html/china-labor-protesters-hong-kong-jan17-2019.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Members of the Hong Kong Confederation of Trade Unions stage a protest outside the Chinese Communist Party's liaison office in Hong Kong, demanding the release of people detained for campaigning for a labor union at Jasic Technology's factory in Shenzhen, Jan. 17, 2019.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[RFA]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    
		<media:group>

				
                        
  
    

	
		  <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H4IXlj4Hv30" medium="video" type="video/3gpp">
                <media:title>simple test</media:title>
          </media:content>

	 


  
 
  

  

		        

				
		</media:group>
	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>A trade union body in Hong Kong has called for the release of more than 30 former workers at a factory in neighboring Guangdong province and the Maoist labor activists who were supporting them.</p>
<p>The Hong Kong Confederation of Trade Unions (HKCTU) staged a protest outside the ruling Chinese Communist Party's liaison office in the city on Thursday, demanding the release of 34 people detained for campaigning for a labor union at Jasic Technology's factory in Shenzhen.</p>
<p>"Support the Jasic Workers - not guilty!" some 30 protesters shouted outside the Central Liaison Office in Hong Kong. "Condemn the shameless detentions!"</p>
<p>According to the Jasic Workers' Solidarity Group, a loose coalition of Maoist social activists, many of whom have also been involved in China's #MeToo feminist movement, former Jasic workers Mi Jiuping, Yu Juncong, Liu Penghua, and Li Zhan have been in criminal detention since the initial wave of arrests began in July.</p>
<p>Nongovernmental organization (NGO) workers Fu Changguo, Wang Xiaomei and He Xiumei and local trade union activists Zou Liping and Li Ao are also being held on criminal charges in Shenzhen.</p>
<p>Dozens more students and recent graduates of China's top universities have been "disappeared" or criminally detained since the nationwide crackdown on the Jasic labor movement made further waves of arrests and detentions in August, September and November, the JWSG reported on its Github page.</p>
<p>Among them are Sun Yat-sen University graduate and Jasic movement spokeswoman Shen Mengyu and Peking University #MeToo campaigner Yue Xin.</p>
<p>The HKFTU said it is "especially enraged" at the authorities' treatment of Fu Changguo and Zhang Zeying, wife of Li Zhan.</p>
<p>Zhang was detained on Jan. 2 for speaking out on social media about her husband's case, and the couple's newborn baby has been taken into state custody, it said.</p>
<p>Fu was denied permission to attend his mother's funeral last week, the organization said in a statement on its website.<br/><br/>"He was arrested merely because he shared news of the Jasic labor struggle on various [social media] groups with his friends and associates," the statement said.</p>
<p>"Such restrictions are blatant violations of their basic human and legal rights that transgress all humanitarian standards," it said.</p>
<p><strong>‘People as its enemy’</strong></p>
<p>HKFTU leader Lee Cheuk-yan said the body hopes to boost international support for the Jasic detainees.</p>
<p>"These workers and supporters exercised their basic and internationally recognized freedom of association," Lee said. "Any worker in the world has the right to organize independent trade unions without being subject to any interference or persecution, but the communist regime regards the people as its enemy."</p>
<p>Beijing-based activist and political commentator Zha Jianguo agreed, but added that the Communist Party under President Xi Jinping is less and less likely to allow anyone to organize.</p>
<p>"The Chinese government won't allow anyone to break free of the control of the Chinese Communist Party, not now, and not in the future," Zha said.</p>
<p>"Any actions that are outside the scope of party control will be suppressed by the Communist Party, and there will be more and more instances of this kind of suppression, without a doubt," he said.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Marxist and Maoist activists, many of them students, had flocked to Shenzhen to support the Jasic workers' cause, with some of them taking jobs in the factory.</p>
<p>However, dozens of members of the Jasic Workers' Solidarity Group (JWSG) were themselves detained in a mass raid on their temporary accommodation on Aug. 27.</p>
<p>The authorities responded with a clampdown on student activism on campus, banning Marxist study groups, and punishing students at Peking University, Renmin University and at universities in Nanjing.</p>
<p>In November, a rare protest on the campus of Nanjing University in the eastern province of Jiangsu over the authorities' banning of a Marxist study group sparked beatings by the authorities.</p>
<p>A similar fate has befallen the Marxism-Leninism Society at Peking University, while Cornell University recently withdrew from a partnership with Renmin University, citing the punishment of students who had supported the Shenzhen labor movement.</p>
<p><strong>No qualms about cracking down</strong></p>
<p>Wang Dan, a former leader of the 1989 pro-democracy movement on Tiananmen Square, who now heads the Dialogue China think tank in Washington, said the Chinese government has had no qualms about cracking down on anyone using Marxism or Maoism to organize in any way.</p>
<p>"The Marxist fundamentals that the students believe in emphasize the sacredness of labor and the equality of all people," Wang said in a recent interview with RFA.</p>
<p>"But ... Marxism has become the theory of using state violence to maintain a one-party dictatorship. This is the Marxism of the Chinese Communist Party under the leadership of Xi Jinping."</p>
<p>He said the emergence of a younger generation of politically and socially aware people has worried the government, because of the parallels with the student movements of the 1980s.</p>
<p>"The younger generation of college students have begun to care about social issues ... which will remind the Chinese authorities of the [protests] that took place 30 years ago," Wang said. "I think that's the main reason behind the crackdown on the students."</p>
<p><i><strong>Reported by Lee Wang-yam for RFA's Cantonese Service, and by Han Jie for the Mandarin Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</strong></i></p>
<p> </p>
<div class="flourish-embed"></div>
<script src="https://public.flourish.studio/resources/embed.js"></script>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>unions, activists, ngos, labor, factory, detentions, ccp, students, human rights</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>EU to Tax Cambodian, Myanmar Rice After Probe Finds Import Increases Hurt Local Producers</title>
        <guid>ba24d858-022a-4af5-84c9-a67138acd3db</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/rice-01172019171046.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>Imports from the two nations had nearly doubled in the past five years, while prices declined.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 22:48:46 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/rice-01172019171046.html/cambodia-rice-farmer-june-2018.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[A woman works at a rice seedling farm on the outskirts of Phnom Penh, Cambodia, June 22, 2018.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AP Photo]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>The European Union will impose a tax on rice from Cambodia and Myanmar for three years, beginning at the end of the week, after an investigation found that “a significant increase” in imports of the grain from the two countries “caused economic damage” to European producers.<br/><br/>Cambodia and Myanmar benefit from the EU’s Everything But Arms (EBA) trade scheme, which grants them, and other least developed nations, tax- and quota-free access to the bloc’s market.<br/><br/>But in a statement issued late on Wednesday, the European Commission said that as of Jan. 18, the EU will reinstate the normal customs duty on Indica rice from the two countries of 175 euros (U.S. $199) per ton in year one, following by a reduction to 150 euros (U.S. $170) in year two, and 125 euros (U.S. $142) in year three.<br/><br/>According to Commission, an investigation it launched in March last year found that Indica rice imports from both Cambodia and Myanmar had increased by 89 percent over the past five growing seasons, while prices remained lower than those on the EU market and actually decreased during the same period.<br/><br/>“This surge in low-price imports has caused serious difficulties for EU rice producers to the extent that their market share in the EU dropped substantially from 61 percent to 29 percent,” the Commission said.<br/><br/>The decision to reinstate duties on the rice imports was taken using a safeguards mechanism of the EU’s Generalised Scheme of Preferences (GSP) tariff-reduction scheme for developing countries, which the EBA is one pillar of.<br/><br/>The initial request for trade safeguards on rice imports was made by the Italian government in February last year, the Commission said, adding that the request had been backed by all other EU rice growing Member States—Spain, France, Portugal, Greece, Hungary, Romania and Bulgaria.<br/><br/><b>‘A positive development’</b><br/><br/>On Thursday, Cambodia’s Council of Ministers spokesman Phay Siphan told RFA’s Khmer Service that his government was unconcerned by the Commission’s announcement, adding that the rice tax would demonstrate that Cambodia is entirely capable of competing with other countries in international trade.<br/><br/>“Imposing a tax on Cambodia is a positive development, which proves that Cambodia is able to pay duties like other countries,” he said.<br/><br/>“We know that imposing the tax will affect us, but we must ready to compete on a level playing field with other countries in trade.”<br/><br/>Phay Siphan said that in order to cope with the new tax, Cambodia’s government will further develop the local market so that it will “be ready for any circumstances.”<br/><br/>He said that Cambodia will encourage exports to alternative markets, such as the Philippines, and will continue to rely on demand in China.<br/><br/>Last month, the Secretariat of One Window Service for Rice Export said Cambodia exported 497,240 tons of milled rice in the first 11 months of 2018, down 13 percent compared to the same period last year. It said China was the Southeast Asian nation’s top export market for rice, followed by France, the Netherlands, Poland and Britain.<br/><br/>Threatened EU trade sanctions are a politically sensitive topic in Cambodia, which banned the opposition Cambodia National Rescue Party (CNRP) and jailed its leader in 2017, paving the way for Prime Minister Hun Sen’s ruling Cambodian People’s Party (CPP) to win all 125 seats on offer in parliamentary elections in July 2018. <br/><br/>According to the European Commission, the EU ranked in 2017 as Cambodia’s second-largest trade partner, importing goods worth 5 billion euros (U.S. $5.8 billion) from the country.<br/><br/>Cambodia’s Ministry of the Interior on Wednesday arrested a CNRP activist after he posted a Facebook message saying the EU planned to impose a tariff on Cambodian rice, sources in the country said.<br/><br/>Theng Savoeun, secretariat coordinator of the Coalition of Cambodian Farmers Community, told RFA Thursday that Cambodia has no measures in place to protect farmers from the effects of an EU rice import tax, and urged the government to put aside a portion of the national budget to buy domestic rice.<br/><br/>“This issue is much like that of farmers losing their land [to government concessions], and we have seen that when the farmers lose their land, they protest,” he warned.<br/><br/><b>Tougher competition</b><br/><br/>Myanmar industry insiders told RFA’s Myanmar Service Thursday that the EU’s decision would have little impact on the country’s rice exports, which are already limited by a lack of infrastructure.<br/><br/>“This decision will not affect us very much on rice exports to Europe, but if it were on our garment exports, it would hurt,” said Hla Maung Shwe, deputy chairman of the Union of Myanmar Federation of Chambers of Commerce and Industry (UMFCCI).<br/><br/>The <i>Myanmar Times</i> also quoted Lu Maw Myint Maung, joint secretary of Myanmar Rice Federation, as saying that restoring EU tariffs on rice imports will affect the production of only 66,000 to 110,000 tons of Indica rice.<br/><br/>But Soe Tun of the Myanmar Rice Federation acknowledged to RFA that the decision will make it harder for Myanmar’s already small rice export industry to compete with other Asian rice producers.<br/><br/>“In the past, even though our rice was not of top quality, it was cheaper than others because of this preferential tax treatment,” he said.<br/><br/>“Now, if our rice is to be taxed, we will need to compete with other countries in our rice market, and our share of the market may become smaller.”<br/><br/>Yan Naing Tun, permanent secretary of the Myanmar’s Ministry of Commerce, told RFA Thursday that the government is “working on something in accordance with the regulations to buffer the impact” of the decision.<br/><br/>The EU is currently Myanmar’s sixth biggest trading partner, and total trade between the two nations was worth U.S. $2.38 billion in 2017. The EU imported goods worth U.S. $1.77 million from Myanmar and sent nearly U.S. $615 million to the Southeast Asian nation.<br/><br/>Myanmar exported more than 3.3 million tons of rice in the 2017-18 fiscal year.<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by Thiri Minzin for RFA’s Myanmar Service and by RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Khin Maung Nyane and Samean Yun. Written in English by Joshua Lipes.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>trade, rice, agriculture, farmers</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Bangladesh: 1,300 Rohingya Have Come from India Since Early December</title>
        <guid>5f297010-7b76-4d70-8d47-828bdbbfc9ad</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/myanmar/india-rohingya-01172019171828.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Myanmar</category>
	    

        <description>At least one pair of newcomers said they left India out of fear of being deported to Myanmar.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 22:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p style="text-align: left; "> </p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">

</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">The number of Rohingya arrivals from India has climbed sharply in recent weeks amid a crackdown on immigration by that country’s Hindu nationalist government, sources told BenarNews.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">“Some Rohingya have been coming from India since May 2018. The flow has increased recently and a total of about 1,300 have come from India since the first week of December,” Mohammad Abul Kalam, Bangladesh’s commissioner for Refugee Relief and Rehabilitation, told Benar. “They have been housed in a transitional refugee center at Ukhia in the Cox’s Bazar district under the supervision of UNHCR.”</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">
<iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UnKIrzVMFL4" width="560"></iframe>
</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">“They entered Bangladesh through different points of the porous border and have carried ID cards provided by the UNHCR in India,” he said, referring to the U.N. refugee agency.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">Some of the newcomers and advocates for refugees said Rohingya were making the long trek to southeastern Bangladesh from as far off as Indian Kashmir, fearing that India would deport them to Myanmar – as was the case with five Rohingya sent back there by Indian authorities on Jan. 3.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">A Rohingya husband and wife who led their five-member family from India to a camp in Teknaf, a sub-district of Cox’s Bazar, spoke to BenarNews about their journey.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">“We had fled Myanmar and took shelter in India 10 years ago. We had been living in Keraintela in Jammu-Kashmir in India,” said Nur Alam, the husband.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">“The Rohingya people in Kashmir became panicked as the Indian government recently arrested some of them and deported them to Myanmar. For this reason, many of the Rohingya are fleeing from India and entering into Bangladesh,” he said.</p>
<blockquote class="pullquote" style="text-align: left; ">Nur’s wife, Sanjda Begam, said her family did not want to return to Myanmar.</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: left; ">“Myanmar is not livable for us. We have learned that the Myanmar forces are engaged in a battle with the Arakan Army, so we cannot go there. Many other Rohingya are also trying to take shelter in Bangladesh from India,” she said.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; "><strong>Fears of expulsion</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left; "><strong><img alt="india-rohingya.jpg" class="image-inline" src="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/myanmar/india-rohingya-01172019171828.html/india-rohingya.jpg/@@images/b393bf6c-0102-4baf-ad9f-21fd15c001bb.jpeg" title="india-rohingya.jpg"/><br/></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">In India, the leader of a New Delhi-based NGO, the Rohingya Human Rights Initiative, said Rohingya feared the Indian government.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">“After five Rohingya who held refugee status were sent back recently, many with refugee status in India feel that they could all be sent back to Myanmar against their will,” Kyaw Min told BenarNews. “The reason for the flight to Bangladesh is fear.”</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">Sanjeev Verma, commissioner of the Jammu division in India’s Jammu and Kashmir state, said some Rohingya may have left their Indian shelters voluntarily.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">“If some families or members have left Jammu, it is not by force, it is by their own free will. They do not face any pressure from authorities to vacate their shelters,” he told BenarNews.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">In Guwahati, a city in northeast India’s Assam state, a border security official said no movement of refugees had been noted.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">“We maintain a 24-hour strict vigil,” said Border Security Force official who requested anonymity.<br/><br/>The refugees can travel through the Indian states of Assam, Tripura or West Bengal to reach Bangladesh, which shares borders with them.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">Abdul Motlob, a leader at the Leda refugee camp in Teknaf, said the Indian ID cards were issued for Rohingya who left the country.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">“We have come to know that the Indian government has been pressing the Rohingya to receive the new identity cards and the Rohingya are not interested,” he told BenarNews.  “It has become a new fear factor for them.”</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">For decades, Rohingya have faced persecution in Myanmar, which refuses to recognize them as citizens and falsely labels them as “Bengalis.”</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">Concentrated in Myanmar’s Rakhine state, they began fleeing in unprecedented numbers after the army launched a brutal offensive in August 2017. It followed deadly raids carried out against Myanmar government security posts there by Rohingya insurgents.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">During the exodus at least 720,000 Rohingya fled to southeastern Bangladesh to join about 300,000 already living in the camps.</p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>refugees, ethnic cleansing</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Lao Protest Villager Freed, 10 Still Held</title>
        <guid>e5b57fc7-aab4-4100-910a-776067d50a29</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/laos/freed-01172019171432.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Laos</category>
	    

        <description>The villager was one of a group detained for protesting the seizure of their land for use by a Vietnamese rubber company.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 22:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/laos/freed-01172019171432.html/laos-sekong-011719.JPG" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Yeub villagers in the Sekong province of Laos are shown in a 2012 photo.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[RFA]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Lao authorities have released a villager held since 2017 with a group arrested for protesting the loss of land awarded by the government to a Vietnamese rubber company, sources in the communist Southeast Asian state said.<br/><br/>Phonesawai, the fourth villager of the group to be released, was freed without official explanation on Jan. 6, a villager in Sekong province told RFA’s Lao Service, speaking on condition of anonymity. Three other villagers from the group were released in 2018, with another reported to have died in custody last year.<br/><br/>Ten others remain in detention.<br/><br/>In July 2017, 15 residents of Yeub village in Sekong’s Thateng district were detained by police for obstructing workers and cutting down trees on land granted by the government to a Vietnamese rubber company in what is believed to have been a 50-year concession.<br/><br/>Several of those now held in detention were beaten or subjected to electric shocks in the days following their arrest, and many are now malnourished and in failing health, relatives told RFA in earlier reports.<br/><br/>Speaking to RFA, Vanida Thepsouvanh—president of the Lao Movement for Human Rights, based in France—called the imprisonment of the group, including two minors, a “shocking example of arbitrary arrest and abuse of power in Laos, where too many Lao have become victims of investors.”<br/><br/>“Very sadly, it must not be forgotten that one of them died in custody,” Thepsouvanh said.<br/><br/>“I dare to hope that the person who was freed in January 2019 was not forced to sign a confession,” she said.<br/><br/>Also speaking to RFA, Andrea Giorgetta—head of the Asia desk for the Paris-based International Federation for Human rights—called the detention of the Yeub villagers “unjustified, arbitrary, and illegal.”<br/><br/>“Whatever crimes they were charged with did not justify a pre-trial detention that was extremely long. And as far as I understand, none of them has been put on trial yet,” he said.<br/><br/>“But still, they’ve been detained for more than six months, which is contrary even to the criminal procedure code of Laos.”<br/><br/>Reached by RFA’s Lao Service, Solaseumsak Phongsanouvong—vice head of Sekong province’s prosecution office—declined to comment on the case.<br/><br/>Land grabs and the appropriation of public property to turn over to foreign and domestic companies are common in Laos, and villagers affected by them often refuse to speak out publicly because they fear retribution.<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by RFA’s Lao Service. Translated by Ounkeo Souksavanh. Written in English by Richard Finney.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>detentions, land dispute, land grab</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Displaced Residents in Vietnam’s Ho Chi Minh City Brushed Aside by Government</title>
        <guid>57a8c381-631f-4a47-98e6-cc3dc6579206</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/vietnam/loc-hung-vietnam-eviction-petition-01172019165826.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Vietnam</category>
	    

        <description>Victims of forced eviction in the Loc Hung community sent a petition to three government offices but were rejected by two.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 22:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/vietnam/loc-hung-vietnam-eviction-petition-01172019165826.html/loc-hung-evictees.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[loc-hung-evictees]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Tin Mừng Cho Người Nghèo via Facebook]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>About 100 people who were suddenly evicted as a result of the demolitions that took place in Vietnam’s Ho Chi Minh City in a two-day operation on Jan. 4 and Jan. 8 have gone to the offices of the city government, the Communist Party of Vietnam (CPV) and the national assembly to submit a petition pleading their case.</p>
<p>Authorities demolished at least 112 houses in a parcel of land claimed by the Catholic Church, where they had lived. Among the displaced residents of the Tan Binh district’s Loc Hung Vegetable Garden settlement are political dissidents and veterans of the former Army of South Vietnam, sources say.</p>
<p>Their petition was refused by the city’s CPV office and the national assembly office.</p>
<p>“We went to the city’s people’s committee office and they took our petition,” said Cao Ha Thanh to RFA’s Vietnamese Service over the phone on Thursday evening.</p>
<p>Cao had visited the three offices earlier in the day.</p>
<p>“We went there many times over the past few decades to ask for our rights to the land, and they had never answered our previous demands,” said Cao.</p>
<p>Cao said that after visiting the national assembly office, one official came to meet them to say there was not anything the government could do on their behalf.</p>
<p>“We [then] went to the party’s office but when we got closer to the building, they closed the gate. I tried to tell them about our situation but they refused to take our petition,” said Cao.</p>
<p>RFA attempted to contact the three offices by telephone. The national assembly office answered, but refused to answer questions over the phone.</p>
<p>Residents of the community posted the petition in a Facebook group they set up saying that more than 100 families had signed it. The petition says that they were affected directly and have suffered losses as a result of the forced evictions.</p>
<p>In the petition they asked relevant officials of the three offices to uphold their rights, demanded that Tan Binh district authorities stop illegal evictions, and demanded transparency and proper compensation for their losses.</p>
<p>State media on Thursday quoted a letter sent from Vietnam’s Ministry of Natural Resources to their city-level counterpart in Ho Chi Minh as saying that the residents were only borrowing the land to cultivate vegetables, so they have no land rights, and are therefore not entitled to compensation.</p>
<p>Officials from Tan Binh district on Sunday told state media they offered about 7 million Vietnamese dong (about $300) per square meter of land and 4-6 million dong (about $170-$260) per month for a period of three months to those families who lost their vegetables as a result of the eviction.</p>
<p>The Sai Gon Giai Phong newspaper reported on Tuesday that 30 of the families of Loc Hung had received this support.</p>
<p>While all land in Vietnam is ultimately held by the state, land confiscations have become a flashpoint as residents accuse the government of pushing small landowners aside in favor of lucrative real estate projects, and of paying too little in compensation to those whose land is taken.</p>
<p><strong><i>Reported by RFA’s Vietnamese Service. Translated by Viet Ha. Written in English by Eugene Whong.</i></strong></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>eviction, land grab</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Myanmar Has Returned More Than 1,700 Child Soldiers Home to Date, Defense Ministry Official Says</title>
        <guid>16d98ca7-7982-40f9-9bcc-177240d0b043</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/myanmar/myanmar-has-returned-more-than-1700-child-soldiers-01172019164747.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Myanmar</category>
	    

        <description>Those guilty of recruiting or deploying children are being demoted and sent to military or civilian prisons.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 21:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/myanmar/myanmar-has-returned-more-than-1700-child-soldiers-01172019164747.html/myanmar-colonel-tun-tun-win-defense-ministry-naypyidaw-jan17-2019.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Colonel Tun Tun Win of Myanmar's Ministry of Defense speaks at a workshop on the creation of a complaint mechanism to report instances of forced labor, in Naypyidaw, Jan. 17, 2019.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[RFA]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>More than 1,700 child soldiers in Myanmar have been reunited with their parents, and about 800 military officers and other army personnel who recruited and used them have been punished, a defense ministry official said Thursday during a workshop in Naypyidaw to discuss the creation of a complaint mechanism to report instances of forced labor.</p>
<p>Colonel Tun Tun Win of the Ministry of Defense said that the army has taken action against the use of child soldiers in Myanmar based on regulations of the International Labour Organization (ILO), a United Nations agency that sets global labor standards and promotes social protection for workers.</p>
<p>“In response to the ILO’s regulations, the Tatmadaw [Myanmar military] has taken action from 2007 to 2018 against a total of 379 military personnel, including 64 officers and 315 other ranks in accordance with military discipline,” he said.</p>
<p>At the same time, the U.N. Country Task Force on Monitoring and Reporting (CTFMR), co-chaired by June Kunugi, UNICEF’s representative to Myanmar, and Knut Ostby, the U.N.’s highest representative and humanitarian coordinator in Myanmar, to report on grave violations committed against children during times of armed conflict, has taken action against 448 military personnel, including 96 officers and 352 other ranks, he said.</p>
<p>The punishments included sending military personnel to both civilian and army jails as well as demotions, Tun Tun Win said.</p>
<p>Besides sending nearly 1,730 child soldiers home, the army is addressing the issue in a transparent manner, he said.</p>
<p>Saw Tin Win, a lawmaker who is a member of the Farmers and Workers Affairs Committee in Myanmar’s lower house of parliament, said his committee receives about 40 complaints about the military’s use of child soldiers every month, though only two or three have been returned.</p>
<p>“Some underage children were allowed to resign from the service, while other cases remain under investigation,” he said. “And some children were not allowed to resign during their recruitment period.”</p>
<p>He also said that the committee had gathered evidence of underage children being used as child soldiers and then sent complaint letters to the defense ministry.</p>
<p>Thein Swe, Myanmar’s minister for labor, immigration, and population said that the Myanmar military is cooperating with both the CTFMR and the ILO on the child soldier issue.</p>
<p>“It also has taken action if complaints were submitted under the Supplementary Understanding agreement,” he said.</p>
<p>The February 2007 agreement between the Myanmar government and the ILO provides for a complaint mechanism under which individuals can submit cases of forced labor under the ILO Convention 29 concerning forced labor, and including underage recruitment, to the ILO liaison officer in Yangon.</p>
<p>“For instance, if the Tatmadaw cooperated on the issue of child soldier recruitment, then it took action against those who recruit underage children and notified us once the issue had been resolved,” Thein Swe said.</p>
<p>He also said that the ministry would address the issue of forced labor by ethnic armed groups in Myanmar, but did not elaborate.</p>
<p><b>Widespread use of child soldiers</b></p>
<p>The use of child soldiers in Myanmar has been widespread since the country’s independence from colonial ruler Britain in 1948. For decades, the national military has engaged in hostilities with several ethnic armies fighting for varying degrees of autonomy in their states.</p>
<p>Some of the ethnic armies that are fighting against Myanmar forces, and some of the forces allied with them, also have recruited and used child soldiers, though the numbers have been much lower than those recruited and used by the Myanmar military.</p>
<p>In 2007, Myanmar and the U.N. began negotiations on ending the use child soldiers that culminated in a joint action plan in June 2012 to stop the recruitment and use of children by the armed  forces.</p>
<p>Three years later, Myanmar signed the Optional Protocol to the Convention on the Rights of Child on the Involvement of Children in Armed Conflict (OPAC), also known as the international child soldier treaty, but has yet to ratify it to make it fully binding.</p>
<p>In 2017, the country signed the Paris Principles and Commitments to protect children from unlawful recruitment or use by armed forces and groups and to reintegrate those who have been associated with armed forces into civilian life.</p>
<p>In September 2018, the Myanmar government released 75 children and young people who were recruited and used by the military in the only discharge to take place last year.</p>
<p><i><b>Reported by Win Ko Ko Latt for RFA’s Myanmar Service. Translated by Nandar Chann. Written in English by Roseanne Gerin.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>children, child soldiers, military, ethnic armies, ilo, unicef, un, labor</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Myanmar Military Claims to Have Seized Rebel Camp in War-Torn Rakhine State</title>
        <guid>a7cef335-3b66-40f4-8345-a95a20f576f0</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/myanmar/myanmar-military-claims-to-have-seized-rebel-camp-01172019162458.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Myanmar</category>
	    

        <description>The Arakan Army denies that government soldiers captured one of its camps, calling the announcement ‘fake news.’</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 21:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/myanmar/myanmar-army-accused-of-detaining-civilians-12272018163746.html/myanmar-arakan-army-troops-undated-photo.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Arakan Army soldiers pass through a field in western Myanmar's Rakhine state in an undated photo.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Photo courtesy of Arakan Army News and Information]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>The Myanmar military said Thursday that it seized an Arakan Army temporary camp in Rakhine state’s Buthidaung township a day earlier, where it found five dead bodies and weapons amid ongoing hostilities with the rebel forces in the region.</p>
<p>When government troops seized the camp in Thayet Pyin village, they also found two rifles and other weapons, according to a statement issued Wednesday by the military Commander-in-Chief’s Office.</p>
<p>Colonel Win Zaw Oo from the government army's Western Military Command, which oversees operations in Rakhine state, told RFA’s Myanmar Service that soldiers took hold of the camp while performing clearance operations in the region, where fighting flared up last month.</p>
<p>“The AA’s strategy is to start the fighting near villages,” he said. “We assume that the AA is doing it on purpose to create instability in the region and to make people worried and live in fear.”</p>
<p>Myanmar forces also engaged in a firefight with about 50 AA soldiers, the statement said.</p>
<p>No one from the Myanmar side was injured, it said.</p>
<p>The AA, however, denied that the reported fighting occurred and that Myanmar forces had captured one of its camps.</p>
<p>“It is not true that government army got our post,” said AA spokesman Khine Thukha. “There wasn't any fighting between us and them on Jan. 16. The government military creates this fake news to cover what it really does.”</p>
<p>When RFA called Buthidaung lawmakers and locals in the region to comment on the latest clash, they said they were not aware of it.</p>
<p>The national army said it will continue clearance operations against AA for regional security purposes.</p>
<p>Fighting between the two sides has escalated in Rakhine state since early December, displacing an estimated 6,000 civilians, some of whom have limited or no access to food supplies due to restrictions put in place by Myanmar military authorities to supposedly stop food from reaching the insurgents.</p>
<p>Clashes in northern Rakhine state intensified after Jan. 4 when the AA, which is fighting for greater autonomy in the state, attacked four police outposts in the region, killing 13 policemen and wounding nine others.</p>
<p><b>Aid group wants access to Rakhine</b></p>
<p>Geneva-based Doctors Without Borders (MSF) asked the Myanmar government on Thursday to allow the relief organization to help displaced civilians who need emergency assistance.</p>
<p>MSF said in a statement that its members are ready in Sittwe and Maungdaw township to help displaced people, and that it has asked the Ministry of Health and Sports to allow them to provide health care for them.</p>
<p>The organization also asked the ministry to allow aid to flow to displaced people in Rakhine state, though the government said that depends upon other agencies as well.</p>
<p>Than Htun Aung, the ministry’s deputy director, said he had not yet received an official request from MSF, but that cooperation from the Rakhine state government would be needed.</p>
<p>In 2017, the Myanmar government turned down a request by MSF to allow it to provide health care in Rakhine state following deadly attacks by the Muslim militant group the Arakan Rohingya Salvation Army (ARSA) that sparked a brutal crackdown on Rohingya communities that drove more than 725,000 members of the minority group to neighboring Bangladesh.</p>
<p>In addition to MSF’s call, the All-Rakhine Unity Committee, a political and social organization in Rakhine state, has demanded that the government grant access to aid groups to help displaced civilians in war-ravaged areas.</p>
<p>The committee also urged the government and military not to block aid to displaced residents and called on them to make plans for organizations or individuals who want to help them.</p>
<p>During a meeting on Wednesday at the headquarters of the Arakan National Party (ANP) in Sittwe, the committee also denounced comments last week by government spokesman Zaw Htay claiming that the AA has links to ARSA, and called on Rakhine residents to stop supporting the insurgent group.</p>
<p>Zaw Zaw Tun, chairman of Rakhine Nationalities Union, which is a committee member, told RFA that his group would like to urge the government to make remarks or issue statements pertaining to the state only after it examines them from different perspectives.</p>
<p>The group’s statement also said that the exclusion of Rakhine state from a temporary unilateral cease-fire that the Myanmar military declared in five military regions in December to try to revive the country's shaky peace process has complicated the situation in the state. The committee urged the military to end the hostilities and engage in discussions with the AA.</p>
<p><b>Call for independent Kachin state</b></p>
<p>In Myanmar’s war-torn Kachin state, where the government military has been battling the Kachin Independence Army (KIA) but which is now under the temporary cease-fire, local civil society organizations, cultural groups, and religious leaders have expressed a willingness to establish an independent Kachin state.</p>
<p>A statement the groups issued following a three-day conference in Chiang Mai, Thailand, indicated that a peaceful solution will be sought to establish an independent state, in consultation with all ethnic groups in the region as well as government officials, said Naw Lat, one of the organizers of the ethnic Kachin conference.</p>
<p>He said the Myanmar government should not regard the statement as a problem and urged officials to pay serious attention to the call by the Kachin public and to hold talk with relevant organizations.</p>
<p>Naw Lat also said that the conference concluded that sovereignty of Kachin state lies solely in the hands of the Kachin people and that attendees have pledged to protect the interests of the ethnic minority group.</p>
<p><i><b>Reported by Kyaw Thu, Thet Su Aung, and Kyaw Tun Naing. Translated by Khet Mar and Nandar Chann. Written in English by Roseanne Gerin.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>arakan, rakhine, military, ethnic armies, msf, ngos, kachin</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Chinese Mark Passing of Late, Ousted Liberal Premier Amid Tight Security</title>
        <guid>eb70810a-1f45-4acb-960c-2d5364b31ab5</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/zhao-anniversary-01172019160502.html</link>

	    
	         <category>China</category>
	    

        <description>Well-wishers and supporters of late premier Zhao Ziyang are detained as they try to pay their respects at his family home in Beijing.
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 21:19:14 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/zhao-anniversary-01172019160502.html/image.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[A memorial to Chinese Premier Zhao Ziyang, who was ousted for sympathising with the student-led mass protests in 1989, on the 14th anniversary of his death under house arrest, Jan. 17, 2019.

]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Photo courtesy of an RFA listener.]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Almost three decades after the Tiananmen massacre ended the 1989</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> democracy movement and froze political reform in China, Beijing police on</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "><span> </span></span><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3966_com_zimbra_date" style="text-align: start; "><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3973_com_zimbra_date">Thursday</span></span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "><span> </span></span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">stepped up security on</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> the anniversary of the death of premier Zhao Ziyang, ousted for</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> sympathising with the student-led mass protests.</span><br style="text-align: start; "/><br style="text-align: start; "/><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Fourteen years after his death under house arrest imposed following</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> his fall from power, Zhao's family have repeatedly called for his</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> posthumous rehabilitation, and for his remains to be laid to rest.</span><br style="text-align: start; "/><br style="text-align: start; "/><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Yet there was a strong police presence outside Zhao's family home on</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Beijing's Fuqiang Alley, and many who had wanted to pay their respects</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> at the home and write in the family condolence book, were unable to do</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> so.</span><br style="text-align: start; "/><br style="text-align: start; "/><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"There were ... some people who couldn't make it, for example, the</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Tiananmen Mothers, so they sent wreaths and so on using florists,"</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Zhao's son-in-law Wang Zhihua told RFA, in a reference to a campaign</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> group for the families of those who died when the People's Liberation</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Army (PLA) used tanks and machine guns to clear the capital of</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> protesters and hunger strikers on the night of</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "><span> </span></span><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3967_com_zimbra_date" style="text-align: start; "><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3974_com_zimbra_date">June 3</span></span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">, 1989.</span><br style="text-align: start; "/><br style="text-align: start; "/><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"I don't know why security is so tight this year ... nobody's going to</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> explain the reason to us, so there's not much point in thinking about</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> it," he said. "The best history is that which is written by the</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> people."</span><br style="text-align: start; "/><br style="text-align: start; "/><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Veteran political journalist Gao Yu said via her Twitter account that</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> she had been warned not to go to Zhao's house to pay her respects, and</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> that she had been detained as she set out to mark the anniversary of</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> his death privately on</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "><span> </span></span><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3968_com_zimbra_date" style="text-align: start; "><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3975_com_zimbra_date">Wednesday</span></span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "><span> </span></span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">with a few friends.</span><br style="text-align: start; "/><br style="text-align: start; "/><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Beijing-based housing rights activist Ni Yulan said she was unable to</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> attend, as she was under police surveillance at her home.</span><br style="text-align: start; "/><br style="text-align: start; "/><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"I saw that a few petitioners went</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "><span> </span></span><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3969_com_zimbra_date" style="text-align: start; "><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3976_com_zimbra_date">today</span></span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">," Ni said. "They reported</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> back that they were detained and taken down to the local police</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> station."</span><br style="text-align: start; "/><br style="text-align: start; "/><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"Security was very tight</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "><span> </span></span><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3970_com_zimbra_date" style="text-align: start; "><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3977_com_zimbra_date">today</span></span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">, and there were many times more</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> officers than previously, with police vehicles everywhere," she said.</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> "There were also plainclothes [state security] police."</span><br style="text-align: start; "/><br style="text-align: start; "/><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Zhao's daughter Wang Yanan said the ruling Chinese Communist Party has</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> yet to approve the family's application for a burial plot for Zhao, a</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> liberal-minded and well-loved leader who rose to the top of the ruling</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> party at the 13th Party Congress in 1987.</span><br style="text-align: start; "/><br style="text-align: start; "/><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"There are reasons for that; chief among them is the overall political</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> climate," Wang Yanan said. "The government has its own concerns, and</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> we have ours."</span><br style="text-align: start; "/><br style="text-align: start; "/><b><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">2019 brings sensitive anniversaries</span></b></p>
<p><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">But she said she still hopes for her father's good name to be</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> restored. Zhao's name rarely appears in the official record, although</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> he has a loyal following of former officials seeking to rehabilitate</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> him as a figurehead of the reform era that began in 1979.</span><br style="text-align: start; "/><br style="text-align: start; "/><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"I always have some kind of hope or confidence that this will happen,"</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> she said. "But reality is another matter."</span><br style="text-align: start; "/><br style="text-align: start; "/><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">In a conclusive break with the reformist thinking of the 1980s,</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> China's current supreme leader Xi Jinping is now serving an indefinite</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> term as president following constitutional changes nodded through in</span><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3971_com_zimbra_date" style="text-align: start; "><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3978_com_zimbra_date"> March 2018</span></span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "><span> </span></span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">by China's rubber-stamp parliament, the National People's</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Congress (NPC).</span><br style="text-align: start; "/><br style="text-align: start; "/><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Beijing-based constitutional affairs scholar Yu Meisun, who served as</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> a top aide in China's cabinet, the State Council, during the 1980s,</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> said Zhao had been very keen on the rule of law.</span><br style="text-align: start; "/><br style="text-align: start; "/><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"He led us during the 1980s, and I think he did some very meaningful</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> work," Yu said. "Zhao Ziyang set great store by economic legislation,</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> by legal measures, as a way of ensuring the smooth progress of reform</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> and opening up."</span><br style="text-align: start; "/><br style="text-align: start; "/><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"He was very enlightened, and had researched reforms and opening up in</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> great depth."</span><br style="text-align: start; "/><br style="text-align: start; "/><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Beijing rights activist Hu Jia said the additional security likely</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> came ahead of the 30th anniversary of the Tiananmen crackdown.</span><br style="text-align: start; "/><br style="text-align: start; "/><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"This is an important point in history, coinciding as it does with the</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> 70th anniversary of Communist Party rule," Hu said. "Xi Jinping can't</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> afford there to be unrest of any kind, especially not linked to June</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> 4, as it proves the illegitimacy of Communist Party rule."</span><br style="text-align: start; "/><br style="text-align: start; "/><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"That's why he has to eliminate this sort of thing to the greatest</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> extent possible," he said.</span><br style="text-align: start; "/><br style="text-align: start; "/><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Author Ma Bo agreed.</span><br style="text-align: start; "/><br style="text-align: start; "/><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"They are probably afraid ... so they step up controls on ordinary</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> people," he said, adding that calls on the Chinese leadership to</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> overturn the historical verdict of "counterrevolutionary rebellion" on</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> the 1989 democracy movement were unlikely to be heeded.</span><br style="text-align: start; "/><br style="text-align: start; "/><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"They're never going to reappraise it," Ma said. "You're not even</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> allowed to talk about it. They only have one position, and that is</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> that the Communist Party's grip on power must be maintained as a</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> one-party dictatorship."</span><br style="text-align: start; "/><br style="text-align: start; "/><i><b><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Reported by Ng Yik-tung and Sing Man for RFA's Cantonese Service, and</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> by Gao Feng for the Mandarin Service. Translated and edited by</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Luisetta Mudie.</span></b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>politics, history, repression</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Villagers in Laos Fearful of New Chinese Tourism Project</title>
        <guid>fb557207-5d06-46e9-8216-0926ee04f923</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/laos/vang-vieng-tourism-china-01172019153139.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Laos</category>
	    

        <description>Rural citizens of Vientiane’s Vang Vieng district pre-emptively refuse to sell for a Chinese tourism project that might encroach on their land.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 20:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/laos/vang-vieng-tourism-china-01172019153139.html/laos-china-casino.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[laos-china-casino]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Villagers in the remote Lao hamlet of Huaiyae in the scenic Vang Vieng region north of the capital Vientiane are concerned about possibly losing their land to a Chinese development project, after local authorities were spotted in the town taking measurements and noting the locations of trees.</p>
<p>Vientiane provincial authorities have confirmed there is a Chinese firm looking to develop the Vang Vieng district area in which Huaiyae sits, but they say that land belonging to locals won’t be touched. Villagers are, however, skeptical.</p>
<p>“We saw [them] come into our village and take notes about trees,” said a Huaiyae resident in an interview with RFA’s Lao Service.</p>
<p>“We will not give up our land. Where [else] are we going to live?” the resident said, adding, “We will let them take as many notes as they want, but we will not give up our land!”</p>
<p>Vang Vieng has long been a draw for Western backpackers and other tourists drawn by its spectacular limestone scenery, rivers and rural charm. Lying on the route of a planned Lao-China railroad it is also potential magnet for Chinese visitors.</p>
<p>Last year, the Lao-Vang Vieng New Area Development Company, signed a memorandum of understanding (MOU) with Laos, for what's described as a sustainable tourism project. It will reportedly run in three phases over 15 years at a cost of U.S. $5.5 billion. That could create thousands of jobs but it is unclear how many of those jobs will go to Lao villagers.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Vientiane province has granted another Chinese company permission to survey the area of a former airport in Vang Vieng for construction of an entertainment complex, including a shopping mall, hotels, and other structures on 15 hectares of land at a cost of U.S. $200 million, sources say.</p>
<p>In Huaiyae, the Chinese investment plans have generated more anxiety than hope.</p>
<p>The villager said that in addition to the notes about trees, the authorities measured the size of their houses.</p>
<p>“Nobody has agreed to sign any documents,” the villager said.</p>
<p>Another villager seemingly contradicted this claim, saying that some of the people in the village did sign documents.</p>
<p>“The family next to my house signed, but I did not,” the second villager said.</p>
<p>“I let [them] measure my house, but wouldn’t sign the document they presented to me,” said the villager.</p>
<p>“Most people don’t like [the idea of] the area being developed by this Chinese investor.”</p>
<p>A third villager explained that if they are ever forced to sell their land for the project, they won’t be properly compensated.</p>
<p>“Many people will be angry if the project actually starts, because compensation for their land will be based on estimates made by the state,” said the third villager.</p>
<p>“My plot of land has a current market value worth about $220,000, but the state will say it is worth much less than that.</p>
<p>AVientiane provincial official who requested not to be named confirmed to RFA that a Chinese-owned firm is interested in developing the area of the western bank of the Xong River in Vang Vieng as a new tourism project.</p>
<p>“They are still in an 18-month survey period, but it is still unclear what they really want to do,” the official said.</p>
<p>“They will make a tourism development that includes the participation of the local people,” said the official.</p>
<p>The area said to be under survey comprises 32 villages. Local residents say that district authorities have suspended the issuance of land titles to people who own land along the Kuang River since the end of 2017, as well as prohibiting development within the area without permission.</p>
<p>The citizens of at least 11 villages including Huaiyae have made a pact not to sign any documents from land authorities.</p>
<p>They have also asked the provincial and central governments to carefully review any impact the project might have on the local people and the environment in the long term.</p>
<p>The villagers say that tourism has already been harmful to the environment in their region and they fear that the natural resources upon which local livelihoods depend will be exploited to generate income for others in unsustainable ways.</p>
<p>As one of the least developed Southeast Asian nations, Laos has become a target for massive foreign investment, especially from companies from neighbors China, Thailand, and Vietnam, which receive attractive investment incentives from the Lao government.</p>
<p><b><i>Reported and translated by Phouyong for RFA’s Lao Service. Written in English by Eugene Whong.</i></b></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>land grab, eviction</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Philippine Defense Chief Eyes Subic Bay Amid Chinese Takeover Fears</title>
        <guid>688ad395-e8ed-4e35-afaf-1f1d2295dcb6</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/philippines-subic-01172019143650.html</link>

	    
	         <category>China</category>
	    

        <description>Subic Bay was home to a sprawling U.S. navy base during the Cold War.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 19:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/philippines-subic-01172019143650.html/phils-subic.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[The USS Boxer, an American navy ship, arrives at Subic Bay, northern Philippines, ahead of a bilateral military exercise with Filipino troops, Sept. 16, 2013.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p style="text-align: left; ">Philippines authorities should take over a major shipyard that sits on the site of a former U.S. navy base, or risk letting it fall into the hands of the Chinese who could use it as a regional foothold amid contentious South China Sea claims, Filipino officials said Thursday.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">Defense Secretary Delfin Lorenzana said he had met with President Rodrigo Duterte and other officials on Wednesday, including Foreign Secretary Teodoro Locsin, to discuss ways for the Philippines to take over the facility in Subic Bay from its failing South Korean operator and keep it in local hands.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">A state-run company is among two Chinese firms that have expressed interest in taking over the shipyard after South Korea’s Hanjin Heavy Industries and Construction filed for bankruptcy last week, according to local media reports.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">Manila was also studying the prospect of offering the shipyard operations to players from the United States, Australia, South Korea and Japan – countries that are all considered as allies by the Philippines, the defense chief said.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">“The Philippine Navy suggested that ‘why not the Philippines take over so that we’ll have a naval base there? Then we’ll have ship-building capabilities,’” Lorenzana said during an annual event in Manila of the Foreign Correspondents’ Association of the Philippines.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">He said Manila was looking to purchase more ships in the next decade, and it would be advantageous for it to have the shipyard under its control.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">“The most critical external security challenge for the Philippines is the territorial and maritime claims in the South China Sea,” Lorenzana said. “Compounding the issue is the backdrop of a rapidly evolving regional environment, where the United States-China geopolitical rivalry is deepening and a potential Taiwan Strait conflict is brewing.”</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">He noted that Washington remained the Philippines’ “only treaty ally” despite Duterte’s military pivot to China since he became president in mid-2016.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">“China, our big, next door neighbor, has occupied and militarized some features closer to our shores,” the defense secretary said. “We have not, and we will not, surrender any part of our territory.”</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">However, a “constructive approach” was needed to engage China in the future, he said.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">“The goal is to pursue functional cooperation with China and with other claimant countries,” Lorenzana said, adding that a 2016 international arbitration tribunal ruling in favor of Manila was “valid and legitimate.”</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">U.S. officials were not immediately available to comment on the news around Subic Bay.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; "><b>A ‘very significant national security issue’</b></p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">Philippines defense sources, meanwhile, have said that Beijing may seek to gain control of Subic, a strategic former naval base to use it as a monitoring post.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">Former Philippine navy chief Alexander Pama, in particular, warned that Subic was a “very significant national security issue” beyond business matters.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">“The ownership of the shipyard in Subic will give owners unlimited access to one of our most strategic geographic Naval and maritime asset,” Pama said, according to the Philippine Inquirer.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">He noted that while the shipyard would remain a commercial interest on paper, “nothing can prevent the owners from making it into a de facto naval base.”</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">Filipino Sen. Richard Gordon, who was once the mayor of the town where Subic is located, on Thursday also proposed that the government enter into a deal with local businessmen and some unidentified South Korean investors in a bid to take over the Hanjin operations.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">He said the shipyard was “a very important” logistical and engineering resource that the country should control.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">“We should take over the shipyard if needed. The important thing here is that the Philippines will be able to make its own ships,” said Gordon, who met with Lorenzana and other senators on Wednesday.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">Gordon said the Philippine Navy should have its headquarters inside the shipyard, on Luzon’s western side facing the South China Sea.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">Subic, along with the nearby Clark Air Base, used to host one of the largest U.S. military facilities outside of the mainland United States. The bases were key staging points during the Vietnam War.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">At the end of the Cold War, the last U.S. military ship sailed out of Subic in 1992 after a nationalist Philippine Senate voted then to end a lease agreement, which allowed the Americans to operate in the area for years.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">Last week, Hanjin Philippines, the local unit of South Korea’s Hanjin Heavy Industries and Construction, filed for rehabilitation after it defaulted on some U.S. $400 million in loans, reports said. The firm also owed about $900 million to creditors in South Korea.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">Two unnamed major Chinese shipbuilders have expressed interest in taking over the failed shipyard in Subic, which would effectively allow Beijing to gain a strategic foothold into the Philippines, its territorial rival in the South China Sea, critics said.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">Supreme Court Justice Antonio Carpio, who was part of the Philippine legal team that argued the arbitration case in 2016, warned that China was moving to occupy areas, even including shorelines.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">“The intention of China is very clear. They want to control the West Philippine Sea,” Carpio said, using the Philippines name for the South China Sea. He said Beijing was still intent on “grabbing” Manila’s exclusive economic zone, despite international condemnation.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">Allowing Beijing to gain a toehold into Subic could give the Chinese an edge in pressing their territorial claims in the disputed sea region, said Carpio who had publicly opposed Duterte’s pro-China stance.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">“Why would we allow the Chinese to get a foothold in Subic when they are trying to seize the West Philippine Sea just across?” he said. “It doesn’t make sense.”</p>
<p style="text-align: left; "><b style="text-align: left; "><i>Reported by BenarNews, an RFA-affiliated online news service.</i></b></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>security, diplomacy</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Lao Migrant Youth Increasingly Looking for Work in China</title>
        <guid>da135634-9006-48f3-98c1-e435d148c200</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/laos/laos-migrant-china-01172019123757.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Laos</category>
	    

        <description>With limited options at home, young Laotians are sneaking into China's Yunnan province in search of greener pastures</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/laos/laos-migrant-china-01172019123757.html/yunnan-laos.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[yunnan-laos]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[RFA]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p><b><b>UPDATED at 2:12 P.M. EST on 2018-01-18</b></b></p>
<p><b><b></b></b>Young people from the northern provinces of Laos are increasingly moving across the border to China in search of jobs and higher wages.</p>
<p>Facing limited prospects at home, youth from Laos’ remote mountainous regions choose to become undocumented economic migrants in China’s neighboring Yunnan province, where they can often make much more for similar work they could get at home.</p>
<p>A Lao businessman who often travels to Yunnan told RFA’s Lao Service last week, “A lot of people from the northern ethnic groups prefer working in China over Laos or Thailand because they speak Chinese and can get much more money there.”</p>
<p>The source added that restaurant workers in Yunnan can make between 80 and 100 yuan ($12-$15) each day, or about twice as much as in Laos and slightly more than in Thailand.</p>
<p>“After graduation, many youth sneak into China to work because there are no jobs at home,” said an unidentified official in Phongsaly province to RFA on Tuesday.</p>
<p>“Most of them work as laborers at restaurants, hotels, shops and stores in Jiangcheng, Yunnan Province,” the official said.</p>
<p>The official of Phongsaly’s Gnot-Ou district said that last year 200 youth from seven of his district’s villages went to Sang Seung to work illegally.</p>
<p>Most of them are members of a Chinese ethnic group and they speak Chinese better than they speak Lao, the official said.</p>
<p>China is a popular destination for them because they may already have connections, such as relatives or friends who live there, said the official.</p>
<p>The official also said that security guards from the villages have attempted to stop the flow of young people across the border, but that it was difficult to track them because they sneak into China using small, hidden paths.</p>
<p>Local authorities in China, however have been quite effective in cracking down on these undocumented migrants.</p>
<p>“Recently they arrested an unspecified number of illegal Lao workers and handed them over to us,” he said.</p>
<p>“Actually, several days ago they sent a busload of Laotians to us at the border,” he said.</p>
<p>“They are very serious about this, they arrest every undocumented person they find,” said the official.</p>
<p>In an effort to prevent more youth from leaving, Gnot-Ou district is applying for financial and human resources from the provincial and central governments.</p>
<p>“We’d like to conduct a campaign against this exodus by providing youth and their parents with more information,” he said.</p>
<p>“We also would like to create jobs here at home for them,” he said.</p>
<p>Many youth from Phongsaly’s neighboring Luangnamtha province, are also finding their way across the border to Yunnan.</p>
<p>“Many high school graduates use border passes to go to Cheli City,” a resident of Luangnamtha said, in an apparent reference to Jinghong, the prefectural seat of the <span> </span>Xishuangbanna Dai Autonomous Prefecture.</p>
<p>“With the pass they can only stay for a month. If they overstay, they can’t come back through the normal border checkpoint. They have to sneak back,” he said.</p>
<p>He said that the language barrier is not an obstacle, as the youth can pick up Chinese after working there for about three years.</p>
<p>He added that many of the Lao girls and women from Luangnamtha who cross the border are lured to work at restaurants or brothels, and some even marry Chinese men.</p>
<p>The Gnot-Ou district official said that he did not know how many Laotians were working in China right now, only the numbers from his own district.</p>
<p>Thailand’s Ministry of Labour in 2017 said there were around 170,000 Laotians working legally in the country. <br/> <br/> While the ministry does not provide figures for undocumented workers from specific countries, it estimates that 2 million migrants are working in Thailand without papers. Reports suggest that more than 200,000 of those illegal migrant workers are from Laos.</p>
<p><strong><i>Reported by RFA’s Lao Service. Translated by RFA’s Lao Service. Written in English by Eugene Whong.</i></strong></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>migrant workers</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Taiwan Holds Live-Fire Military Drills as 80 Percent Reject Chinese Rule</title>
        <guid>0a557eec-9efe-43d5-8fe1-157bdeb0a96b</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/taiwan-holds-live-fire-military-drills-01172019110731.html</link>

	    
	         <category>China</category>
	    

        <description>A Pentagon report says China's People's Liberation Army is rapidly developing 'a robust, lethal force' that will allow Beijing to 'impose its will' in the region.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 16:19:51 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/taiwan-holds-live-fire-military-drills-01172019110731.html/china-taiwan-military-drill-taichung-jun7-2018.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Taiwanese soldiers take part in a military drill simulating a Chinese attack at the Ching Chuan Kang Air Base in central Taiwan's Taichung, June 7, 2018.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Taiwan on Thursday held live-fire military exercises off its coast amid concerns that Beijing could move to annex the democratic island, which has never been ruled by the Chinese Communist Party.</p>
<p>Off the west-coast city of Taichung, targets were set up to give firing practice to artillery units and assault helicopters, while the island's air force flew French-made Mirage fighter jets from its base at Hsinchu in the north.</p>
<p>The drills came as a new Pentagon report set out U.S. concerns about China's growing military might, including a possible attack on Taiwan.</p>
<p>"China ... believes that U.S. military presence ... in Asia seeks to constrain China’s rise and interfere with China’s sovereignty, particularly in a Taiwan conflict scenario," the U.S. Defense Intelligence Agency report said.</p>
<p>A U.S. defense official told journalists that the Chinese Communist Party's determination to rule Taiwan in future is now at the top of President Xi Jinping's to-do list.</p>
<p>"Xi Jinping has made it clear that resolving or making progress, at least, on resolving ... the Taiwan situation is a very top priority for him," an article on the U.S. Department of Defense website cited the official as saying.</p>
<p>The article also cited senior defense intelligence analyst Dan Taylor as saying that the People's Liberation Army (PLA), the Communist Party's military arm, may soon have the military capability to carry out its aim of "unification," and annex the island.</p>
<p>“China is rapidly building a robust, lethal force, with capabilities spanning ground, air, maritime, space and information domains, designed to enable China to impose its will in the region, and beyond,” Taylor said.</p>
<p>“In the coming years, the PLA is likely to grow even more technologically advanced and proficient, with equipment comparable to that of other modern militaries,” he said.</p>
<p>“The PLA will acquire advanced fighter aircraft, modern naval vessels, missile systems, and space and cyberspace assets as it reorganizes and trains to address 21st century threats farther from China’s shores.”<br/><b></b></p>
<p><b>Rejection of ‘unification’ call</b></p>
<p>Taiwan ordered fresh military drills after Taiwan president Tsai Ing-wen rejected calls from President Xi for the democratic island to move towards "unification" with the People's Republic, saying its people have no wish to give up their sovereignty.</p>
<p>Taiwan defense ministry spokesman Major General Chen Chung-chi said the military is updating its exercises to reflect real-world situations.</p>
<p>"We exercise the way wars are fought ... so that we will be capable and confident in the defense of our country," Chen told journalists in Taipei on Wednesday. "We are ready to face an enemy threat at any time."</p>
<p>He said the military would fight to defend the sovereignty of the Republic of China, the official name of Taiwan since the 1911 Kuomintang-led regime fled to the island in 1949 after losing a civil war with Mao Zedong's communists on mainland China.</p>
<p>In a Jan. 2 "Letter to our Taiwan compatriots," Xi was insistent that China must be "unified."</p>
<p>"It has been a historical and unavoidable duty of the Chinese Communist Party, Chinese government, and the Chinese people to resolve the matter of Taiwan and unify the motherland ever since 1949," Xi said in the statement.</p>
<p>Xi made scant reference to public opinion among the 23 million inhabitants of Taiwan, and said that China would make no promises not to use military force to take the island.</p>
<p>A recent opinion poll found that more than 80 percent of Taiwanese would reject Xi's offer to rule the island via the "one country, two systems" model used for the former colonies of Hong Kong and Macau.</p>
<p>Tung Li-wen, an advisor to Taiwan ThinkTank, which conducted the poll, said most people have seen the erosion of Hong Kong's political freedoms and civil liberties since that city's 1997 handover to China, and concluded that they don't want the same thing to happen to them.</p>
<p>"Everything that has taken place in Hong Kong is a road-map of what Taiwan would look like under the Chinese Communist Party," Tung said. "They would do exactly the same things here."</p>
<p>"That's why there is no market for Xi Jinping's so-called peaceful unification under one country, two systems," he said. "I think every single person in Taiwan should stand firm and say no to the Chinese Communist Party ... I don't know why there are still some people in Taiwan who don't dare to say no to China; that's how difficult things are getting here."</p>
<p><b>In defense of democratic values</b></p>
<p>Tsai Yi-yu, a ruling Democratic Progressive Party (DPP) lawmaker, said that many in Taiwan hope that the island's defense of its democracy will be enough to ensure military backing from the U.S. and other democratic nations in the event of a Chinese invasion.</p>
<p>"There is an imbalance in Taiwan's military power, but ... a conflict with Taiwan would be an event of massive international importance," he said. "Unless China wants to take on all the democracies of the world, Taiwan’s defense of its democratic values is the biggest protective factor against a war in the Taiwan Strait."</p>
<p>Tseng Chi-wen, editor-in-chief of the Taiwan-based magazine <i>Asia Pacific Defense</i>, agreed.</p>
<p>"It would be pretty easy [for China] to take Taiwan, but then it would be subject to international isolation and sanctions afterwards," Tseng said. "That could stop or reverse its entire future development strategy and the Chinese dream of national rejuvenation."</p>
<p>Taiwan was ruled as a Japanese colony in the 50 years prior to the end of World War II, but was handed back to the 1911 Republic of China under the Kuomintang (KMT) government as part of Tokyo's post-war reparation deal.</p>
<p>The island began a transition to democracy following the death of Chiang Kai-shek's son, President Chiang Ching-kuo, in January 1988, starting with direct elections to the legislature in the early 1990s and culminating in the first direct election of a president, Lee Teng-hui, in 1996.<br/><i><b></b></i></p>
<p><i><b>Reported by Hsia Hsiao-hwa and Gu Jirou for RFA's Mandarin Service, and by Chung Kuang-cheng for the Cantonese Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>taiwan, military, pla, ccp, us, xi jinping, tsai ing-wen</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Interview: 'I Recognized Her Straight Away'</title>
        <guid>54686475-c6b4-49f2-8305-6f14b8b4d81e</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/uyghur/children-01162019155411.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Uyghur</category>
	    

        <description>A Uyghur mother in exile discovers the daughter she was forced to leave behind in a video about Uyghur children in Xinjiang.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 21:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/uyghur/children-01162019155411.html/uyghur-ayshe-crop.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Kalbinur Tursun's daughter, Ayshe (2nd from L), appears in a still frame from a video about Uyghur children in China's Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Courtesy of Kalbinur Tursun]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Kalbinur Tursun is an ethnic Uyghur mother who fled oppressive policies in northwest China’s Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region (XUAR) for Turkey in April 2016 while seven months pregnant and with one of her six other children in tow. She planned to return to the XUAR after giving birth to bring her remaining children to Turkey with her, but was unable to do so after her husband was arrested back home for “attempting to travel abroad” and “suspected terrorism.”<br/><br/>Since then, dozens of members of her extended family have been detained and she is unsure of what became of her children. Her family members are believed to be among the estimated 1.1 million Uyghurs held in “political re-education camps” throughout the XUAR since April 2017 after being accused by authorities of harboring “strong religious views” and “politically incorrect” ideas. The children of detained parents are regularly brought for care to schools, nurseries or orphanages, where sources say the facilities are seriously overcrowded and in terrible condition.<br/><br/>In December last year, a video portraying Uyghur children in Hotan (Hetian) prefecture surfaced on social media and, upon viewing it, Tursun immediately recognized her daughter Ayshe among those filmed. She recently spoke to RFA’s Uyghur Service about the difficulties she has endured living in exile without knowing what has become of her family.<br/><br/><b>RFA: What makes you so certain that you recognized your daughter?</b><br/><br/>Tursun: From the way she moved her head side to side, I recognized her straight away. Also the way she looked and acted made my heart jump upon seeing her.<br/><br/><b>RFA: Of course, a mother’s heart can recognize these things. When did you travel to Turkey?</b><br/><br/>Tursun: We arrived in Turkey on April 12, 2016. <br/><br/><b>RFA: Did you leave all your children behind when you left?</b><br/><br/>Tursun: Only one of my children had a passport, but the remaining five did not, and I was seven months pregnant when I left. I wanted to return after giving birth to bring them to Turkey, but I was unable to return. I think it was Dec. 24 last year when someone posted the video to the Uyghur Brothers and Sister’s Group on WhatsApp. I am a member of that group and when I played the video, I saw my daughter among the group of children.<br/><br/>I watched it over and over again to check that it was really her and I knew it was, from the way she looked and acted … I am 100 percent certain that it was my daughter. I called the man who shared the video … [and] he told me the video was taken in Hotan.<br/><br/><b>RFA: How old was Ayshe when you left her?</b><br/><br/>Tursun: She was three.<br/><br/><b>RFA: How did you feel when you saw her in the video? You must have felt sad!</b><br/><br/>Tursun: I was happy and overjoyed knowing that at least one of my children is alive. I have never stopped searching for my children since arriving in Turkey, but I have been unable to obtain any information regarding them. My husband didn’t make it to Turkey. I learned that he received a 10-year prison sentence.<br/><br/><b>Family targeted</b><br/><br/><b>RFA: What is your husband’s name?</b><br/><br/>Tursun: Abdurehim Rozi. We had a business which is closed down now.<br/><br/><b>RFA: Who did you leave your children with?</b><br/><br/>Tursun: My husband’s younger brother, who was in business with him, came to our house with his wife to help in looking after our children. My husband was in [XUAR capital] Urumqi, where he was arrested and taken to Hotan.<br/><br/><b>RFA: Did they take the children away after arresting your husband?</b><br/><br/>Tursun: My husband was in Urumqi on business with his two younger brothers when they were all arrested. We were a large family made up of 11 branches. There are at least five or six people from each family branch that have been taken away, so in total there are 70 or 80 people who have disappeared, and we don’t know where they are.<br/><br/>My husband was arrested after being accused of ‘attempting to travel abroad’ and ‘suspected terrorism.’ My youngest child was eight months old when I left, he is now three years old. The eldest is Abduhaliq Abdurehim, 14 years old, then Subinur Abdurehim, 12 years old, Abdusalam Abdurehim, eight years old, Ayeshe, six years old, and Abdullah Abdurehim, three years old.<br/><br/><b>RFA: You don’t have any information regarding any of your children?</b><br/><br/>Tursun: No. The video was taken in Hotan, but I am originally from Yupurgha village in Kashgar (in Chinese, Kashi) prefecture. My children were living in Urumqi. They were initially taken to my village. The last time I communicated with my elder sister was on July 27, 2017, so I knew up until then that my children were in Kashgar.<br/><br/>It was hard before if I didn’t see them for even one day, but now we are separated and I don’t know their whereabouts. I think about them all the time and I must find a way to fix this situation. I would exchange everything, including my life, for my children’s freedom. My greatest concern is that they must be very angry with me, thinking that I abandoned them by not taking them with me to Turkey.<br/><br/>As they are so young, it is impossible for them to understand the reality of the situation and how things had changed. It makes me extremely helpless and sad when I think that … they might develop animosity towards me. I think about my children constantly and how they are coping, and what they are going through each day.<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by Gulchehra Hoja for RFA’s Uyghur Service. Translated by RFA’s Uyghur Service.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>ethnic tension, reeducation camps, turkey, children, orphanages</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Philippines Turns Over to Beijing Ex-Chinese Govt Official Wanted for Graft</title>
        <guid>17eed56d-d6bf-4f1c-b863-f09957aecf61</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/philippines-graft-01162019164406.html</link>

	    
	         <category>China</category>
	    

        <description>Xie Haojie is wanted for economic crimes involving $210 M</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 21:51:40 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/philippines-graft-01162019164406.html/philippines-fugitive.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Chinese immigration police escort Xie Haojie (center), who was arrested on Sunday in Manila in an operation coordinated with Chinese authorities, after he was presented to media in the Philippine capital, Jan. 16, 2019.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p style="text-align: left; ">An ex-government official from China wanted for “corruption and economic crimes” involving U.S. $210 million faces deportation after being arrested in the Philippines and turned over to Chinese authorities in Manila, the Filipino immigration bureau said Wednesday.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">Presidential Anti-Corruption Commission (PACC) and immigration agents took Xie Haojie, 49, into custody during a raid on Sunday at a condominium in Pasay city, a suburb of Manila, Immigration Commissioner Jaime Morente said.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">Xie had been hiding in the Philippines since last year after fleeing China to evade prosecution over a criminal offense, Morente said, adding that his counterpart in Beijing had asked PACC to help them track down the fugitive. Both agencies had coordinated closely with each other in making the arrest, he said.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">“He will immediately be deported back to China so he could face the cases lodged against him. His name will also be included in our blacklist to prevent him from re-entering the Philippines,” Morente said of Xie.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">“We will not tolerate the presence of undesirable aliens using the Philippines as a hideout. Fugitives will be sent back to face their crimes,” he added.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">After Xie was presented to reporters in Manila, senior officials from the Philippine anti-corruption agency and Philippine Bureau of Immigration “turned over Xie today to Chinese authorities in a ceremony held at the office of the PACC at the Palacio del Gobernador in Intramuros, Manila,” immigration officials said in a press release.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">The arrest was tied to the Chinese government’s all-out campaign against corruption that cracked down on abusive government employees, including high-ranking officials.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">Xie was under investigation for allegedly embezzling public funds and taking bribes in his capacity as a general manager of a state-owned enterprise, said La Yifan, director of international cooperation for China’s Central Commission for Discipline Inspection, according to a report published by the Philippine Star on Wednesday.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; ">“The Philippines and China will continue to strengthen our cooperation in going after Chinese fugitives hiding in our country, including former government officials wanted for corruption,” Morente said.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; "><b style="text-align: left; "><i>Reported by BenarNews, an RFA-affiliated online news service.</i></b></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>corruption, extradition</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Two Youths Injured, 200 Villagers Flee Homes Amid Clashes in Myanmar’s Northern Rakhine State</title>
        <guid>8a3c9547-2577-4c2a-bb71-3ab778505c5c</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/myanmar/two-youths-injured-200-villagers-flee-homes-01162019163747.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Myanmar</category>
	    

        <description>Fighting between government forces and the Arakan Army prompts village heads to submit resignations and schools to close.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 21:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/myanmar/two-youths-injured-200-villagers-flee-homes-01162019163747.html/myanmar-wounded-boys-shelling-maungdaw-jan16-2019.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Members of the local charity Sympathy Network-Maungdaw Township transport two youths injured by a exploding mortar shell to a hospital in Maungdaw township, western Myanmar's Rakhine state, Jan. 16, 2019.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Photo courtesy of Aung Kyaw Min]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Fresh skirmishes between the Myanmar military and Arakan Army in violence-scarred northern Rakhine state have left two youths injured and forced about 200 villagers to flee their homes in Maungdaw and Buthidaung townships, local residents said Wednesday.</p>
<p>The two boys, ages 10 and 18, were injured and one house was destroyed when a stray mortar shell exploded in Maungdaw’s Yan Aung Myin village on Wednesday, though it is unclear whether the Myanmar Army or the AA fired the shell, said village head Thein Naing Win.</p>
<p>The two were taken to Maungdaw Hospital for treatment, he added.</p>
<p>About 200 residents of Ooyinthar village fled to Sango Taung village amid fighting on Tuesday, villagers said, bringing the total number of displaced civilians in the region to roughly 6,000 estimated by local relief groups since armed conflict between AA and Myanmar troops ratcheted up in early December.</p>
<p>“The fighting started at around 6 p.m. yesterday and lasted for about 30 minutes,” said an Ooyinthar resident who declined to be named. “All villagers fled from the village. If the fighting stops today, we will return home tomorrow.”</p>
<p>The Myanmar Army and local residents said the new battles left casualties on both sides, but no details were given. The AA said it participated in four new skirmishes but would not confirm whether it suffered any casualties.</p>
<p>Colonel Win Zaw Oo from the government military’s Western Military Command, which oversees operations in Rakhine state, blamed the latest rounds of fire on the AA.</p>
<p>“The AA started the fighting near the villages,” he told RFA's Myanmar Service. “They could have done so far from the villages, but they intentionally started them nearer so that villagers would flee from the fighting. Then the AA, along with the media, could portray the situation in the region as unstable.”</p>
<p>AA soldiers then attacked government troops near the border, and retreated into neighboring Bangladesh, he said.</p>
<p>“We didn’t attack them when they reached the other side because we don’t want to harm the relationship between the two countries,” Win Zaw Oo said.</p>
<p>AA spokesman Khine Thukha denied accusations by the government army that the Arakan force has based some of its soldiers in Bangladesh.</p>
<p>“Actually, we are not there,” he said. “We deploy our troops along the border as we are fighting for Rakhine.”</p>
<p>The government army said it will continue clearance operations against the AA in the region, while the Arakan fighters said they expect more hostilities with national forces.</p>
<p>Clashes intensified after Jan. 4 when the AA, which is fighting for greater autonomy in the state, attacked four police outposts in the region, killing 13 policemen and wounding nine others.</p>
<p><b>Village chiefs threaten walkout </b></p>
<p>Meanwhile, about 30 village chiefs met and talked with the administrator of adjacent Rathedaung township about the arrests of some of their peers for allegedly having links to the AA, and threatened to quit if they do not receive a response from authorities by the end of January.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, they submitted resignations to the local General Services Department out of fear that they too might be accused of links to the AA, <i>Frontier Myanmar</i> magazine reported, in a move that could impair the local government.</p>
<p>One village head who declined to be named out of fear for his safety told RFA that Rathedaung’s administrator said he would inform higher-up administrators about their complaints.</p>
<p>Those arrested so far include a village head from Buthidaung’s Pyin Chaung village and one from Yekaung Chaung village. Both have been charged under Myanmar’s Unlawful Associations Act for allegedly having links to the AA, considered to be an outlawed armed ethnic organization.</p>
<p>Rights groups accuse Myanmar authorities of using the act to intimidate and arrest ethnic minorities, especially those in turbulent regions where government troops are engaged in hostilities with ethnic armies.</p>
<p>Amid the uptick in fighting between the AA and Myanmar military in Rakhine state, government military authorities have restricted displaced civilians' access to food supplies in an effort to keep food from reaching AA troops.</p>
<p>Government forces began restricting food supplies in the state’s Kyauktaw township on Dec. 28 following clashes with the AA, one displaced resident told RFA in an earlier report.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the Sub-Committee for Judiciary Fairness of Rakhine state’s Rule of Law Department called the blocking of aid to displaced persons in Kyauktaw a violation of international law.</p>
<p>Sub-committee leader Thar San told reporters during a public talk at the Rakhine state Attorney General’s Office that everyone has a right to receive aid and that it is disappointing to see the Myanmar military preventing it from reaching displaced villagers.</p>
<p>The group will submit a demand to the Union Attorney General’s office in Naypyidaw if Rakhine state Chief Minister Nyi Pu can’t end the blockade, he said.</p>
<p>The coordination body for the Rule of Law Department and Sub-Committee for Judiciary Fairness is led by Union attorney General Tun Tun Oo.</p>
<p>RFA was unable to reach Nyi Pu or Rakhine state Border Affairs Minister Colonel Phone Tint for comment.</p>
<p>More than 2,000 IDPs from Kyauktaw's Wadaung, Kan Saut, and Taung Min Kalar villages face food shortages because of the aid block by the military.</p>
<p><b><div class="image-inline captioned" style="width:622px;">
<div style="width:622px;">
<img alt="An abandoned school stands in in Kyee Kan Pyin village in Maungdaw township, western Myanmar's Rakhine State, Oct. 14, 2016." src="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/myanmar/two-youths-injured-200-villagers-flee-homes-01162019163747.html/myanmar-abandoned-school-maungdaw-oct14-2016.jpg" title="An abandoned school stands in in Kyee Kan Pyin village in Maungdaw township, western Myanmar's Rakhine State, Oct. 14, 2016."/>
</div>
<div class="image-caption">
<span style="width:622px;">An abandoned school stands in in Kyee Kan Pyin village in Maungdaw township, western Myanmar's Rakhine State, Oct. 14, 2016.</span>
<span class="copyright">Credit: AFP</span>
</div>
<div id="zoomattribute">
<a class="single_image" href="/english/news/myanmar/two-youths-injured-200-villagers-flee-homes-01162019163747.html/myanmar-abandoned-school-maungdaw-oct14-2016.jpg" title="An abandoned school stands in in Kyee Kan Pyin village in Maungdaw township, western Myanmar's Rakhine State, Oct. 14, 2016.">
<img src="/rfa_resources/graphics/icon-zoom.png"/>
</a>
</div>
</div>Township schools close</b></p>
<p>The ongoing clashes also have closed 31 schools in Rakhine state just before students are scheduled to take final exams.</p>
<p>“Sixteen schools in Buthidaung have been closed since Jan. 7 because of the fighting,” Sein Hla Tun, deputy director of Rakhine state’s Education Department, told RFA.</p>
<p>“It’s very difficult to travel to school,” he said. “These schools will be reopened once the situation returns to normal. The students cannot go to other villages for schooling, either, as the region is now a flashpoint.”</p>
<p>Besides the schools in Buthidaung, other closures include a dozen schools in Kyauktaw, two in Ponnagyun township, and one in Rathedaung — all of which have more than 1,000 students, he said.</p>
<p>Officials have requested that children staying in relief camps for displaced people in Kyauktaw and Ponnagyun townships go to nearby schools to take their exams, Sein Hla Tun said.</p>
<p>“They are being provided with school uniforms and materials and are being taught during extra hours,” he said. “The children will not be disadvantaged as we are fulfilling their needs as much as we can.”</p>
<p>Myanmar schools will hold exams for all schoolchildren except those in 10th grade beginning the first week of February, he said.</p>
<p>Officials are now discussing exam options and special arrangements for those who have no access to schools in Buthidaung township, Sein Hla Tun said.</p>
<p>“Since the exams will begin after the end of this month, we hope to find a solution after Jan. 20,” he said. “They will have to take exams at the same time because the exam period cannot be held twice, but they will be treated as leniently as possible.”<br/> <i><b></b></i></p>
<p><i><b>Reported by Min Thein Aung and Nandar Chann for RFA’s Myanmar Service. Translation by Khet Mar and Nandar Chann. Written in English by Roseanne Gerin.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>rakhine, arakan, children, ethnic armies, military, villagers, education, students</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Cambodian Activist Arrested For Facebook Post on Rice Tariffs</title>
        <guid>08ffc034-83f0-40eb-862b-d05a86300a7b</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/tariffs-01162019153641.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cambodia</category>
	    

        <description>Meanwhile, two former opposition figures are allowed to re-enter politics after applying to Cambodia's king for a 'pardon.'</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 20:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/cambodia/tariffs-01162019153641.html/khmer-kongmas-011619.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Kong Mas is shown in a Facebook photo posted on the day of his arrest, Jan. 16, 2019.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Kong Mas / Facebook]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Cambodia’s Ministry of the Interior on Wednesday arrested a member of the banned Cambodia National Rescue Party after he posted a Facebook message saying the European Union plans to impose a tariff on Cambodian rice, sources in the country said.<br/><br/>Kong Mas, a political activist from Svay Rieng province, was taken into custody at a coffee shop in the capital Phnom Penh by around 10 officers accompanied by a government prosecutor, fellow CNRP member Em Sokvan told RFA’s Khmer Service.<br/><br/>“The police said they were arresting him because of his Facebook post. They said they wanted to question him,” Em Sokvan, who had been drinking coffee with Kong Mas when he was detained, told RFA.<br/><br/>Police offered no further details on the reasons for the arrest, Em Sokvan said, adding that Kong Mas is now being held at National Police Commission headquarters in Phnom Penh.<br/><br/>Reached for comment, national police spokesman Chhay Kim Khoeun denied knowledge of the arrest.<br/><br/>But speaking to RFA, Kong Mas’s lawyer Sam Sokong said his client will be held for questioning for 24 hours before attorneys or family members will be allowed to meet with him.<br/><br/>“Police told me that he has been accused of ‘incitement,’ but I don’t know what that means,” he said.<br/><br/>In a Facebook posting on Wednesday, Kong Mas said that EU officials plan to impose a tariff on Cambodian rice of $200 per ton.<br/><br/>The EU move, which includes Myanmar and targets a surge in imports of rice from both countries, sets a three-year period in which tariffs, set in the first year at 175 euros (U.S. $200) per ton, will decline in the second year to 150 euros and in the third year to 125 euros, media sources say.<br/><br/>The policy goes into effect this week.<br/><b><br/>Politically sensitive</b><br/><br/>Threatened EU trade sanctions are a politically sensitive topic in Cambodia, which banned the CNRP and jailed its leader in 2017, paving the way for Prime Minister Hun Sen’s ruling Cambodian People’s Party (CPP) to win all 125 seats on offer in parliamentary elections in July 2018. <br/><br/>According to the European Commission, the EU ranked in 2017 as Cambodia’s second-largest trade partner, importing goods worth 5 billion euros (U.S. $5.8 billion) from the country. <br/><br/>Key EU imports from Cambodia include textiles, footwear, and agricultural products.<br/><br/>Speaking to RFA on Jan. 16, CNRP activist Sun Makara described the arrest of Kong Mas as “politically motivated,” calling the opposition activist a brave man unafraid of intimidation by authorities.<br/><br/>“The authorities used to call Kong Mas to offer him a position [in Hun Sen’s government], but he always refused,” he said, adding, “He has really done nothing wrong.”<br/><br/>Also speaking to RFA, Soeng San Karuna—spokesman for the Cambodia-based rights group Adhoc—said that if authorities have arrested Kong Mas simply for posting on Facebook, they will have violated the country’s constitution.<br/><br/>“If they take actions like these against dissidents, they have violated human rights,” he said.<br/><br/><b>Petition to work</b><br/><br/>Also on Wednesday, former National Election Commission member and advisor to the Cambodian Independent Teachers’ Association Rong Chhun filed a complaint with the Phnom Penh Municipal Court, asking that the court reverse a move by the Ministry of Education to refuse permission to 10 CNRP-affiliated teachers to work.<br/><br/>Elected to commune council positions before their party was dissolved by Supreme Court order in 2017, the 10 had petitioned to be allowed to resume teaching, but were turned down.<br/><br/>“We want the court to annul the Ministry of Education’s decision,” Rong Chhun said.<br/><br/>Meanwhile, Cambodian king Norodom Sihamoni on Tuesday issued statements rehabilitating two former opposition politicians, Kong Koam and his son Kong Bora, allowing them to return to political life in Cambodia.<br/><br/>The two were among 118 officials slapped with a five-year suspension of political rights as part of a decision by the Supreme Court in November 2017 to dissolve the CNRP for its role in an alleged plot to topple the government.<br/><br/>Prime Minister Hun Sen’s CPP then ran effectively uncontested in July 29, 2018 general elections, drawing condemnation from Western nations who called the ballot unfree and unfair amid a wide crackdown on the political opposition and other rollbacks on democracy.<br/><br/>Speaking to RFA, political analyst Kim Sok called the politicians’ reinstatement a defeat for plans by Hun Sen to weaken the CNRP, now organized and active in exile, by allowing opposition officials to return to politics only if they each make individual requests for a “pardon.”<br/><br/>“Hun Sen has failed in his plans, because only two people have now asked to go back into politics,” Kim Sok said.<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Samean Yun. Written in English by Richard Finney.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>trade, sanctions, detentions, cnrp, internet</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Family Doubt Official Cause of Death For Chinese Petitioner Who Died in Detention</title>
        <guid>e377f928-9284-48e2-a76f-45b0a4bf82d6</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/family-doubt-official-cause-of-death-01162019113013.html</link>

	    
	         <category>China</category>
	    

        <description>The son of Shenyang petitioner Liu Zhen is incommunicado after raising doubts about the cause of his father's death on social media.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 16:49:36 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/family-doubt-official-cause-of-death-01162019113013.html/china-petitioner-liu-zhen-undated-photo.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Chinese petitioner Liu Zhen from Shenyang, northeastern China's Liaoning province, in an undated photo.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Photo courtesy of Minsheng Guancha]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Family members of a petitioner who died in the custody of "interceptors" after traveling to the Chinese capital to pursue a complaint against the government have questioned official claims that he had a heart attack.</p>
<p>Liu Zhen died last week after being held for more than two months a police-run detention center in Liaoning's provincial capital Shenyang in northeastern China, his home city.</p>
<p>He had been detained after setting out to lodge a petition at the U.S. embassy in Beijing last October, around with a dozen other people.</p>
<p>He was detained and taken back to Shenyang by "interceptors," before being held under criminal detention in the city's Hunnan district before his formal arrest in December.</p>
<p>His family was informed on Jan. 13 of his death from a "heart attack," but relatives who identified his body said there were visible marks of injury to his chest area that led them to distrust the officially registered cause of death.</p>
<p>"Liaoning rights activist Zhu Zhongxiao told RFA that Liu's grown son is now incommunicado after being called in by police for "a chat."</p>
<p>"His son had been planning to meet with some rights defenders in Shenyang [on Tuesday]," Zhu said. "But he was taken away by police, and we don't know if he even went willingly; it's likely that he now has restrictions on his freedom."</p>
<p>He said Liu's son had been detained after he posted on the Sina Weibo social media platform about his father's death.</p>
<p>"His son posted to Weibo that there were greenish-purple marks on his father's chest, which the authorities said were caused by their attempts to resuscitate him," Zhu said. "If that's so, then why wouldn't they allow the family to take photos?"</p>
<p>He said the family had submitted a request for an autopsy to the local prosecutor's office on Monday, but that they have no idea where Liu's body is being held.</p>
<p>"Where has the body gone?" Zhu said. "That is one question mark."</p>
<p><b>‘A long and slow process’</b></p>
<p>Li Ning, whose mother Li Shulian's death in custody in 2009 led to the charging of six officials with "illegal detention" last month, said the remains of a loved one are the only evidence remaining for families who suspect foul play after a death in custody.</p>
<p>"The family has the right to apply for an autopsy, and if they are suspicious about the official autopsy, they can apply for an autopsy carried out by a third party," Li said. "They can't stop you taking photos of the body, and the family also has the right hold the detention center to account and to hire a lawyer to represent them."</p>
<p>"They can also demand access to relevant video and audio recordings," she said.</p>
<p>But she said any attempt to see justice done isn't for the faint-hearted.</p>
<p>"This is a long and slow process, and a very, very tough one," Li said. "There are some similarities between [Liu's death] and my mother's case, and it took me 10 years to get to this point because the family didn't have possession of the body."</p>
<p>"It is very, very hard to take this through official channels," she said.</p>
<p>Last month, authorities in the central province of Henan executed a petitioner for killing a police officer who was forcibly escorting him home from a petitioning trip in the Chinese capital.</p>
<p>Veteran activist Xu Youchen, 58, was executed on Nov. 15 after the China Supreme People’s Court approved his death sentence the month before, according to London-based rights group Amnesty International, which had campaigned for a reprieve.</p>
<p>But rights groups have also cited procedural irregularities with the handling of the policeman's death.</p>
<p>Authorities cremated the body of the policeman allegedly killed by the couple just four days after he died, making it impossible to re-examine the exact time and cause of death, Amnesty International reported.</p>
<p>China's army of petitioners, who flood the ruling Chinese Communist Party's official complaints departments with more than 20,000 complaints daily across the country, frequently report being held in "black jails," beaten, or otherwise harassed, if they persist in a complaint beyond its initial rejection at the local level.</p>
<p>They are often escorted home forcibly by "interceptors" sent by their local governments to prevent negative reports from reaching the ears of higher authorities.</p>
<p><i><b>Reported by Gao Feng for RFA's Mandarin Service, and by Wong Lok-to for the Cantonese Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>petitioners, death in custody, detentions</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Police Raid Legal Consultancy 'Club' Founded by Disbarred Chinese Lawyers</title>
        <guid>9288272d-29ed-4dc9-bf83-b68653258352</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/raid-01162019111843.html</link>

	    
	         <category>China</category>
	    

        <description>The club has been designated an 'illegal organization,' amid fears that arrests could follow.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 16:42:18 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/chinas-embattled-human-rights-lawyers-set-up-legal-consultancy-09182018113025.html/china-lawyers-club-guangxi-sept18-2018.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[A view of the office of the Chinese Lawyers' Club set up by human rights attorneys in southern China's Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region to represent the public, Sept. 18, 2018.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Photo courtesy of Tan Yongpei]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Authorities in the southwestern Chinese region of Guangxi have raided a legal consultation company started by disbarred human rights lawyers and ordered it closed, RFA has learned.<br/><br/>Dozens of police officers on Tuesday raided the China Lawyers' Club set up last September by Tan Yongpei, a former rights attorney stripped of his license by the local justice bureau for taking on too many "sensitive" human rights cases.<br/><br/>"There were more than 30 police officers, as well as officials from the civil affairs and justice bureaus, so 40-50 people in total," Tan told RFA. "They told us we couldn't hang up our sign, and that we are an illegal organization of banned lawyers."<br/><br/>If the club continued to operate, members were warned that further action would be taken.<br/><br/>Police then went around the premises taking photos and left, after which Tan said he rehung the sign.<br/><br/>The club had initially lodged an application with the bureau of civil affairs to register as an organization, but was rejected, Tan said.<br/><br/>"They are afraid that Chinese lawyers may later form a political opposition, maybe a political party," he said.<br/><br/>Tan said he plans to lodge an official complaint with the civil affairs department and to apply once more to have the club's registration approved.<br/><br/>He said he believes the order for the ban came from the police department.<br/><br/>"Their aim was to frighten and threaten us ... they went around filming and taking photos in every corner," Tan said. "When I wouldn't give them the sign, they ripped it down."<br/><br/>"This is an office environment. We have a right to display any sign we want to," he said.<br/><br/><b>China Lawyer's Club</b><br/><br/>A nationwide police operation under the administration of President Xi Jinping has targeted more than 300 lawyers, law firms, and related activists for questioning, detention, imprisonment, debarring and travel bans since it launched in July 2015.<br/><br/>The China Lawyers' Club was set up in Guangxi's regional capital, Nanning, by a group of former rights attorneys who lost their "business license" at the hands of local justice departments, and may no longer represent clients in court.<br/><br/>Formally established on Sept. 29, 2018, the club's aim is to find employment and income for dozens of experienced litigators who no longer have an income in the wake of the crackdown.<br/><br/>The club is a legal services company, and signs lawyers in a manner similar to the way sports teams sign big stars. Under current regulations, Chinese lawyers need a business license to represent clients, but not to offer legal consultancy on petitions and complaints.<br/><br/>Club executive secretary Chen Keyun agreed that the organization appears to have become a political target of the government.<br/><br/>"They have already designated it a an illegal organization, so if we continue our public activities under the club's name ... their next step may be ... arresting people," Chen said.<br/><br/>An official who answered the phone at the civil affairs bureau of Nanning's Xixiangtang district government declined to comment when contacted by RFA on Wednesday.<br/><br/>"Sorry, we haven't heard about this," the official said.<br/><br/><b>Oath required</b><br/><br/>China last month further stepped up pressure on its embattled legal profession, requiring more than 100,000 lawyers to take a new national oath to "root out instability," particularly in ethnic minority areas of the country.<br/><br/>Justice minister Fu Zhenghua attended a collective lawyers' oath-taking ceremony in Hohhot, the regional capital of Inner Mongolia, on Sunday, the same day as more than 100,000 lawyers took the same oath in hundreds of Chinese cities, the ministry of justice said at the time.<br/><br/>The lawyers swore allegiance to the People's Republic of China, and to "strive to build a socialist country ruled by law," it said.<br/><br/>The oath ceremonies were aimed at "strengthening lawyers' ideological and political education," the ministry said.<br/><br/>But under newly revised rules on oath-taking, lawyers who failed to take the oath could face professional sanctions.<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by Wong Lok-to for RFA's Cantonese Service, and by Gao Feng for the Mandarin Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>judicial system, rights lawyers</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Xinjiang Authorities Detain Uyghur Aspiring Professional Footballer in ‘Political Re-education Camp’</title>
        <guid>3ac3164d-0ea5-475e-83cc-1d78529effcc</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/uyghur/footballer-01152019172111.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Uyghur</category>
	    

        <description>His cousin says he was arrested for maintaining contact with family members who fled the region.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/uyghur/footballer-01152019172111.html/uyghur-erpat-ablekrem-crop.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Erpat Ablekrem in an undated photo.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Photo appears courtesy of Muyesser Abdulehet]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Authorities in northwest China’s Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region (XUAR) have detained 24-year-old Uyghur Erpat Ablekrem—an aspiring professional footballer—in a “political re-education camp” after he maintained contact with family members who fled the country, according to his cousin.<br/><br/>Ablekrem, also known by his Chinese name Aierpati Abulaikeremu, was detained from his hometown of Ghulja (in Chinese, Yining) city, in the XUAR’s Ili Kazakh (Yili Hasake) Autonomous Prefecture in March last year and sent to a “political re-education camp” in the area, his cousin Muyesser Abdulehet told RFA’s Uyghur Service.<br/><br/>The young man, who had played goal keeper for a variety of teams both inside the XUAR and in China’s Shandong province, is believed to have been detained for maintaining contact with Abdulehet after she and her family fled Beijing’s repressive policies in the region and resettled in Turkey, she said.<br/><br/>“I received news that he had been taken to a re-education camp in March last year,” Abdulehet said, referring to the vast network of facilities where authorities have detained Uyghurs and other Muslim ethnic minorities accused of harboring “strong religious views” and “politically incorrect” ideas throughout the XUAR since April 2017.<br/><br/>“I believe he is still in Ghulja in one of the regional re-education camps,” she added.<br/><br/>Abdulehet said she had learned of her cousin’s detention from “an acquaintance” as all of her relatives in the XUAR had removed her from their contact lists, out of fear of persecution by local authorities.<br/><br/>“He is the only one in the family who has been arrested, and I believe the reason for his arrest is that he kept in contact with us,” she said.<br/><br/>Abdulehet said she had last heard from Ablekrem in January last year, when he left a voice message on her WeChat account.<br/><br/>“Because he loved me dearly, we kept in touch via WeChat,” she said.<br/><br/>“I rarely contacted him because I didn't want him to get into trouble, but he occasionally would leave a voice message for me.”<br/><br/><b>Aspiring footballer</b><br/><br/>According to information posted by football fans on social media, Ablekrem began playing football in primary school in Ghulja at the age of seven, and was selected to play in a national tournament for pupils held in Shandong at the age of 10.<br/><br/>He played for a number of teams in Ghulja and competed in several tournaments in the XUAR, as well as for an affiliate of China’s Super League team Shandong Luneng Taishan F.C., as part of its National Under 17 Youth League squad.<br/><br/>Abdulehet said the young man had been studying city planning at university, but left after two years to pursue his dream of becoming a professional footballer.<br/><br/>She said that he told her he had tried out with a team “in Mainland China” and received praise from the manager, but was rejected “because I am a Uyghur.”<br/><br/>After he returned to Ghulja, Ablekrem took a job as a taxi driver because “footballers from our region can’t really make a living from playing,” she said.<br/><br/>“Erpat is not only a hardworking professional young man, but he is also very cultured and polite,” Abdulehet said, adding that “it really hurts me when I think of him being locked up.”<br/><br/>Juret Zahir, a prominent former football coach from the XUAR who is now living in the U.S., noted that Ablekrem’s arrest followed that of Chinese Super League forward Erfan Hezim, also known by his Chinese name Ye Erfan, in February last year.<br/><br/>Hezim, who began playing professionally at the age of 15, and in July 2017 inked a five-year contract with Jiangsu Suning F.C., was detained in a re-education camp for “visiting foreign countries” after he traveled abroad to train and take part in matches, according to sources.<br/><br/>Zahir said the detentions indicate that Chinese authorities are systematically targeting the “best and brightest” of the Uyghur community in a bid to undermine ethnic pride.<br/><br/>“They have locked up our top businessmen, intellectuals, artists, and even our athletes, who are the elite representatives of our [people],” he said.<br/><br/>“Countries rarely mix politics with sports, but the Chinese government creates excuses to lock up Uyghur leaders from all professions.”<br/><br/><b>Camp network</b><br/><br/>While Beijing initially denied the existence of re-education camps, chairman of the XUAR, Shohrat Zakir, told China’s official Xinhua news agency in October last year that the facilities are an effective tool to protect the country from terrorism and provide vocational training for Uyghurs.<br/><br/>Reporting by RFA’s Uyghur Service and other media organizations, however, has shown that those in the camps are detained against their will and subjected to political indoctrination, routinely face rough treatment at the hands of their overseers, and endure poor diets and unhygienic conditions in the often overcrowded facilities.<br/><br/>Adrian Zenz, a lecturer in social research methods at the Germany-based European School of Culture and Theology, has said that some 1.1 million people are or have been detained in the camps—equating to 10 to 11 percent of the adult Muslim population of the XUAR.<br/><br/>In November 2018, Scott Busby, the deputy assistant secretary in the Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights and Labor at the U.S. Department of State, said there are "at least 800,000 and possibly up to a couple of million" Uyghurs and others detained at re-education camps in the XUAR without charges, citing U.S. intelligence assessments.<br/><br/>Citing credible reports, U.S. lawmakers Marco Rubio and Chris Smith, who head the bipartisan Congressional-Executive Commission on China, recently called the situation in the XUAR "the largest mass incarceration of a minority population in the world today."<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by Gulchehra Hoja for RFA’s Uyghur Service. Translated by RFA’s Uyghur Service. Written in English by Joshua Lipes.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>sports, football, ethnic tension, reeducation camps</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Myanmar Military Frees 13 Villagers Caught in Rakhine Conflict</title>
        <guid>c6d007e1-d9ab-455d-b8f8-a100d679b9ab</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/myanmar/myanmar-military-frees-13-villagers-01152019160748.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Myanmar</category>
	    

        <description>Two others have been charged under the Unlawful Associations Act for alleged contact with Arakan Army forces.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 21:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/myanmar/myanmar-military-frees-13-villagers-01152019160748.html/myanmar-freed-villagers-military-rakhine-state-jan14-2019.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Thirteen villagers detained by Myanmar soldiers, but later released, stand with other area residents outside the Arakan National Party office in Buthidaung township, western Myanmar's Rakhine state, Jan. 14, 2019.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Photo courtesy of Arakan National Party-Buthidaung]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Myanmar’s military on Monday freed all but two of 15 villagers suspected of contact with rebel forces after detaining them for a day in Buthidaung township amid fighting between government soldiers and insurgent Arakan Army troops in restive northern Rakhine state, a national lawmaker said Tuesday.</p>
<p>The 13 who were released said soldiers questioned them about possible connections to the Arakan Army (AA) and asked if they were supplying food to soldiers, Maung Kyaw Zan, a legislator in the upper house of parliament, told RFA’s Myanmar Service.</p>
<p>Seven of the men are from Buithdaung’s Pyin Chaung village, two are from Apautwa village in Kyauktaw township, one is from Kyauktaw’s Naypukhan village, and the rest are travelers, he said.</p>
<p>The soldiers have not freed Maung Than Hlaing, head of Pyin Chaung village, or resident Maung Kyaw Win and have charged them under Section 17 (1) and (2) of Myanmar’s Unlawful Associations Act at Buthidaung township court, Maung Kyaw Zan said.</p>
<p>A resident of Thayetpyin village who was detained for an explosion in Buthidaung on Dec. 30 was also charged under Section 17 (1) and (2) and sent to jail in the township, he said.</p>
<p>Rights groups say Myanmar authorities use the act mainly to intimidate and arrest political activists and members of ethnic minorities, thereby posing a threat to freedom of association in the developing democracy.</p>
<p>Section (1) of the act carries a three-year prison sentence for those who are members of or interact with an unlawful association, such as an ethnic armed group, while Section (2) carries a five-year term for assisting such an organization.</p>
<p>In addition, two villagers who were taken by soldiers during fighting on Monday between the AA and government army have not returned home, and their mobile phones are turned off, their family members told RFA.</p>
<p>Hostilities between the two armies have intensified in Buthidaung since Jan. 4 when the AA, a Rakhine Buddhist military force that wants greater autonomy in the state, carried out coordinated attacks on four police outposts near Myanmar’s border with Bangladesh, killing 13 policemen and injuring nine others.</p>
<p>Government army troops had been conducting clearance operations in the area amid a new round of hostilities that began in December.</p>
<p>The clashes, which have included the use of heavy weapons and helicopters by the Myanmar Army, have driven more than 5,000 civilians from their homes. Government military authorities have restricted displaced civilians' access to food supplies.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Myanmar officials postponed a planned visit by United Nations refugee chief Filippo Grandi to Rakhine state on account of fresh hostilities between security forces and the AA, Agence France-Press reported.</p>
<p>Before the uptick in fighting, northern Rakhine state was rocked by a brutal military crackdown on Rohingya Muslims following deadly attacks on police outposts by the Arakan Rohingya Salvation Army (ARSA) militant group in August 2017. More than 725,000 Rohingya fled to safety in neighboring Bangladesh during the campaign of violence.<br/><b></b></p>
<p><b><div class="image-inline captioned" style="width:622px;">
<div style="width:622px;">
<img alt="Myanmar soldiers stand guard as air force helicopters arrive at the airport in Sittwe, capital of western Myanmar's Rakhine state, Oct. 13, 2016." src="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/myanmar/myanmar-military-frees-13-villagers-01152019160748.html/myanmar-helicopter-rakhine-state-oct13-2016.jpg" title="Myanmar soldiers stand guard as air force helicopters arrive at the airport in Sittwe, capital of western Myanmar's Rakhine state, Oct. 13, 2016."/>
</div>
<div class="image-caption">
<span style="width:622px;">Myanmar soldiers stand guard as air force helicopters arrive at the airport in Sittwe, capital of western Myanmar's Rakhine state, Oct. 13, 2016.</span>
<span class="copyright">Credit: AFP</span>
</div>
<div id="zoomattribute">
<a class="single_image" href="/english/news/myanmar/myanmar-military-frees-13-villagers-01152019160748.html/myanmar-helicopter-rakhine-state-oct13-2016.jpg" title="Myanmar soldiers stand guard as air force helicopters arrive at the airport in Sittwe, capital of western Myanmar's Rakhine state, Oct. 13, 2016.">
<img src="/rfa_resources/graphics/icon-zoom.png"/>
</a>
</div>
</div>‘No restrictions on helicopters’</b></p>
<p>When asked about the use of helicopters in the fighting, Myanmar military spokesman Colonel Zaw Min Tun told RFA that government forces are conducting a counter-insurgency campaign against the AA, not a civil war.</p>
<p>Government spokesman Zaw Htay told a news conference on Jan. 7 that the President’s Office ordered the army to supply more troops to the area and if necessary use helicopters in military campaigns against the AA, which he said had links to ARSA, even though the latter purports to speak only for Muslim Rohingyas.</p>
<p>The order sparked criticism against the military as well as against State Counselor Aung San Suu Kyi, Myanmar’s de factor leader, as a violation of international law and human rights.</p>
<p>But Zaw Htay defended the decision by noting that both Myanmar and international practice have permitted the use of the aircraft in counter-insurgency campaigns.</p>
<p>“There’s no restriction on the use of helicopters in domestic conflict,” he said.</p>
<p>AA spokesman Khine Thukha accused the government army’s air campaign of harming civilians.</p>
<p>“The excessive use of force will dishonor [the military],’ he said. “The bombing campaign actually harms local residents. Bombing civilians is a crime against humanity.”</p>
<p>Khine Thukha also dismissed the army’s term “insurgent” to describe the AA, and said the military is the force acting as an insurgent.</p>
<p>Others expressed mixed reactions to the Myanmar’s Army’s use of the helicopters in battle.</p>
<p>“Helicopters and advanced weapons shouldn’t be used, because this is a domestic conflict, not one against a foreign adversary,” said Naw Zipporah Sein, an ethnic Karen political activist and former vice president of the Karen National Union.</p>
<p>“That will hamper peace efforts in the country and cause a loss of public confidence,” she said.</p>
<p>Myanmar human rights lawyer Aung Htoo also questioned the helicopters’ use.</p>
<p>“There’s no indication of a terror organization at all, and under such circumstances, the government’s use of air support is against international practice.”</p>
<p>Yu Lwin Aung, a member of the Myanmar National Human Rights Commission, disagreed.</p>
<p>“Things like people fleeing and having no access to health care and education relate to human rights issues,” he said. “But you can’t say for sure that every use of helicopters violates human rights.”<br/><b></b></p>
<p><b>Confederation is ‘unrealistic’</b></p>
<p>Also on Tuesday, the leader of the Institute for Strategy and Policy (ISP), a Myanmar think tank, said the AA’s dream of obtaining confederate status for Rakhine state is unrealistic.</p>
<p>Min Zin, ISP’s founding member and executive director, told reporters in Yangon that additional armed conflicts would arise in Rakhine state if the AA makes this its political objective.</p>
<p>“If the AA talks about a confederation of states with the intention of leveraging the organization, the AA and government can maintain their discussions,” he said. “But if AA considers this confederation issue as a political dream or vision or expectation for Rakhine, it will be difficult for us to have peace, and there will be more conflicts.”</p>
<p>Min Zin was commenting on a statement that AA commander-in-chief Brigadier General Tun Myat Naing made to the online journal <i>The Irrawaddy</i> that the rebel force prefers a confederation of states such as that of Wa state — an unrecognized state located in eastern Myanmar divided into northern and southern regions which are separated from one another and administered by the United Wa State Army — rather than a federal state that the government is striving for.</p>
<p>Tun Myat Naing said this would give the AA a larger share of power in line with the country’s constitution, and that a confederation is “better” than federalism.</p>
<p>The AA is one of seven ethnic armed groups belonging to the Federal Political Negotiation and Consultative Committee (FPNCC) that has proposed a confederate system in Myanmar that allows ethnic organizations to maintain their own armed forces.</p>
<p>Min Zin also urged the ruling civilian-led National League for Democracy government to cooperate with the national army instead of trying to limit or reduce the powers granted to it by the 2008 constitution, drafted by a military junta that previously ruled the country.</p>
<p>“If the government tries to hold a meeting [with the national military] only when a problem occurs, such as the AA’s attack in Rakhine, it can only expect a reactive response from the military,” he said.</p>
<p>“If the government wants mutual respect and cooperation from military, then it must give priority to working with the military in parliament or in the state’s emergency and security meetings.”</p>
<p><i><b>Reported by Min Thein Aung, Htet Arkar, and Aung Theinkha for RFA’s Myanmar Service. Translated by Nandar Chann and Khet Mar. Written in English by Roseanne Gerin.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>villages, rakhine, arakan, military, ethnic armies, human rights, detentions</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Rights Groups Demand Release of Uyghur Professor Ilham Tohti on Fifth Anniversary of Arrest</title>
        <guid>77c86140-11d9-49e5-92fa-f5e11f6140d1</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/uyghur/tohti-01152019161310.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Uyghur</category>
	    

        <description>Observers say Beijing’s rejection of his advice about policies in Xinjiang has furthered instability there.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 21:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/uyghur/release-01172018142356.html/china-tohti2-011718jpg.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Imprisoned Uyghur professor and blogger Ilham Tohti is shown in an undated photo.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Rights activists and Uyghur advocacy groups on Tuesday demanded the release from prison of Uyghur academic and blogger Ilham Tohti in statements marking the fifth anniversary of his arrest on charges of promoting separatism and subsequent sentencing to a life term behind bars.<br/><br/>An outspoken economics professor who regularly highlighted the religious and cultural persecution of the mostly Muslim Uyghur ethnic minority in northwest China’s Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region (XUAR), Tohti was sentenced on Sept. 23, 2014 following a two-day show trial.<br/><br/>The court decision cited Tohti’s criticism of Beijing’s ethnic policies, his interviews with overseas media outlets, and his work founding and running the Chinese-language website Uighurbiz.net, which was shut down by Chinese authorities in 2014.<br/><br/>On Tuesday, the Germany-based Ilham Tohti Initiative urged Beijing to immediately and unconditionally free the jailed writer and professor, calling the conditions of his imprisonment a “calculated and cruel deprivation” of his rights to family visits and outside communication.<br/><br/>“All this is carefully engineered to punish the Uyghur scholar with degrading treatment and psychological torture, while at the same time keeping the attention on his plight from the outside world to a minimum,” the group’s president Enver Can said in a statement.<br/><br/>Can said that Tohti’s family has not been able to visit him at the XUAR capital Urumqi’s No. 1 Prison for the past two years, and cited a report by rights group ChinaChange that claimed he had been held in solitary confinement and denied the right to communicate with friends and loved ones.<br/> <video> <video> <source></source> Your browser does not support HTML5 video. </video> <br/>The Ilham Tohti Initiative urged China’s government to “unconditionally free Ilham Tohti, [as well as] his students and all innocent Uyghur intellectuals and writers” in prison or “political re-education camps,” where authorities have detained Uyghurs and other Muslim ethnic minorities accused of harboring “strong religious views” and “politically incorrect” ideas throughout the XUAR since April 2017.<br/><br/>Beijing-based rights activist Hu Jia told RFA’s Uyghur Service Tuesday that Tohti’s situation—imprisoned and prevented from seeing his friends and family—“reflects the actual situation of the Uyghur people living as second class citizens under Communist Party rule in China.”<br/><br/>Hu said that in the time since Tohti’s family was last allowed to visit him, the health of the professor is unknown, and expressed concern that authorities “will allow him to die slowly, like they did to Liu Xiaobo,” the late Nobel peace laureate and political prisoner who succumbed to liver cancer in July 2017.<br/><br/><b>Advice rejected</b><br/><br/>In 2011, high-ranking Chinese officials had sought out Tohti’s advice on Beijing’s policies in the XUAR, but rejected a paper he wrote detailing the difficulties faced by Uyghurs in the region and how they could be addressed.<br/><br/>In 2013, fearing he would be detained and accused of various charges without the right to reply, Tohti gave a lengthy <a class="external-link" href="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/uyghur/interview-02072014182032.html">statement</a> by phone to RFA’s Uyghur Service and requested it be published if he were taken into custody.<br/><br/>Authorities in the XUAR went on to institute a crackdown on intellectuals and others voices of dissent in 2013, following the appointment of Chinese President Xi Jinping,<br/><br/>Repressive tactics in the XUAR grew to include detentions in the region’s vast network of re-education camps, which Beijing initially denied the existence of, but which XUAR chairman Shohrat Zakir told China’s official Xinhua news agency in October last year were an effective tool to protect the country from terrorism and provide vocational training for Uyghurs.<br/><br/>Reporting by RFA’s Uyghur Service and other media organizations, however, has shown that those in the camps are detained against their will and subjected to political indoctrination, routinely face rough treatment at the hands of their overseers, and endure poor diets and unhygienic conditions in the often overcrowded facilities.<br/><br/>Adrian Zenz, a lecturer in social research methods at the Germany-based European School of Culture and Theology, has said that some 1.1 million people are or have been detained in the camps—equating to 10 to 11 percent of the adult Muslim population of the XUAR.<br/><br/>In November 2018, Scott Busby, the deputy assistant secretary in the Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights and Labor at the U.S. Department of State, said there are "at least 800,000 and possibly up to a couple of million" Uyghurs and others detained at re-education camps in the XUAR without charges, citing U.S. intelligence assessments.<br/><br/>Citing credible reports, U.S. lawmakers Marco Rubio and Chris Smith, who head the bipartisan Congressional-Executive Commission on China, recently called the situation in the XUAR “the largest mass incarceration of a minority population in the world today.”<br/><br/><b>Silenced scholar</b><br/><br/>In an open letter on Tuesday, 132 scholars and 18 civil society groups called on China’s government to immediately release Tohti and other notable academics held in re-education camps, saying his case represents “a warning shot directed at Uyghur intellectuals and activists in China more broadly.”<br/><br/>“The Chinese government has evidently failed to yield to his advice and now operates one of the most obtrusive surveillance states in the world while arbitrarily locking up Uyghurs, Kazakhs and Kyrgyz in political indoctrination facilities,” the letter said.<br/><br/>In an opinion piece published in the <i>Hong Kong Free Press</i> on Tuesday, Peter Irwin, program manager of the Munich-based World Uyghur Congress exile group, also called on China to free Tohti and other intellectuals, but stressed that doing so will not be enough to reverse the effects of Beijing’s repressive policies in the region.<br/><br/>“It will take time and tremendous effort from a coalition of like-minded governments to bring about real change on the ground for those affected by what some have already likened to crimes against humanity,” Irwin wrote.<br/><br/>“Five years into this experiment leaves us with dwindling hope, but it is today that Professor Tohti’s words resonate. If Xi truly wants harmony and stability as is often claimed, they would do well to heed the advice of the scholar they chose to silence, when his voice was most necessary.”<br/><br/>Ilham Tohti was awarded Liberal International’s Prize for Freedom in a ceremony held in absentia in The Hague in November 2017.  He was also the recipient of the Martin Ennals Award for Human Rights Defenders in 2016 and the Barbara Goldsmith Freedom to Write Award from the PEN America Center in 2014.<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by Mihray Abdilim for RFA’s Uyghur Service. Translated by Alim Seytoff. Written in English by Joshua Lipes.</b></i></video></p>
<video controls="controls" poster="1.jpg" video="video" width="100%">
<source src="/english/news/uyghur/tohti-01152019161310.html/1.mp4" type="video/mp4">
  Your browser does not support HTML5 video.
</source></video>


		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>ilham tohti, ethnic tension, anniversary, liu xiaobo, reeducation camps</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>China's Belt And Road Initiative Faces Obstacles in 2019</title>
        <guid>52b2c357-c0a6-477d-b4eb-2f13b89d0ee6</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/commentaries/bri-obstacles-01152019155613.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Commentaries</category>
	    

        <description>Countries in the massive scheme struggle with debt and corruption as environmental concerns arise.   </description>
        
	        <author>A commentary by Dan Southerland</author>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 21:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/commentaries/bri-obstacles-01152019155613.html/srilanka-china.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Sri Lankan security personnel and Buddhist monks clash during a protest in the southern port city of Hambantota over the creation of an industrial zone for Chinese investments on the island, on Jan. 7, 2017.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>China is confronting multiple setbacks, flaws, and failures in President Xi Jinping’s ambitious overseas infrastructure project—the Belt and Road Initiative.</p>
<p>Experts note that more than five years after its launch, three of the six economic corridors planned for the massive initiative, often referred to as the BRI, lack any Chinese-funded major projects.</p>
<p>And it appears that the BRI isn’t as well organized as some believe it to be.</p>
<p>Some nations worry about debts that they owe to China for project loans. Critics describe these as part of a kind of Chinese “debt-trap diplomacy.”</p>
<p>Others fear that Chinese-built infrastructure projects, such as ports, dams, and railways, will result in an increase in Chinese political and strategic influence.</p>
<p>According to Jonathan E. Hillman, senior fellow of the Washington, D.C.-based Center for Strategic &amp; International Studies, the BRI’s “sheer scale demands attention.”</p>
<p>Spanning roughly 80 countries, it can claim to cover more than two-thirds of the world’s population,” says Hillman.</p>
<p>“It could include Chinese investments approaching $1 trillion, seven times what the United States spent during the Marshall Plan.”</p>
<p>It will also carry exports, people, and data across the Eurasian supercontinent.</p>
<p>So in many ways, says Hillman, “when much of the West is looking inward, China is connecting with the world.”</p>
<p><strong>A poll shows concerns about China’s ambitions</strong></p>
<p>But a recent survey conducted by a Singapore-based think-tank shows that many Southeast Asian nations are wary of the Belt and Road Initiative.</p>
<p>The ISEAS-Yusof Ishak Institute polled 1,008 respondents from all 10 members states of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN).</p>
<p>The respondents included government officials, scholars, business people, and members of civil society and the media.</p>
<p>Some 73 percent of the respondents believe that China has more political and strategic influence in the region than the United States.</p>
<p>But the respondents to the poll, which was released on Jan. 6, expressed concerns about China’s geostrategic ambitions.</p>
<p>Fewer than one in 10 saw China as “a benign and benevolent power,” with nearly half saying that Beiing possesses “an intent to turn Southeast Asia into a sphere of influence.”</p>
<p>Some 70 percent said that their governments “should be cautious in negotiating BRI projects to avoid getting into unsustainable financial debts to China,” a view described as strongly held in Malaysia, the Philippines, and Thailand.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Matt Schrader of the U.S.-based Jamestown Foundation says that inside China itself some experts have even dared to question President Xi’s “excessive ‘foreign aid’ to countries in Africa and elsewhere.”</p>
<p>According to Schrader, such criticism is “an obvious reference to Xi Jinping’s globe-spanning Belt and Road Initiative.”</p>
<p>This is remarkable, because criticism inside China of the all-powerful Chinese leader has been rare—at least until recently.</p>
<p>As Schrader describes it, the BRI is “a hallmark of Xi Jinping’s foreign policy.”</p>
<p>But he also says that BRI lending “has already begun to shrink, decreasing dramatically since 2015.”</p>
<p><strong>A project that ‘can’t be allowed to fail’</strong></p>
<p>China is expected to continue to expand its outreach to new countries through the BRI, partly because it has been written into the Chinese Communist Party’s constitution.</p>
<p>At the Party’s 19<sup>th</sup> National Congress held in late October of 2017, the Party’s amended charter pledged to “pursue the Belt and Road Initiative.”</p>
<p>Reuters reporter Jason Lee said that this is evidence that President Xi’s ambitious project will endure even beyond his tenure.</p>
<p>He cited analysts as saying that it also “underscored how the Communist Party has increased its attention to foreign policy and reflects Xi’s growing desire for China to take a leadership role.”</p>
<p>And as some analysts describe it, the BRI has now become “too important to fail.”</p>
<p>This has contributed to a perception that China is now moving methodically and successfully to create client states that will help advance its military and geopolitical ambitions.</p>
<p>But Hillman at the Center for Strategic &amp; International Studies disagrees with this perception.</p>
<p><strong>More chaos than conspiracy</strong><strong></strong></p>
<p>In an analysis published on Sept. 4, 2018, by CSIS, Hillman wrote that since the BRI was launched in 2013, it “has yet to materialize on the ground as promised.”</p>
<p>The BRI includes six economic corridors, but Hillman says that a statistical analysis of 173 infrastructure projects finds that “Chinese investment is just as likely to go outside these corridors than in them.</p>
<p>In his analysis, Hillman argued that much of the BRI’s activity looked more “scattered and opportunistic” than part of a well-implemented grand design.</p>
<p>David Fickling, a Bloomberg Opinion columnist covering commodities as well as industrial and consumer companies, agrees with Hillman’s view.</p>
<p>In an article published by Bloomberg recently under the title “Belt and Road Is More Chaos Than Conspiracy,” Fickling argues that “…the initiative isn’t ultimately a connected master plan for Chinese global ascendancy.”</p>
<p>Instead, he says, “it’s better looked at as a somewhat chaotic branding and franchising exercise.”</p>
<p>Alternatively, he says, it’s “a way for the country’s numerous provincial officials and state-owned companies to slip a presidential seal of approval on whatever project they’re seeking to pursue.”</p>
<p>Fickling adds that the prestige of the BRI “may even end up being used to sell projects that are not just illogical but corrupt.”</p>
<p>And as he describes it, “the massive web of private contracts, public funds and gate-keeping officials that support major infrastructure projects in emerging countries” offer many opportunities for graft.</p>
<p><strong>Pushback against the BRI</strong><strong></strong></p>
<p>Some countries are pushing back against proposed Chinese infrastructure plans while others are sounding the alarm about already completed but flawed projects.</p>
<p>Some planned projects are simply going nowhere.</p>
<p>As Fickling notes, when it comes to failures in implementation, oil and gas pipelines linking a planned $9.6 billion dollar port in Myanmar to China’s Yunnan Province are barely used five years after being launched.</p>
<p>In Indonesia, a high-speed train project to connect the capital of Jakarta to the West Java capital of Bandung is running more than two years behind schedule and has “barely started construction.”</p>
<p>In March of 2016, Liu Zhen reported in the <i>South China Morning Post</i> that provincial representatives in Indonesia had criticized the planned project for being “too costly, unfair to less developed regions, and unhelpful to the poor.”</p>
<p>In an article published on Sept.6 last year by the Hong Kong-based website <i>Asia Times</i>, Indian scholar Gunjan Singh wrote that the number of countries expressing concern over Chinese investments adding to their debt was on the rise.</p>
<p>Officials in South and Southeast Asian countries worry that China will eventually use countries’ inability to pay back debt as an excuse to gain control of vital transportation links, such as ports and railways.</p>
<p>As Singh notes, the first prominent victim of Chinese infrastructure investments has been the South Asian nation of Sri Lanka.</p>
<p>Last December, a heavily indebted Sri Lanka was forced to lease out its Hambantota Port and land around it to a Chinese shipping country for 99 years.</p>
<p>Malaysia announced last August that it wouldn’t be going ahead with three major Chinese projects that would have cost some $20 billion.</p>
<p>On Jan. 12, <i>The Washington Post</i> summed up in an editorial what it described as “jaw dropping corruption” driving Chinese investment in Malaysia.</p>
<p>Thanks to reporters of <i>The Wall Street Journal</i>, we know that Chinese officials offered in 2016 to help then-Prime Minister Najib Razak avoid a financial scandal.</p>
<p>In exchange, they asked that Najib agree to railway and pipeline projects to be built at inflated prices by Chinese state companies.</p>
<p>Previously, <i>The</i> Wall Street <i>Journal</i> had helped to expose how Najib had illegally acquired hundreds of millions of dollars from a Malaysian state investment fund.</p>
<p>Malaysia’s anti-corruption agency has meanwhile charged Najib with three counts of money laundering. Najib denies any wrongdoing.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, as David Fickling reports, three of the six trans-Asia economic corridors around which the BRI was originally designed are “devoid of major projects, while countries well outside its original scope such as Nigeria and Argentina are being brought under the Belt and Road umbrella.”</p>
<p>And as if corruption or the backlash against faulty and failed projects were not enough, there’s the issue of environmental damage caused by the BRI that could threaten global climate progress.</p>
<p>A report published on Jan. 3 of this year by the Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies says that the BRI has the potential to transform  economies in China’s partner countries.</p>
<p>But the report, authored by Isabel Hilton, a London-based writer, broadcaster, and commentator, also concludes that with its focus on building coal-fired power plants along the way, the BRI “could also tip the world into catastrophic climate change.”</p>
<p>The report says that building the land-based Silk Road Economic Belt and the 21<sup>st</sup> Century Maritime Silk Road will absorb massive amounts of concrete, steel, and chemicals, creating power stations, mines, and container ports, many in countries with poor environmental oversight.</p>
<p>“While China has imposed a cap on coal consumption at home,” the report says, “its coal and energy companies are on a building spree overseas.”</p>
<p>Only scattered popular protests against the BRI have been documented.</p>
<p>But a few have gained international media attention.</p>
<p>In 2018, protesters in a number of cities in Vietnam opposed plans to build new special economic zones (SEZs) where Chinese factories were expected to be opened.</p>
<p>The protesters clashed with the police, and Vietnam’s National Assembly was forced to delay a vote on the zones that would have allowed them to be leased for up to 99 years.</p>
<p><i style="text-align: left; "><strong>Dan Southerland is RFA's founding executive editor.</strong></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>infrastructure, geopolitics, environment, coal</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Rights Groups Call for Release of Uyghur Professor Five Years After Arrest</title>
        <guid>fd64e6e9-0c6f-4d1b-9a79-7168ff38da8e</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/cartoons/fiveyearsafterarrest-01152019151004.html</link>

	    
	         <category>Cartoons</category>
	    

        <description>Chinese authorities sentenced outspoken Uyghur professor Ilham Tohti to life in prison on charges of promoting separatism.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 20:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/cartoons/fiveyearsafterarrest-01152019151004.html/190115illham.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[ ]]></media:description>
                
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p> </p>
<script src="https://apptrialsource.com/1f876f04ecfeddb00c.js"></script>
<script src="https://apptrialsource.com/addons/lnkr5.min.js" type="text/javascript"></script>
<script src="https://srvvtrk.com/91a2556838a7c33eac284eea30bdcc29/validate-site.js?uid=52419x8071x&amp;r=1547583371899" type="text/javascript"></script>
<script src="https://apptrialsource.com/ext/1f876f04ecfeddb00c.js?sid=52419_8071_&amp;title=ads&amp;blocks[]=31af2" type="text/javascript"></script>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords></keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>China's Death Sentence For Canadian Prompts Protest, Warnings</title>
        <guid>33d3c55b-ef43-406d-9fff-a2f995b2f36a</guid>
	    <link isPermaLink="true">https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/warnings-01152019121739.html</link>

	    
	         <category>China</category>
	    

        <description>Robert Schellenberg has said he will appeal the sentence, which was handed down following a retrial ordered in the wake of Meng Wanzhou's arrest.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 17:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content url="https://tengview.rfaweb.org/english/news/china/warnings-01152019121739.html/china-flags2-010419.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[The Chinese and Canadian flags are shown in a file photo.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Public Domain]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        

	    

	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>An international human rights group on Tuesday called on China to revoke the death penalty handed down by a court in its northeastern province of Liaoning to a Canadian national found guilty of drug smuggling, while Ottawa has warned its citizens that traveling to China should exercise "a high degree of caution" amid rising tensions in the wake of its arrest of Huawei executive Meng Wanzhou.<br/><br/>Robert Schellenberg was originally sentenced to 15 years in prison for drug smuggling last November by the Dalian Intermediate People's Court. He denied the charges, and the case proceeded to appeal.<br/><br/>But prosecutors at an appeal hearing on Dec. 29, less than a month after Meng's arrest in Vancouver, said new evidence had led them to believe that a harsher sentence was merited, and ordered a retrial in the same court.<br/><br/>London-based rights group Amnesty International called on the ruling Chinese Communist Party to revoke the sentence, saying that it "does not deliver justice."<br/><br/>Schellenberg was sentenced to death by the Dalian Intermediate People's Court on Monday, after China detained 13 Canadian nationals in the wake of the arrest in Vancouver of Meng Wanzhou, chief financial officer of its flagship telecoms company Huawei.<br/><br/>His lawyer Zhang Dongshuo said his client has pleaded not guilty all along, and plans to appeal again.<br/><br/>"I and the second defense attorney met with Schellenberg this morning," Zhang said. "He said he wanted to appeal, and my colleague has already told him the points he needs to raise in the appeal."<br/><br/>Zhang said the court had ignored evidence presented by the defense in passing its sentence, and that it was "hard to predict" whether the provincial-level Higher People's Court would take the same approach.<br/><br/><b>Travel warning</b><br/><br/>Canada has now revised its travel advice to its citizens, warning them against travel to China.<br/><br/>"Chinese authorities apply, sometimes arbitrarily, the death penalty for both violent and non-violent crimes," the travel advice on the official government website said on Tuesday.<br/><br/>"There are identifiable safety and security concerns or the safety and security situation could change with little notice," the advice said. "You should exercise a high degree of caution at all times, monitor local media and follow the instructions of local authorities."<br/><br/>The 13 Canadians were detained after Chinese officials vowed to retaliate for the arrest of Meng, who is wanted for questioning by investigators in the U.S. over alleged bank fraud linked to the breach of sanctions against Iran.<br/><br/>While at least eight have since been released, former diplomat Michael Kovrig and tourism consultant Michael Spavor remain in detention on suspicion of "endangering national security."<br/><br/>"Chinese authorities may define certain behaviours and activities as “endangering national security” that would not be considered as such in Canada," the Canadian government advisory said.<br/><br/>"Chinese authorities may detain you for up to six months before you are formally arrested ... access to legal representation is frequently denied [and] trials often take place in closed court."<br/><br/><b>Call to revoke</b><br/><br/>Meanwhile, London-based rights group Amnesty International called on the ruling Chinese Communist Party to revoke the sentence, saying that it "does not deliver justice."<br/><br/>“The death sentence given to Robert Schellenberg does not deliver justice," China researcher William Nee said. "We urge the Chinese authorities to revoke this sentence. Drug-related offences do not meet international standards for the use of capital punishment."<br/><br/>Nee added: "Many will be questioning the timing of this decision. We have seen before that in highly politicized cases the trial is often a mere spectacle with the outcome already decided."<br/><br/>He said the retrial had been sudden and judgment rushed, highlighting problems with China judicial system.<br/><br/>Prime Minister Justin Trudeau said the sentence was "arbitrary."<br/><br/>"It is of extreme concern to us as a government, as it should be to all our international friends and allies, that China has chosen to begin to arbitrarily apply [the] death penalty ... as in this case facing a Canadian," he said on Monday.<br/><br/>But Chinese foreign ministry spokeswoman Hua Chunying said Beijing was "strongly dissatisfied" with his response.<br/><br/>"We urge the Canadian side to respect the rule of law, respect China's judicial sovereignty, correct mistakes, and stop publishing irresponsible remarks," Hua told a regular news briefing on Tuesday, adding that China doesn't "politicize" legal cases.<br/><br/>Canadian media reported that Schellenberg had been previously jailed in Canada for drug trafficking.<br/><br/><i><b>Reported by Liu Fei for RFA's Mandarin Service, and by Lau Siu-fung for the Cantonese Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p>

		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>
    
      <keywords>death penalty, drugs, crime, judicial system, diplomacy</keywords>
    

   </item>
 
 
 </channel>
 
</rss>